<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Code Africa</string>

    <!-- Strings for On Boarding Screen -->

    <!-- Titles -->
    <string name="first_slide_title">Learn From Any Location</string>
    <string name="second_slide_title">Learn In Different Languages</string>
    <string name="third_slide_title">Learn To Code</string>
    <string name="fourth_slide_title">Practice with Quiz</string>

    <!-- Descriptions -->
    <string name="first_slide_desc">You can access Code Africa from any where you are and anytime.</string>
    <string name="second_slide_desc">You can now learn how to code in different native languages</string>
    <string name="third_slide_desc">Learn to code with various programming technologies</string>
    <string name="fourth_slide_desc">You can test your knowledge with the quiz test</string>

    <!-- Buttons -->
    <string name="skip_btn">Skip</string>
    <string name="next_btn">Skip</string>
    <string name="let_get_started">Lets Get Started</string>

    <!-- Titles -->
    <string name="discover_courses">Discover Courses</string>
    <string name="top_rated">Top Rated Courses</string>
    <string name="category">Categories</string>
    <string name="software_development">Software Development</string>
    <string name="select_language">Select Language</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="profile">Profile</string>
    <string name="logout">Logout</string>
    <string name="coming_soon">Coming Soon</string>
    <string name="artificial_intelligence">Artificial Intelligence</string>
    <string name="java_programming">Java Programming</string>
    <string name="mobile_development">Mobile Development</string>
    <string name="web_development">Web Development</string>
    <string name="view_all">View All</string>
    <string name="info">info</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="search">Search</string>
    <string name="all_categories">All Categories</string>
    <string name="lesson">Lesson</string>
    <string name="html">HTML</string>
    <string name="learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="css">CSS</string>
    <string name="javascript">Javascript</string>

    <string name="igbo">IGBO</string>
    <string name="yoruba">YORUBA</string>
    <string name="hausa">HAUSA</string>
    <string name="english">ENGLISH</string>


    <!-- HTML contents -->

    <!-- HTML English Contents -->
    <string name="en_html_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tWhat is HTML?\n
        \tHTML is the standard markup language for creating Web pages.\n
        HTML stands for Hyper Text Markup Language\n
        HTML describes the structure of Web pages using markup\n
        HTML elements are the building blocks of HTML pages\n
        HTML elements are represented by tags\n
        HTML tags label pieces of content such as \"heading\", \"paragraph\", \"table\", and so on\n
        Browsers do not display the HTML tags, but use them to render the content of the page\n\n
        \t\t\tA Simple HTML Document\n
        \tExample\n
        <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        <html>\n
        <head>\n
        <title>Page Title</title>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n\n

        <h1>My First Heading</h1>\n
        <p>My first paragraph.</p>\n\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        \t\tExample Explained\n
        The <!DOCTYPE html> declaration defines this document to be HTML5\n
        The <html> element is the root element of an HTML page\n
        The <head> element contains meta information about the document\n
        The <title> element specifies a title for the document\n
        The <body> element contains the visible page content\
        The <h1> element defines a large heading\n
        The <p> element defines a paragraph\n\n
        \t\tHTML Tags\n\n
        HTML tags are element names surrounded by angle brackets:\n
        HTML tags normally come in pairs like <p> and </p>\n
        The first tag in a pair is the start tag, the second tag is the end tag\n
        The end tag is written like the start tag, but with a forward slash inserted before the tag name\n\n
        \t\tThe <!DOCTYPE> Declaration\n\n
        The <!DOCTYPE> declaration represents the document type, and helps browsers to display web pages correctly.\n
        It must only appear once, at the top of the page (before any HTML tags).\n
        The <!DOCTYPE> declaration is not case sensitive  Case sensitive: (of a computer program or function) differentiating between capital and lower-case letters)\n
        The <!DOCTYPE> is the  declaration for HTML5\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_html_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
        HTML Editors\n\n
        Write HTML Using Notepad or TextEdit\n
        Web pages can be created and modified by using professional HTML editors.
        However, for learning HTML we recommend a simple text editor like Notepad (PC) or TextEdit (Mac).
        We believe using a simple text editor is a good way to learn HTML.
        Follow the four steps below to create your first web page with Notepad or TextEdit.\n\n
        Step 1: Open Notepad (PC)\n\n
        Windows 8 or later:\n
        Open the Start Screen (the window symbol at the bottom left on your screen). Type Notepad.\n
        Windows 7 or earlier:\n
        Open Start > Programs > Accessories > Notepad\n
        Step 1: Open TextEdit (Mac)\n\n
        Open Finder > Applications > TextEdit\n
        Also change some preferences to get the application to save files correctly.
        In Preferences > Format > choose \"Plain Text\"
        Then under \"Open and Save\", check the box that says \"Display HTML files as HTML code instead of formatted text\".
        Then open a new document to place the code.\n\n
        Step 3: Save the HTML Page\n\n
        Save the file on your computer. Select File > Save as in the Notepad menu.
        Name the file \"index.htm\" and set the encoding to UTF-8 (which is the preferred encoding for HTML files).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_html_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
        HTML Documents\n\n
        All HTML documents must start with a document type declaration: <!DOCTYPE html>.\n
        The HTML document itself begins with <html> and ends with </html>.\n
        The visible part of the HTML document is between <body> and </body>.\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        <html>\n
        <body>\n

        <h1>My First Heading</h1>\n
        <p>My first paragraph.</p>\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        HTML Headings\n\n
        HTML headings are defined with the <h1> to <h6> tags.\n
        <h1> defines the most important heading. <h6> defines the least important heading:\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <h1>This is heading 1</h1>\n
        <h2>This is heading 2</h2>\n
        <h3>This is heading 3</h3>\n\n
         HTML Paragraphs\n\n
        HTML paragraphs are defined with the <p> tag:\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <p>This is a paragraph.</p>\n
        <p>This is another paragraph.</p>\n\n

        /t/tHTML Links/n/n
        HTML links are defined with the <a> tag:/n
        Example/n/n
        <a href=\"https://www.codeafrica.com\">This is a link</a>/n
        The link\'s destination is specified in the href attribute. /n
        Attributes are used to provide additional information about HTML elements./n
        You will learn more about attributes in a later chapter./n/n

        HTML Images\n\n
        HTML images are defined with the <img> tag.\n
        The source file (src), alternative text (alt), width, and height are provided as attributes:\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <img src=\"goat.jpg\" alt=\"goat\" width=\"104\" height=\"142\">\n\n
        HTML Buttons\n\n
        HTML buttons are defined with the <button> tag:\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <button>Click me</button>\n\n
        HTML Lists\n\n
        HTML lists are defined with the <ul> (unordered/bullet list) or the <ol> (ordered/numbered list) tag, followed by <li> tags (list items):\n
        Example\n\n
        <ul>\n
          <li>Coffee</li>\n
          <li>Tea</li>\n
          <li>Milk</li>\n
        </ul>\n

    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_html_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
        Empty HTML Elements\n\n
        HTML elements with no content are called empty elements.\n
        <br> is an empty element without a closing tag (the <br> tag defines a line break):\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <p>This is a <br> paragraph with a line break.</p>\n\n
        HTML Attributes\n
        •	All HTML elements can have attributes\n
        •	Attributes provide additional information about an element\n
        •	Attributes are always specified in the start tag\n
        •	Attributes usually come in name/value pairs like: name="value"\n
        The href Attribute\n
        HTML links are defined with the <a> tag. The link address is specified in the href attribute:\n
        Example\n\n
        <a href=\"#\">This is a link</a>\n
        The src Attribute\n
        HTML images are defined with the <img> tag.\n
        The filename of the image source is specified in the src attribute:\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <img src=\"goat.jpg\">\n
        The width and height Attributes\n
        Images in HTML have a set of size attributes, which specifies the width and height of the image:\n\n
        Example\n
        <img src=\"goat.jpg\" width=\"500\" height=\"600\">\n\n
        The alt Attribute\n\n
        The alt attribute specifies an alternative text to be used, when an image cannot be displayed.\n
        The value of the attribute can be read by screen readers.\n
        This way, someone \"listening\" to the webpage, e.g. a vision impaired person, can \"hear\" the element.\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <img src=\"jacket.jpg\" alt=\"Girl with a jacket\">\n
        The alt attribute is also useful if the image does not exist:\n
        The style Attribute\n
        The style attribute is used to specify the styling of an element, like color, font, size etc.\n\n
        Example\n\n
        <p style=\"color:red\">I am a paragraph</p>\n\n
        HTML Headings\n\n
        Headings are defined with the <h1> to <h6> tags.\n
        <h1> defines the most important heading. <h6> defines the least important heading.\n\n
        Example\n
        <h1>Heading 1</h1>\n
        <h2>Heading 2</h2>\n
        <h3>Heading 3</h3>\n
        <h4>Heading 4</h4>\n
        <h5>Heading 5</h5>\n
        <h6>Heading 6</h6>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_html_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tThe HTML Style Attribute\n\n
        \tSetting the style of an HTML element, can be done with the style attribute.\n
        The HTML style attribute has the following syntax:\n
        <tagname style=\"property:value;\">\n
        The property is a CSS property. The value is a CSS value.\n
        You will learn more about CSS later in this tutorial.\n\n
        \tHTML Background Color\n
        The background-color property defines the background color for an HTML element.\n
        This example sets the background color for a page to powderblue:\n\n
        Example\n
        <body style=\"background-color:powderblue;\">\n

        <h1>This is a heading</h1>\n
        <p>This is a paragraph.</p>\n

        </body>\n\n
        \tHTML Text Color\n\n
        The color property defines the text color for an HTML element:\n
        Example\n
        <h1 style=\"color:blue;\">This is a heading</h1>\n
        <p style=\"color:red;\">This is a paragraph.</p>\n\n
        \tHTML Fonts\n
        The font-family property defines the font to be used for an HTML element:\n
        Example\n\n
        <h1 style=\"font-family:verdana;\">This is a heading</h1>\n
        <p style=\"font-family:courier;\">This is a paragraph.</p>\n\n
        \tHTML Text Size\n
        The font-size property defines the text size for an HTML element:\n
        Example\n\n
        <h1 style=\"font-size:300;\">This is a heading</h1>\n
        <p style=\"font-size:160;\">This is a paragraph.</p>\n\n
        \tHTML Text Alignment\n
        The text-align property defines the horizontal text alignment for an HTML element:\n
        Example\n\n
        <h1 style=\"text-align:center;\">Centered Heading</h1>\n
        <p style=\"text-align:center;\">Centered paragraph.</p>\n\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_html_lesson_six"><![CDATA[
        HTML The class Attribute\n\n
        The HTML class attribute is used to define equal styles for elements with the same class name.\n
        So, all HTML elements with the same class attribute will have the same format and style.\n
        Here we have three <div> elements that point to the same class name:\n\n
        <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        <html>\n
        <head>\n
        <style>\n
        .cities {
          background-color: black;
          color: white;
          margin: 20px;
          padding: 20px;
        }
        </style>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n

        <div class=\"cities\">\n
          <h2>London</h2>\n
          <p>London is the capital of England.</p>\n
        </div>\n

        <div class=\"cities\">\n
          <h2>Paris</h2>\n
          <p>Paris is the capital of France.</p>\n
        </div>\n

        <div class=\"cities\">\n
          <h2>Tokyo</h2>\n
          <p>Tokyo is the capital of Japan.</p>\n
        </div>\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        HTML The id Attribute\n\n
        The id attribute specifies a unique id for an HTML element (the value must be unique within the HTML document).\n
        The id value can be used by CSS and JavaScript to perform certain tasks for a unique element with the specified id value.\n
        In CSS, to select an element with a specific id, write a hash (#) character, followed by the id of the element:\n\n
        <style>\n
        #myHeader {\n
          background-color: lightblue;\n
          color: black;\n
          padding: 40px;\n
          text-align: center;\n
        }
        </style>\n

        <h1 id=\"myHeader\">My Header</h1>\n
        Tip: The id attribute can be used on any HTML element.\n
        Note: The id value is case-sensitive.\n
        Note: The id value must contain at least one character, and must not contain whitespace (spaces, tabs, etc.).\n\n
        Difference Between Class and ID\n\n
        An HTML element can only have one unique id that belongs to that single element, while a class name can be used by multiple elements:\n\n

    ]]></string>

    <!-- end of English html contents -->

    <!-- HTML Hausa Contents -->

    <string name="ha_html_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        Menene HTML?\n\n
        HTML shine daidaitaccen harshen fara rubutu don ƙirƙirar shafukan yanar gizo.\n
        \t• HTML tsaye ga Harshen Rubutun Tsallake\n
        \t• HTML ya bayyana tsarin shafukan yanar gizo suna amfani da alamar aiki\n
        \t• Abubuwan HTML sune abubuwan toshe shafukan HTML\n
        \t• Abubuwan HTML ana wakilta ta alamun alama\n
        \t• Alamomin HTML alamun gumakan abun ciki kamar \"taken\", \"sakin layi\", \"tebur\", da sauransu\n
        \t• Masu bincike ba sa nuna alamun HTML, amma yi amfani da su don sanya abubuwan da shafin ya ƙunsa\n
        Rubutun HTML mai sauki\n\n
        \t\tMisali\n\n
        <! DOCTYPE html>\n
        <html>\n
        <head>\n
        <title> taken shafin </title>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n\n

        <h1> Kai na farko </h1>\n
        <p> Sakin farko na. </p>\n\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n

        Misali Ya Bayyana\n
        \t• Bayanin <! DOCTYPE HTML> sanarwa ta bayyana wannan takaddar ta zama HTML5\n
        \t• Sinadarin <html> shine tushen shafin HTML\n
        \t• Sinadarin <head> ya ƙunshi bayanin meta game da daftarin\n
        \t• Sinadarin <title> yana ba da taken ga takaddar\n
        \t• Sinadarin ya ƙunshi abun cikin shafi na gani\n
        \t• Sinadarin <h1> yana bayyana babban take\n
        \t• Sinadarin <p> ya bayyana sakin layi\n\n

        Alamun HTML\n
        Alamar HTML sune sunayen abubuwanda aka zagaye da kusurwar kusurwa:\n
        \t• Alamomin HTML a koyaushe suna zuwa nau\'i-nau\'i kamar <p> da </p>\n
        Alamar ta farko a cikin wata mata ita ce alamar farawa, alama ta biyu ita ce alamar karshen
        • Rubutun alamar ƙarshen an rubuta shi azaman alamar farawa, amma tare da shigar da ƙara gaba kafin sunan alamar\n\n

        \t\t\tBayanin <! DOCTYPE> Bayanin\n
        Bayanin <! DOCTYPE> yana wakiltar nau\'in daftarin aiki, kuma yana taimaka wa masu bincike su nuna shafukan yanar gizo daidai.\n
        Dole ne kawai ya bayyana sau ɗaya, a saman shafin (kafin kowane alamun HTML).\n
        Sanarwar <! DOCTYPE>  ba batun mai hankali bane.( case sensitive: na shirin komputa ko aiki wanda ya bambanta tsakanin manyan haruffa da ƙarafa)\n\n
        <! DOCTYPE> ita ce sanarwar HTML5\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_html_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
         \t\t\tEdita HTML\n
        \tRubuta HTML Ta amfani da notepad ko TextEdit\n
        Za\'a iya ƙirƙirar shafukan yanar gizon da inganta su ta amfani da masu gyara HTML.\n
        Koyaya, don koyan HTML muna bada shawara ga edita mai sauƙi kamar Notepad (PC) ko TextEdit (Mac).\n
        Mun yi imanin yin amfani da editan rubutu mai sauƙi hanya ce mai kyau don koyon HTML.\n
        Bi matakai huɗu da ke ƙasa don ƙirƙirar shafin yanar gizonku na farko tare da Notepad ko TextEdit.\n
        \t\tMataki na 1: Buɗe notepad (PC)\n
        Windows 8 ko daga baya:\n
        Bude Allon farawa (alamar taga a kasan hagu a allonka). Rubuta littafin rubutu.\n
        Windows 7 ko a baya:\n
        Buɗe Fara> Shirye-shirye> Na\'urorin haɗi> Alamar sanarwa\n\n
        Mataki 2: Bude TextEdit (Mac)\n
        Buɗe Mai Nemo> Aikace-aikace> TextEdit\n
        Hakanan canza wasu abubuwan zaɓin don samun aikace-aikacen don adana fayiloli daidai. A fifiko> Tsarin> zabi \"Rubutun rubutu\"\n
        Sannan a ƙarƙashin \"Buɗe da Ajiye\", duba akwatin da ke cewa \"Nuna fayilolin HTML azaman lambar HTML maimakon rubutun da aka tsara\".\n
        Sai ka buɗe sabon takarda don sanya lambar.\n\n
        Mataki na 3: Adana Shafin HTML\n
        Adana fayil ɗin a kwamfutarka. Zaɓi Fayil> Ajiye kamar yadda yake cikin menu na bayanin kula.\n
        Sunaye fayil ɗin \"index.htm\" kuma saita saka bayanan zuwa UTF-8 (wanda shine mafi kyawun ɓoye bayanan fayilolin HTML).\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_html_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
        /t/tTakaddun HTML/n/n
        /tDuk takardun HTML dole ne su fara tare da sanarwau\'in sanarwa: <! DOCTYPE html>./n
        Kundin HTML din kansa yana farawa da <html> kuma ya ƙare tare da </html>./n
        Bayyanan sashen da ke bayyane daga cikin kundin HTML din yana tsakanin <body> da </body>./n
        Misali/n/n
        <! DOCTYPE html>/n
        <html>/n
        <body>/n

        <h1> Kai na farko </h1>/n
        <p> Sakin farko na. </p>/n

        </body>/n
        </html>/n/n
        Labaran HTML/n
        An bayyana taken HTML tare da alamun <h1> zuwa <h6>.\n
        <h1> bayyana ma\'anar taken. <h6> ya bayyana mafi ƙanƙanta taken:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <h1> Wannan itace taken 1 </h1>\n
        <h2> Wannan itace taken 2 </h2>\n
        <h3> Wannan itace taken 3 </h3>\n\n
        \tSakin layi HTML\n
        An bayyana sakin layi na HTML tare da alamar <p>:\n
        Misali\n
        <p> Wannan sakin layi ne. </p>\n
        <p> Wannan wani sakin layi ne. </p>\n\n
        Hanyoyin haɗin HTML\n
        An bayyana hanyoyin haɗin HTML tare da alamar <a>:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <a href=\"https://www.codeafrica.com\"> Wannan hanyar haɗi ce </a>
        An bayyana makamar hanyar mahadar a cikin halayen href.\n
        Ana amfani da halaye don samar da ƙarin bayani game da abubuwan HTML.\n
        Za ku koyi abubuwa da yawa game da halaye a cikin babi na gaba.\n\n
        Hotunan HTML\n
        An bayyana hotunan HTML tare da alamar <img>.\n
        An samar da fayil ɗin asalin (src), madadin rubutu (alt), nisa, da tsayi azaman halaye:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\" alt = \"goat\" nisa = \"104\" tsawo = \"142\">\n\n
        HTML maballin\n
        An bayyana maɓallin HTML tare da alamar <button>:\n
        Misali\n
        <button> Danna ni </button>\n
        Lissafin HTML\n
        An bayyana jerin abubuwan HTML tare da alamar <ul> (ba a rufe su ba / harsashi) ko alamar \"olol (jerin da aka ƙaddara / adadi), mai bibiyar alamar <li> (jerin abubuwan):\n
        Misali\n
        <ul>\n
          <li> Kawa </li>\n
          <li> Tea </li>\n
          <li> Milk </li>\n
        </ul>\n\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_html_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tBabu komai game da abubuwan HTML(Empty HTML Elements)\n\n

        \tAbubuwan HTML ba tare da abun ciki ba ana kiransu abubuwa mara komai.\n
        <br> wani fanko ne ba tare da alamar rufewa ba (alamar <br> tana ma\'anar hutun layin):\n\n
        Misali\n
        <p> Wannan sakin layi ne na <br> tare da hutun layi. </p>\n\n
        Sifa  HTML\n
        \t• Duk abubuwan HTML zasu iya samun halayen\n
        \t• Halayen suna samar da ƙarin bayani game da wani abu\n
        \t• Ana nuna halaye koyaushe a cikin alamar farawa\n
        \t• Halayen halaye sukan zo da suna / darajojin nau\'i kamar: suna = \"darajar\"\n\n
        Hallaka Sanarwa\n
        An bayyana hanyoyin haɗin HTML tare da alamar <a>. An bayyana adireshin mahaɗin a cikin sifofin href:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <a href=\n"#\n"> Wannan hanyar haɗi ce </a>\n
        Sifa Src\n
        An bayyana hotunan HTML tare da alamar <img>.\n
        An bayyana sunan asalin sunan hoton a sigar ckin src:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\">\n
        Fadi da tsayi Halayen\n
        Hotunan cikin HTML suna da nau\'ikan girman, wanda ke ƙayyade faɗi da tsawo na hoton:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\" height = \"500\" width = \"600\">\n\n
        Sifa Alt\n
        Alt halayen yana bayyana wani madadin rubutu da za a yi amfani da shi, lokacin da hoto ba zai iya nuna ba.\n
        Za a iya karanta ƙimar halayen ta hanyar masu karatun allo. Wannan hanyar, wani \"yana sauraron\" shafin yanar gizon, misali. hangen nesa mai hangen nesa, zai iya \"ji\" kashi.\n\n
        Misali\n
        <img src = \"jaket.jpg\" alt = \"Yarinya da jaket\">\n
        Alt halayen na da amfani idan hoton bai wanzu ba:\n\n
        Salon(style) Yanayi\n
        Ana amfani da sifayar salo don tantance salo na abun, kamar launi, rubutu, girma da sauransu.\n
        Misali\n
        <p style = \"kala: ja\"> Ni sakin layi ne </p>\n\n
        Jefa(Heading) HTML\n
        An bayyana taken tare da alamun <h1> zuwa <h6>.\n
        <h1> bayyana ma\'anar taken. <h6> ya bayyana mafi ƙanƙanta taken.\n
        Misali\n
        <h1> heading </h1>\n
        <h2> heading </h2>\n
        <h3> heading </h3>\n
        <h4> heading 4 </h4>\n
        <h5> heading </h5>\n
        <h6> heading </h6>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_html_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tSiffar Sigar HTML\n\n
        Tsarin salon kayan HTML, za\'a iya aiwatar dashi tare da sifofin salo.\n
        Siffar salo na HTML yana da asalin rubutun:\n
        <tagname style = \"dukiya: darajar;\">\n
        Kayan mallakin CSS ne. Darajar darajar CSS ce.\n
        Za ku sami ƙarin koyo game da CSS daga baya a wannan koyawa.\n\n

        Hotunan Bayan Fage HTML(HTML Background Color)\n
        Abubuwan da ke cikin tushen launi suna ba da launi na bango na asali na HTML.\n
        Wannan misalin yana saita launi na bango ga shafi zuwa shafi:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <body style=\"background-color:powderblue;\">\n
        <h1> Wannan itace </h1>\n
        <p> Wannan sakin layi ne. </p>\n

        </body>\n\n
        Launin Rubutun HTML\n
        Dukiya mai launi tana ma\'anar launi rubutu na abubuwan HTML:\n\n
        Misali\n
        <h1 style = \"launi: shudi;\"> Wannan itace take </h1>\n
        <p style = \"launi: ja;\"> Wannan sakin layi ne. </p>\n\n
        Tsarin rubutun HTML\n
        Ginin font-iyali yana bayyana font da za a yi amfani dashi don kayan HTML:\n
        Misali\n
        <h1 style = \"font-family: verdana;\"> Wannan itace taken </h1>\n
        <p style = \"font-family: Courier;\"> Wannan sakin layi ne. </p>\n\n
        Girman Rubutun HTML\n
        Ginin font-size yana bayyana girman rubutun ga abun HTML:\n
        Misali\n
        <h1 style = \"font-size: 300;\"> Wannan itace taken </h1>\n
        <p style = \"font-size: 160;\"> Wannan sakin layi ne. </p>\n\n
        Tsarin Rubutun HTML\n
        Da rubutu-align dukiya ya bayyana a kwance rubutu jeri ga HTML kashi:\n
        Misali\n
        <h1 style = \"rubutu-align: tsakiya;\"> Matsakaicin Cibiyar </h1>\n
        <p style = \"rubutu-align: cibiyar;\"> Sakin layi. </p>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_html_lesson_six"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tHTML AJI SIFA\n\n
        \tAna amfani da sifar ɗabi\'ar HTML don ayyana daidaitattun halaye don abubuwa tare da sunan aji ɗaya.\n
        Don haka, duk abubuwan HTML tare da sifofin aji iri ɗaya za su sami tsari iri ɗaya.\n
        Anan muna da abubuwa guda uku <div> waɗanda ke nuna sunan aji ɗaya:\n\n
        <! DOCTYPE html>\n
        <html>\n
        <head>\n
        <style>\n
        .cikin {\n
          launi-launi: baki;\n
          launi: fari;\n
          gefe: 20px;\n
          padding: 20px;\n
        }\n
        </style>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n

        <div aji = \"birane\">\n
          <h2> London </h2>\n
          <p> London babban birnin Ingila ne. </p>\n
        </div>\n

        <div aji = \"birane\">\n
          <h2> Paris </h2>\n
          <p> Paris babban birnin Faransa ne. </p>\n
        </div>\n

        <div aji = \"birane\">\n
          <h2> Tokyo </h2>\n
          <p> Tokyo babban birni ne na Japan. </p>\n
        </div>\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        HTML ID SIFA CE\n\n
        Siffar id ya ƙayyade keɓantaccen id na kayan HTML (ƙimar dole ne ya zama na musamman a cikin takaddar HTML).\n
        CSS da JavaScript za su iya amfani da shi don yin wasu ayyuka don ainihin keɓaɓɓen tare da ƙimar id ɗin da aka ƙayyade.\n
        A CSS, don zaɓar wani abu tare da takamaiman id, rubuta harafin zanta (#), mai biye da sifin:\n
        <style>\n
        #myHeader {\n
          launi-bango: hasken fitila;\n
          launi: baƙi;\n
          padding: 40px;\n
          rubutu-align: cibiyar;\n
        }\n
        </style>\n\n

        <h1 id = \"myHeader\"> Shugaban kaina </h1>\n
        Tukwici: Za\'a iya amfani da sifar id ɗin akan kowane abu na HTML.\n
        Lura: valueimar id ɗin tana da halayyar damuwa.\n
        Fadakarwa: Darajar id dole ne ya ƙunshi aƙalla halayya ɗaya, kuma dole ne ya ƙunshi farar fata (sarari, shafuka, da sauransu).\n\n
        Bambanci Tsakanin aji da ID\n
        Abun HTML na iya samun guda ɗaya na daban wanda ke mallakar wannan kayan guda ne, yayin da abubuwan abubuwa da yawa zasu iya amfani da su:\n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of Hausa HTML Contents -->

    <!-- HTML Yoruba Contents -->

    <string name="yo_html_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tKini  HTML?\n\n
        HTML ni ede ipo ṣiṣedeede fun ṣiṣẹda awọn oju-iwe wẹẹbu.\n
        \t• HTML duro fun Ede gbigbọ-ọrọ Iwe Alumọni\n
        \t• HTML ṣe apejuwe be ti awọn oju opo wẹẹbu nipa lilo iṣẹda\n
        \t• Awọn eroja HTML jẹ awọn bulọọki ile ti awọn oju-iwe HTML\n
        \t• Awọn eroja HTML jẹ aṣoju nipasẹ awọn afi\n
        \t• Awọn aami afi aami HTML ti awọn akoonu bi \"akọle\", \"paragirafi\", \"tabili\", ati bẹbẹ lọ\n
        \t• Awọn aṣawakiri ko ṣe afihan awọn afi HTML, ṣugbọn lo wọn lati san akoonu ti oju-iwe naa han\n\n
        Iwe adehun HTML ti o rọrunn\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <! DOCTYPE HTML>\n
        <html>\n
        <head>\n
        <title> Akọle Oju-iwe </title>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n
        \n
        <H1> Akọkọ Akọkọ mi </H1>\n
        <p> ìpínrọ̀ àkọ́kọ́ mi. </p>\n
        \n
        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        Apejuwe Apeere\n
        \t• ikede <! DOCTYPE HTML> asọtẹlẹ ṣalaye iwe yii lati jẹ HTML5\n
        \t• Ẹya <html> jẹ ipilẹ ti oju-iwe HTML\n
        \t• Apakan <head> ni alaye meta nipa iwe aṣẹ naa\n
        \t• Ẹya <title> ṣalaye akọle fun iwe-aṣẹ naa\n
        \t• Ẹya <body> ni akoonu oju-iwe ti o han\n
        \t• Ẹya <h1> ṣalaye akọle nla kan\n
        \t• Ipilẹ <p> ṣalaye paragirafi kan\n\n
        Awọn afi HTML\n
        Awọn afi HTML jẹ awọn orukọ nkan ti yika nipasẹ awọn biraketi igun:\n
        \t• Awọn afi HTML deede wa ni awọn orisii bii <p> ​​ati </p>\n
        \t• Ami orukọ akọkọ ninu bata ni taagi ibere, orukọ keji jẹ aami igbẹhin\n
        A samisi orukọ opin bi aami taagi, ṣugbọn pẹlu titẹ slash siwaju ti o fi sii orukọ tag\n
        Alaye naa (The <!DOCTYPE> Declaration)\n\n

        Ifihan <! DOCTYPE> n ṣe aṣoju iru iwe aṣẹ naa, ati iranlọwọ awọn aṣawakiri lati ṣafihan awọn oju-iwe wẹẹbu ni deede.\n
        O gbọdọ han lẹẹkan, ni oke oju-iwe (ṣaaju eyikeyi awọn afi HTML).\n
        Ifihan <! DOCTYPE> ikede kii ṣe ọran ifura Ọpọlọ --- (ti eto kọmputa kan tabi iṣẹ) iyatọ laarin awọn leta nla ati kekere)\n
        I <! DOCTYPE> jẹ ikede naa fun HTML5\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_html_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
                 \t\t\tAwọn olootu HTML\n\n
        \tKọ HTML Lilo Akọsilẹ tabi TextEdit\n
        Awọn oju opo wẹẹbu le ṣẹda ati yipada nipasẹ lilo awọn olootu HTML ọjọgbọn.\n
        Sibẹsibẹ, fun kikọ HTML a ṣeduro olootu ọrọ ti o rọrun bi Notepad (PC) tabi TextEdit (Mac).\n
        A gbagbọ lilo olootu ọrọ rọrun kan jẹ ọna ti o dara lati kọ ẹkọ HTML.\n
        Tẹle awọn igbesẹ mẹrin ni isalẹ lati ṣẹda oju-iwe wẹẹbu akọkọ rẹ pẹlu Akọsilẹ tabi TextEdit.\n\n
        Igbesẹ 1: Ṣi akọsilẹ bọtini (PC)\n
        Windows 8 tabi nigbamii:\n
        Ṣii Ibẹrẹ iboju (aami window ni isalẹ apa osi loju iboju rẹ). Iru akọsilẹ.\n
        Windows 7 tabi sẹyìn:\n
        Ṣii Bibẹrẹ> Awọn eto> Awọn ẹya ẹrọ miiran> Akọsilẹ\n\n
        Igbesẹ 1: Ṣi TextEdit (Mac)\n
        Ṣawari Ṣi i> Awọn ohun elo> TextEdit\n
        Paapaa tun yipada diẹ ninu awọn ayanfẹ lati gba ohun elo lati fi awọn faili pamọ daradara. Ni Awọn aṣayan> Ọna kika> yan \“Text Text\”\n
        Lẹhin naa labẹ \"Ṣi ati Fipamọ\", ṣayẹwo apoti ti o sọ \“Ṣafihan awọn faili HTML bi koodu HTML dipo ọrọ ti a fiwe\”.\n
        Lẹhinna ṣii iwe tuntun lati fi koodu sii.\n\n

        Igbesẹ 3: Fi oju-iwe HTML pamọ\n
        Fi faili pamọ sori kọmputa rẹ. Yan Faili> Fipamọ bi ninu apo iwe akọsilẹ.\n
        Sọ lorukọ faili \“index.htm\” ki o ṣeto koodu si UTF-8 (eyiti o jẹ koodu ti o fẹ fun awọn faili HTML).\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_html_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
                /t/tTAwọn iwe aṣẹ HTML\n\n
        Gbogbo awọn iwe aṣẹ HTML gbọdọ bẹrẹ pẹlu ikede iru ikede: <! DOCTYPE html>.\n
        Iwe HTML tikalati bẹrẹ pẹlu <html> o si pari pẹlu </html>.\n
        Apakan ti a rii ti iwe HTML ni o wa laarin <body> ati </body>.\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <! DOCTYPE HTML>\n
        <html>\n
        <body>\n
        \n
        <h1> Akọkọ Akọkọ mi </h1>\n
        <p> ìpínrọ̀ àkọ́kọ́ mi. </p>\n
        \n
        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        Awọn akọle HTML\n
        A ṣalaye awọn akọle HTML pẹlu awọn ami <h1> si awọn afi orukọ <h6>.\n
        <H1> ṣalaye akọle pataki julọ. <H6> ṣalaye akọle pataki ti o kere julọ:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <h1> Eyi nlọ 1 </h1>\n
        <h2> Eyi nlọ 2 </h2>\n
        <h3> Eyi nlọ 3 </h3>\n
         \t\tAwọn ọrọ HTML\n
        Awọn ìpínrọ HTML ni a ṣalaye pẹlu ami-ika <p>:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <p> Eyi ni ìpínrọ kan. </p>\n
        <p> Eyi ni ìpínrọ miiran. </p>\n\n
        Awọn ọna asopọ HTML\n
        Awọn ọna asopọ HTML ni asọye pẹlu ami-jijade <a>:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <a href=\"https://www.codeafrica.com\"> Eyi ni ọna asopọ kan </a>\n
        Opo ọna asopọ naa ni pato ninu abuda href.\n
        A lo awọn ifamọra lati pese alaye ni afikun nipa awọn eroja HTML.\n
        Iwọ yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa awọn eroja ni ori atẹle kan.\n\n
        Awọn aworan HTML\n
        A ṣalaye awọn aworan HTML pẹlu aami <img>.\n
        Faili orisun (src), ọrọ miiran (alt), iwọn, ati iga ni a pese bi awọn eroja:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\" alt = \"ewurẹ\" iwọn = \"104\" iga = \"142\">\n\n
        Awọn bọtini HTML\n
        Awọn bọtini HTML ni asọye pẹlu aami <button>:\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <button> Tẹ mi </button>\n\n
        Awọn atokọ HTML\n
        Awọn atokọ HTML ti wa ni asọye pẹlu <ul> (atokọ kika / iwe ọta ibọn) tabi ami orukọ <ol> (ti paṣẹ / ti nomba), atẹle nipa awọn isamisi <li> (awọn ohun atokọ):\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <ul>\n
          <li> Kọfi </li>\n
          <li> Tii </li>\n
          <li> Wara </li>\n
        </ul>\n\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_html_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tAwọn nkan HTML ti o ṣofo\n\n
        Awọn eroja HTML ti ko ni akoonu ni a pe ni awọn eroja ti o ṣofo.\n
        <br> jẹ nkan ti o ṣofo laisi aami ipari (aami taagi tumọ si fifọ laini):\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <p> Eyi jẹ paragi-ọrọ <br> pẹlu fifọ laini. </p>\n\n
        Awọn ifarahan HTML\n
        \t • Gbogbo awọn eroja HTML le ni awọn eroja\n
        \t • Awọn ifarahan pese alaye afikun nipa ẹya kan\n
        \t • Awọn ifarahan ti wa ni itọkasi nigbagbogbo ni tag aami\n
        \t • Awọn ifarahan nigbagbogbo wa ni orukọ / awọn orisii iye bii: orukọ = \"iye\"\n\n
        Awọn href Ẹya\n
        Awọn ọna asopọ HTML ni asọye pẹlu ami-jijade <a>. Adirẹsi opopo ọna asopọ ni iyasọtọ href:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <a href=\"#\"> Eyi ni ọna asopọ kan </a>\n\n
        Ẹya src\n
        A ṣalaye awọn aworan HTML pẹlu aami <img>.\n
        Filename ti orisun aworan ni pato ninu abuda src:\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\">\n\n
        Iwọn ati Awọn ifarahan giga\n
        Awọn aworan ni HTML ni ṣeto awọn abuda iwọn, eyiti o ṣe asọtẹlẹ iwọn ati giga ti aworan:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\" iwọn = \"500\" iga = \"600\">\n

        Awọn alt Ẹya\n
        Irisi alt n ṣalaye ọrọ miiran lati ṣee lo, nigbati aworan ko le han.\n
        Iwọn abuda naa le ka nipasẹ awọn oluka iboju. Ni ọna yii, ẹnikan “\tẹtisi\” si oju opo wẹẹbu naa, fun apẹẹrẹ. eniyan ti ko ni iran, le \“gbọ\” ẹda naa.\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <img src = "\jaketi.jpg\" alt = \"Ọmọbinrin pẹlu jaketi kan\">\n
        Irisi alt tun wulo ti aworan naa ko ba si:\n\n
        Awọn ara Irisi\n
        A nlo adapọ ara lati ṣe pato aṣa ti ano kan, bii awọ, font, iwọn ati be  lo.\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <p style = \"awọ: pupa\"> Emi ni paragirafi </p>\n\n
        Awọn akọle HTML\n
        Awọn akọle ni itumọ pẹlu awọn ami <h1> si awọn ami <h6>.\n
        <H1> ṣalaye akọle pataki julọ. <h6> ṣalaye akọle pataki ti o kere ju.\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <H1> Akọkọ 1 </H1>\n
        <H2> Awọn akọle 2 </H2>\n
        <H3> Awọn akọle 3 </H3>\n
        <H4> Awọn akọle 4 </H4>\n
        <H5> Akọkọ 5 </H5>\n
        <H6> Awọn akọle 6 </H6>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_html_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tẸya ara ti HTML\n\n
        Ètò  aṣa ti ẹya HTML, le ṣee ṣe pẹlu abuda ara.\n
        Ẹya ara HTML ni ipilẹṣẹ-ọrọ atẹle:\n
        <tagname ara = \"ohun-ini: iye;\">\n
        Ohun-ini naa jẹ ohun-ini CSS. Iwọn naa jẹ iye CSS.\n
        Iwọ yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa CSS nigbamii ninu ikẹkọ yii.\n
        Awọ HTML abẹlẹ\n
        Ohun-ini lẹhin-asọ asọye awọ abẹlẹ fun ẹya HTML.\n
        Apẹẹrẹ yii ṣeto awọ isale fun oju-iwe kan si powderblue:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <ara = \"awọ lẹhin: powderblue;\">\n

        <H1> Eyi ni akọle </H1>\n
        <p> Eyi ni ìpínrọ kan. </p>\n

        </body>\n
        Awọ ọrọ HTML\n
        Ohun-ini awọ ṣe asọye awọ ọrọ fun nkan HTML:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <h1 ara = \"awọ: bulu;\"> Eyi ni akọle </H1>\n
        <p style = \"awọ: pupa;\"> Eyi ni ìpínrọ kan. </p>\n\n
        Awọn awọn nkọwe HTML\n
        Ohun-ini fonti idile tumọ si fonti lati ṣee lo fun nkan HTML:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <h1 style = \"font-family: verdana;\"> Eyi ni akọle </H1>\n
        <p style = \"font-family: Oluranse;\"> Eyi ni ìpínrọ kan. </p>\n\n
        Iwọn ọrọ HTML\n
        Ohun-ini font-iwọn asọye iwọn ọrọ fun nkan HTML:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <h1 style = \"font-size: 300;\"> Eyi ni akọle </H1>\n
        <p style = \"font-size: 160;\"> Eyi ni ìpínrọ kan. </p>\n\n
        HTML Text Atunse\n
        Ohun-ini-aligning ohun ini asọye titete ọrọ petele fun nkan HTML:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <h1 ara = \"ọrọ-align: aarin;\"> Ṣiṣẹ-ori Century </H1>\n
        <p style = \"ọrọ-align: aarin;\"> Aarin-ọrọ. </p>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_html_lesson_six"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tHTML Awọn kilasi Irisi\n\n
        A lo aami kilasi HTML lati ṣe itumọ awọn aza deede fun awọn eroja pẹlu orukọ kilasi kanna.\n
        Nitorinaa, gbogbo awọn eroja HTML pẹlu abuda kilasi kanna ni yoo ni ọna kika kanna ati ara.\n
        Nibi a ni awọn eroja <div> mẹta ti o tọka si orukọ kilasi kanna:\n\n
        <! DOCTYPE HTML>\n
        <html>\n
        <head>\n
        <style>\n
        . awọn ilu {\n
          awọ-lẹhin: dudu;\n
          awọ: funfun;\n
          ala: 20px;\n
          ohun elo fifọ: 20px;\n
        }\n
        </style>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n
        \n
        <div kilasi = \"awọn ilu\">\n
          <H2> London </H2>\n
          <p> London ni olu ilu England. </p>\n
        </div>\n
        \n
        <div kilasi = \"awọn ilu\">\n
          <H2> Paris </h2>\n
          <p> Paris ni olu-ilu Faranse. </p>\n
        </div>\n
        \n
        <div kilasi = \"awọn ilu\">
          <H2> Tokyo </H2>\n
          <p> Tokyo ni olu-ilu Japan. </p>\n
        </div>\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n
        HTML Awọn id Ẹya ara ẹrọ\n\n

        Oniwun id naa ṣalaye idamọ alailẹgbẹ fun nkan HTML (iye naa gbọdọ jẹ alailẹgbẹ laarin iwe HTML).\n
        Iye id naa le ṣee lo nipasẹ CSS ati JavaScript lati ṣe awọn iṣẹ kan fun ipin alailẹgbẹ kan pẹlu iye id pàtó kan.\n
        Ni CSS, lati yan nkan pẹlu id kan pato, kọ ohun kikọ ti elile (#), atẹle nipa id ti ano:\n
        <style>\n
        #myHeader {\n
          awọ-awọ lẹhin: gilasi ina;\n
          awọ: dudu;\n
          ohun elo fifọ: 40px;\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
        }\n
        </style>
        \n
        <h1 id = \"myHeader\"> Akọri mi </H1>\n\n
        Akiyesi: A le lo iduu id naa lori eyikeyi nkan HTML.\n
        Akiyesi: Iye id jẹ ifamọra ọran.\n
        Akiyesi: Iye id naa gbọdọ ni ohun kikọ ti o kere ju, ati pe ko gbọdọ ni ipo alafo (awọn aaye, awọn taabu, bbl).\n
        Iyato laarin Kilasi ati ID\n
        Ẹya HTML kan le ni idamọ alailẹgbẹ kan ti o jẹ ti ẹda kanna, lakoko ti o le lo orukọ kilasi kan nipasẹ awọn eroja pupọ:\n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of Yoruba HTML Contents -->

    <!-- HTML Igbo Contents -->

    <string name="ib_html_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        Gini bu HTML?\n\n
        HTML bụ asụsụ ndebiri maka ịmebe ibe weebụ.\n
        \t• HTML nọchiri anya Asụsụ Hype Text Markup\n
        \t• HTML na-akọwa nhazi nke ibe ya site na iji akara ede\n
        \t• Ihe HTML bu ulo nke ulo HTML\n
        \t• Ihe HTML na-anọchite anya ya site na mkpado\n
        \t• HTML na mkpado gosipụtara ọdịnaya nke ọdịnaya dịka \"isi\", \"paragraf\", \"tebụl\", na ndị ọzọ\n
        \t• Ihe nchoputa egosighi ihe ngosi HTML, kama jiri ha gosiputa ọdịnaya peeji a\n
        Akwụkwọ Dị Mfe HTML\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <! DOCTYPE HTML>\n
        <html>\n
        <isi>\n
        <title> Peeji Mbụ </title>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n

        <h1> Isiokwu Mbụ M </h1>\n
        paragraf nke mbụ m. pp\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n
        A kọwara\n
        \t• Nkwupụta <! DOCTYPE HTML> na-akọwapụta akwụkwọ a ka ọ bụrụ HTML5\n
        \t• Ihe <html> bụ mgbọrọgwụ nke ibe HTML\n
        \t• Akụkụ <head> nwere ozi meta banyere akwụkwọ a\n
        \t• Akụkụ <title> na-akọwapụta aha maka akwụkwọ ahụ\n
        \t• Akụkụ <body> nwere ọdịnaya a na-ahụ anya\n
        \t• Akụkụ <h1> na-akọwapụta isi okwu\n
        \t• Ihe <p> na-akọwapụta paragraph\n\n
        Ntinye HTML\n
        HTML na mkpado bu aha mmeghe nke akuku ejiri akuku gosiputara:\n
        HTML HTML na -adakarị ụzọ abụọ dị ka <p> na </p>\n
        \t• Mkpado mbụ n\’ime otu ụzọ bụ mkpado mmalite, akara nke abụọ bụ akara ikpeazụ\n
        \t• A na-ede mkpado njedebe dị ka mkpado mmalite, mana ejiri ntanetị gaa n\'ihu tupu ịpị aha mkpado\n\n
        Nkwupụta <! DOCTYPE> Nkwupụta\n
        Nkwupụta <! DOCTYPE> na-anọchite anya ụdị akwụkwọ a, ma na-enyere ndị nchọgharị aka igosipụta ibe weebụ nke ọma.\n
        Ọ ga-apụta otu ugboro, n\'elu nke ibe (n\'ihu mkpado HTML ọ bụla).\n
        Nkwupụta <! DOCTYPE> ahụ adịghị ama Ọ bụrụ na ọnye iche na-emetụta ọdịiche dị n\'etiti mkpụrụedemede na obere mkpụrụedemede na-emetụ ntaramahụhụ (-
        Ihe <! DOCTYPE> bu nkwupụta maka HTML5\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_html_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\t\Ndị editọ HTML\n\n
        \tDee HTML iji notepad ma ọ bụ TextEdit\n
        Enwere ike ịmepụta ma dozie ibe weebụ site na iji ndị editọ HTML ndị ọkachamara.\n
        Agbanyeghị, maka ịmụ HTML anyị na-akwado nchịkọta akụkọ ederede dị ka Notepad (PC) ma ọ bụ TextEdit (Mac).\n
        Anyị kwenyere na iji nchịkọta ederede dị mfe bụ ụzọ dị mma iji mụta HTML.\n
        Soro usoro anọ n\'okpuru iji mepụta ibe weebụ mbụ gị na Notepad ma ọ bụ TextEdit.\n\n
        Kwụpụ 1: Mepee akara (PC)\n
        Windows 8 ma ọ bụ mgbe e mesịrị:\n
        Mepee mbido Start (akara ngosi windo nke ala aka na ihu gi). Pịnye akara.\n
        Windows 7 ma ọ bụ tupu:\n
        Mepee Mbido> Mmemme> Ngwa mma> Ndenye ederede\n\n
        Nzọụkwụ 2: Mepee TextEdit (Mac)\n
        Mepe emepe> Ngwa> TextEdit\n
        Gbanwee ụfọdụ ihe ịchọrọ iji nweta ngwa ịchekwaa n\'ụzọ ziri ezi. Na Mmasị> Usoro> họrọ \"Ederede Akwụkwọ\"\n
        Wee n\'okpuru \"Mepee ma chekwaa\", lelee igbe nke kwuru \"Gosiputa HTML faịlụ dị ka koodu HTML kama ederede ederede\".\n
        Mepee akwukwo ohuru iji tinye koodu.\n\n
        Kwụpụ 3: Chekwaa HTML Page\n
        Chekwaa faịlị na kọmputa gị. Họrọ Faịlụ> Chekwa dị ka ihe atụ n\’ime menu.\n
        Kpọọ aha faịlụ ahụ \n"index.htm\n" ma debe ntinye ka ọ bụrụ UTF-8 (nke bụ ntanetị ahọrọ maka faịlụ HTML).\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_html_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tAkwụkwọ HTML\n\n
        \tAkwụkwọ HTML niile ga-ebido site na nkwupụta ụdị akwụkwọ: <! DOCTYPE html>.\n
        Akwụkwọ HTML n\’onwe ya na-amalite na <html> ma jiri njedebe </html> kwụsị.\n
        Akụkụ a na-ahụ anya na akwụkwọ HTML dị n\'etiti <body> na </body>.\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <! DOCTYPE HTML>\n
        <html>\n
        <body>\n

        <h1> Isiokwu Mbụ M </h1>\n
        paragraf nke mbụ m. pp\n

        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        \tIsi Okwu HTML\n
        A kọwara isi okwu HTML na mkpado <h1> na <h6>.\n
        <h1> na-akọwapụta isiokwu kachasị mkpa. <h6> na-akọwa isi okwu kachasị mkpa:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <h1> Nke a na-aga 1 </h1>\n
        <h2> Nke a na-aga 2 </h2>\n
        <h3> Nke a na-aga 3 </h3>\n\n
         \tParagraf HTML\n
        A na-akọwa paragraf HTML na mkpado <p>:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <p> Nke a bụ paragraf\n
        <p> Nke a bụ paragraf ọzọ. </p>\n\n
        \tNjikọ HTML\n
        Ekowara njikọ HTML na njirimara <a>:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <a href=\"https://www.codeafrica.com\"> Nke a bụ njikọ </a>\n
        Kuputara ebe aga-ejikọ njikọ ahụ na njiri href.\n
        A na-eji njirimara iji nye ozi ndị ọzọ gbasara ihe HTML.\n
        Will ga-amatakwu banyere àgwà na isiakwụkwọ na-esote.\n\n
        \tIhe osise HTML\n
        A na-akọwa ihe ngosi HTML na mkpado <img>.\n
        Enyere faịlụ (src), ederede ọzọ (alt), obosara, na ịdị elu dị ka njiri:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\" alt = \"ewu\" obosara = \"104\" elu = \"142\">\n\n
        \tBọtị HTML\n
        Ekpesiri bọtịnụ HTML na mkpado <button>:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <button> Pịa m </button>\n
        \tNtinye HTML\n
        Edere ndepụta HTML na njirimara <ul> (enweghị ndepụta / mgbọ) ma ọ bụ mkpado <ol> (nke nyere iwu / ọnụọgụ), na - agbaso akara ngosi <li> (depụta ihe):\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n\n
        <ul>\n
          <li> Kọfị </li>\n
          <li> Tea </li>\n
          <li> Mmiri ara ehi </li>\n
        </ul>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_html_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tIhe efu HTML\n\n
        \tA na-akpọ ihe HTML na-enweghị ọdịnaya a na-akpọ ihe efu.\n
        <br> bụ ihe efu na-enweghị mkpado mkpọchi (akara njirisi ahụ na-akọwa nhado ahịrị):\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <p> Nke a bụ paragraf <br> <br> nwere akara\n\n
        Njirimara HTML\n
        \t• Ihe HTML niile nwere ike inwe njirimara\n
        \t• Njirimara na-enye ozi ndị ọzọ gbasara otu\n
        \t• A na-akọwapụta njirimara oge niile na mkpado mbido\n
        \t• Njirimara na-abụkarị n\'aha / uru ụzọ abụọ dị ka: aha = \"uru\"\n\n
        Na href mara\n
        A na-akọwa njikọ HTML na mkpado <a>. Ezipụtala njikọ njikọta ahụ na njiri href:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <a href=\"#\"> Nke a bụ njikọ </a>\n\n
        \tMara src\n
        A na-akọwa ihe ngosi HTML na mkpado <img>.\n
        A na-akọwapụtara aha nke ihe oyiyi ahụ na src àgwà:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\">\n\n
        \tOgo na ogo mara\n
        Ihe onyonyo na HTML nwere udiri nha, nke na-akowa obosara ya na idi elu ya.\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <img src = \"goat.jpg\" obosara = \"500\" elu = \"600\">\n
        \tNgosiputa alt\n\n
        Alt àgwà na-ezipụta ederede ọzọ ka aga-eji, mgbe enweghị ike igosipụta ihe onyonyo.\n
        Ndị na-agụ ihuenyo nwere ike ịgụ uru nke omume ahụ. N\'ụzọ a, mmadụ \"na-ege ntị\" webpage, dịka. onye ọhụhụ ụzọ, nwere ike \"nụ\" mmewere.\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <img src = \"jaket.jpg\" alt = \"Nwa agbọghọ nwere jaketị\">\n
        Njirimara alt dịkwa uru ma ọ bụrụ na eserese ahụ adịghị:\n
        \tAttdị maran\n
        A na-eji ụdị ejiji ahụ akọwapụta ụdị nke otu ihe, dị ka agba, font, nha wdg.\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <p style = \"color: red\"> Abụ m paragraf </p>\n\n
        \tIsi Okwu HTML\n
        A kọwara isi okwu na <h1> na <h6> mkpado.\n
        <h1> na-akọwapụta isiokwu kachasị mkpa. <h6> na akowaputa isi okwu di nkpa.\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <h1> Isi 1 </h1>\n
        <h2> Isi 2 </h2>\n
        <h3> Isi 3 </h3>\n
        <h4> Isi 4 </h4>\n
        <h5> Isi 5 </h5>\n
        <h6> Isi nke 6 </h6>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_html_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tNjirimara Nleta HTML\n\n
        \tTingtọ ụdị nke HTML nwere ike mezie ya.\n
        Njirimara HTML nwere ụdị syntax ndị a:\n
        <mkpado ụdị = \"akụ: uru;\">\n
        Ngwongwo bu ihe ndi CSS. Ihe bara uru bu ihe omuma CSS.\n
        Will ga-amatakwu gbasara CSS n\’ozi nkuzi a.\n\n
        \tHTML Mụrụ ụcha\n
        Ngwongwo na agba na-akọwa agba dị n\’okirikiri maka ihe HTML.\n
        Ihe atụ a setịpụrụ ụcha agba maka ibe iji mee ka akwụkwọ mmịrị pụta:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <ahu ụdị = \"ndabere-agba: powderblue;\">\n

        <h1> Nke a bụ isiokwu </h1>\n
        <p> Nke a bụ paragraf\n

        </body>\n\n
        \tAgba ederede HTML\n
        Akụ na agba na-akọwa agba ederede maka otu HTML:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <h1 style = \"agba: acha anụnụ;"> Nke a bụ isiokwu </h1>\n
        <p style = \"agba: ọbara;\"> Nke a bụ paragraf\n\n
        \tFonts HTML\n
        Ngwunye font-ezinụlọ na-akọwapụta font a ga-eji mee ihe maka HTML:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <h1 style = \"font-family: verdana;\"> Nke a bụ isiokwu </h1>\n
        <p style = \"font-family: courier;\"> Nke a bụ paragraf. </p>\n\n
        \tNtuzi ederede HTML\n
        Ngwongwo font-size na-akọwa nha ederede maka ihe HTML:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <h1 style = \"font-size: 300;\"> Nke a bụ isiokwu </h1>\n
        <p style = \"font-size: 160;\"> Nke a bụ paragraf. </p>\n
        \tNtinye ederede HTML\n
        Ndenye-mmezi akụ na-akọwa kwụpụta ederede itinye n\'ọnọdụ maka HTML mmewere:\n\n
        Ihe Nlereanya\n
        <h1 ụdị = \"ederede-mmezi: etiti;\"> Ebe a na-agbago </h1>\n
        <p style = \"ederede-mmezi: etiti;\"> paragraf etiti. </p>\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_html_lesson_six"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tHTML Klaasị Njirimara\n\n
        \tA na-eji njikwa HTML otu kọwaa ụdị ejiji maka ihe na otu klas ahụ.\n
        Yabụ, ihe HTML niile nwere otu klaasị ga-enwe otu usoro na ụdị.\n
        Lee, anyị nwere ihe <dized> atọ na-arụtụ aka na otu klaasị:\n\n
        <! DOCTYPE HTML>\n
        <html>\n
        <isi>\n
        <style> \n
        .isi {\n
          ụcha n\’azụ: nwa ojii;\n
          agba: ọcha;\n
          oke: 20px;\n
          padding: 20px;\n
        }\n
        </style>\n
        </head>\n
        <body>\n
        \n
        <div klas = \"obodo\">\n
          <h2> London </h2>\n
          <p> London bu isi obodo England. </p>\n
        </div>\n
        \n
        <div klas = \"obodo\">\n
          <h2> Paris </h2>\n
          <p> Paris bụ isi obodo France. </p>\n
        </div>\n
        \n
        <div klas = \"obodo\">\n
          <h2> Tokyo </h2>\n
          <p> Tokyo bụ isi obodo Japan. </p>\n
        </div>\n
        \n
        </body>\n
        </html>\n\n
        \tHTML Njirimara id\n

        Njirimara id na-ezipụta id pụrụ iche maka ihe HTML (ọnụahịa ahụ ga-apụ iche n\'ime akwụkwọ HTML).\n
        CSS na JavaScript nwere ike iji rụọ ọrụ ụfọdụ maka otu ihe pụrụ iche na uru aha akọwapụtara.\n
        Na CSS, iji họrọ otu ihe nwere otu ụdị aha, dee agwa hash (#), sochiri akara nke mmewere:\n\n
        <style>\n
        #myHeader {\n
          ụcha n\’azụ: ọkụ;\n
          agba: ojii;\n
          padding: 40px;\n
          ederede-align: center;\n
        }\n
        </style>\n

        <h1 id = \"myHeader\"> Onye isi m </h1>\n\n
        NDpMỌD:: Enwere ike iji njirimara id na ihe HTML ọ bụla.\n
        Mara: Ngosi nke id na-emetuta ya.\n
        Mara: Uru id ga-enweriri opekata mpe otu, ma agaghị enwe cha (oghere, taabụ, wdg).\n
        Ọdịiche dị n\'etiti Klas na NJ\n
        Ihe HTML nwere ike inwe naanị otu ihe pụrụ iche nwere so na otu mmele, ebe ọtụtụ ihe nwere ike iji klaasị klas:\n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of Igbo HTML Contents -->
    <!-- End of HTML Contents -->

    <!-- CSS contents -->
    <!-- English CSS Contents -->
    <string name="en_css_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tCSS Introduction\n\n\n
        \tWhat is CSS?\n
        \t CSS stands for Cascading Style Sheets\n
        \t CSS describes how HTML elements are to be displayed on screen, paper, or in other media\n
        \t CSS saves a lot of work. It can control the layout of multiple web pages all at once\n
        \t External stylesheets are stored in CSS files\n\n
        Why Use CSS? \n
        \t CSS is used to define styles for your web pages, including the design, layout and variations in display for different devices and screen sizes.\n\n

        CSS Solved a Big Problem\n
        \t HTML was NEVER intended to contain tags for formatting a web page! \n
        \t HTML was created to describe the content of a web page, like: \n
        \t <h1>This is a heading</h1>\n
        \t <p>This is a paragraph.</p>\n
        \t When tags like <font>, and color attributes were added to the HTML 3.2 specification, it started a nightmare for web developers. Development of large websites, where fonts and color information were added to every single page, became a long and expensive process. \n
        \t To solve this problem, the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) created CSS. \n
        \t CSS removed the style formatting from the HTML page! \n
        \t CSS Saves a Lot of Work! \n
        \t The style definitions are normally saved in external .css files. \n
        \t With an external stylesheet file, you can change the look of an entire website by changing just one file!\n\n

        CSS Syntax and Selectors\n

        \t CSS Syntax\n
        \t A CSS rule-set consists of a selector and a declaration block: \n

        \t The selector points to the HTML element you want to style. \n
        \t The declaration block contains one or more declarations separated by semicolons. \n
        \t Each declaration includes a CSS property name and a value, separated by a colon. \n
        \t A CSS declaration always ends with a semicolon, and declaration blocks are surrounded by curly braces. \n
        \t In the following example all <p> elements will be center-aligned, with a red text color: \n\n

        \t Example\n
        \t p {\n
         \t color: red; \n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t CSS Selectors\n
        \t CSS selectors are used to \"find\" (or select) HTML elements based on their element name, id, class, attribute, and more.\n\n

        \t The element Selector\n
        \t The element selector selects elements based on the element name. \n
        \t You can select all <p> elements on a page like this (in this case, all <p> elements will be center-aligned, with a red text color): \n\n

        Example\n
        \t p {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t }\n\n

        \t The id Selector\n
        \t The id selector uses the id attribute of an HTML element to select a specific element. \n
        \t The id of an element should be unique within a page, so the id selector is used to select one unique element! \n
        \t To select an element with a specific id, write a hash (#) character, followed by the id of the element. \n
        \t The style rule below will be applied to the HTML element with id=\"para1\":\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t #para1 {\n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n
        \t The class Selector\n
        \t The class selector selects elements with a specific class attribute. \n
        \t To select elements with a specific class, write a period (.) character, followed by the name of the class. \n
        \t In the example below, all HTML elements with class=\"center\" will be red and center-aligned: \n
         \t Example\n
        \t.center {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n

        \t You can also specify that only specific HTML elements should be affected by a class. \n
        \t In the example below, only <p> elements with class=\"center\" will be center-aligned: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t p.center {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n

        \t HTML elements can also refer to more than one class. \n
        \t In the example below, the <p> element will be styled according to class=\"center\" and to class=\"large\":\n
        \t Example
        \t <p class=\"center large\">This paragraph refers to two classes.</p> \n

        \t Note: A class name cannot start with a number! \n

        \t Grouping Selectors\n
        \t If you have elements with the same style definitions, like this: \n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        }\n

        \t p {\n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n

        \t It will be better to group the selectors, to minimize the code. \n
        \t To group selectors, separate each selector with a comma. \n
        \t In the example below we have grouped the selectors from the code above:\n
        \t Example \n
        \t h1, h2, p {\n
         \t text-align: center;\n
          \t color: red;\n
        \t } \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_css_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tTYPES OF STYLING SHEET\n
        \t Three Ways to Insert CSS\n
        \t There are three ways of inserting a style sheet: \n
        \t External style sheet\n
        \t Internal style sheet\n
        \t Inline style\n

        External Style Sheet\n
        \t With an external style sheet, you can change the look of an entire website by\n
        \t changing just one file! \n
        \t Each page must include a reference to the external style sheet file inside the <link>\n \t element. The <link> element goes inside the <head> section: \n
        \t Example\n
        <head>\n
        <link rel=\"stylesheet\" type=\"text/css\" href=\"mystyle.css\">\n
        </head> \n
        \t An external style sheet can be written in any text editor. The file should not contain\n \tany html tags. The style sheet file must be saved with a .css extension. \n
        \t Here is how the \"mystyle.css\" looks: \n
        \tbody {\n
        \t  background-color: lightblue; \n
        \t}\n\n

        \th1 {\n
         \t color: navy; \n
         \t margin-left: 20px; \n
        \t} \n
        \t Note: Do not add a space between the property value and the unit (such as margin-left\n
        \t: 20 px;). The correct way is: margin-left: 20px; \n\n


        Internal Style Sheet\n
        \t An internal style sheet may be used if one single page has a unique style. \n
        \t Internal styles are defined within the <style> element, inside the <head> section of an \t HTML page: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t<head>\n
        \t<style>\n
        \tbody {\n
         \tbackground-color: linen; \n
        \t}\n

        \th1 {\n
        \t  color: maroon; \n
         \t margin-left: 40px; \n
        \t} \n
        \t</style>\n
        \t</head> \n\n

        Inline Styles\n
        \t An inline style may be used to apply a unique style for a single element. \n
        \t To use inline styles, add the style attribute to the relevant element. The style\n \tattribute can contain any CSS property. \n
        \t The example below shows how to change the color and the left margin of a <h1>\n \telement: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t <h1 style=\"color:blue;margin-left:30px;\"/>This is a heading</h1> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_css_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tCSS Backgrounds\n
        The CSS background properties are used to define the \n background effects for elements.\n
        \t CSS background properties: \n
        \t background-color\n
         \t background-image\n
         \t background-repeat\n
         \t background-attachment\n
         \t background-position\n\n

        \t Background Color\n
         \t The background-color property specifies the background color of an element. \n
         \t The background color of a page is set like this: \n
         \t Example\n
         \t body { \n
         \t background-color: lightblue; \n
         \t }\n\n

        \tWith CSS, a color is most often specified by: \n
        \t a valid color name - like \"red\" \n
         \t a HEX value - like \"#ff0000\" \n
         \t an RGB value - like \"rgb(255,0,0)\" \n
        \t In the example below, the <h1>, <p>, and <div> elements have different background \tcolors: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  background-color: green;\n
        \t }\n

        \t div {\n
         \t background-color: lightblue;\n
        \t }\n

        \t p {\n
        \t  background-color: yellow;\n
        \t }\n\n

        \t Background Image\n
        \t The background-image property specifies an image to use as the background of an element. \n
        \t By default, the image is repeated so it covers the entire element. \n
        \t The background image for a page can be set like this: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t body { \n
         \t background-image: url(\"paper.gif\"); \n
        \t } \n
         \t Below is an example of a bad combination of text and background image. The text is \t hardly readable: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"bgdesert.jpg\");\n
        \t } \n
        \t Note: When using a background image, use an image that does not disturb the text. \n\n

        \t Background Image - Repeat Horizontally or Vertically\n
        \t By default, the background-image property repeats an image both horizontally and vertically.\n
        \t Some images should be repeated only horizontally or vertically, or they will look strange, like this:\n
        \t Example\n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\");\n
        \t }\n
        \t If the image above is repeated only horizontally (background-repeat: repeat-x;), the background will look better: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: repeat-x; \n
        \t } \n
        \t Tip: To repeat an image vertically, set background-repeat: repeat-y; \n\n

        Background Image - Set position and no-repeat\n
        \t Showing the background image only once is also specified by the background-repeat \n property: \n
        Example\n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t } \n
        \t The position of the image is specified by the background-position property: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
         \t background-position: right top; \n
        \t  } \n\n

        Background Image - Fixed position\n
        \t To specify that the background image should be fixed (will not scroll with the rest of\n
        \t the page), use the background-attachment property: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\");  \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t  background-position: right top; \n
        \t  background-attachment: fixed; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Border Width\n
        \t The border-width property specifies the width of the four borders.\n
        \t The width can be set as a specific size (in px, pt, cm, em, etc) or by using one of the\n \t three pre-defined values: thin, medium, or thick. \n
        \t The border-width property can have from one to four values (for the top border, right\n \t border, bottom border, and the left border). \n
        \t Example\n
        \t p.one { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: 5px; \n
        }\n

        \t p.two { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: medium; \n
        }\n

        \t p.three {\n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-width: 2px 10px 4px 20px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Border Color\n
        \t The border-color property is used to set the color of the four borders. \n
        \t The color can be set by: \n
        \t name - specify a color name, like \"red\" \n
        \t Hex - specify a hex value, like \"#ff0000\" \n
        \t RGB - specify a RGB value, like \"rgb(255,0,0)\" \n
        \t Transparent \n
        \t The border-color property can have from one to four values (for the top border, right \n
        \t border, bottom border, and the left border). \n
        \t If border-color is not set, it inherits the color of the element. \n
        \t Red border \n
        \t Example \n
        \t p.one { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: red; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.two { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: green; \n
        \t } \n

        \t p.three { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-color: red green blue yellow; \n
        \t }  \n\n

        Border - Individual Sides \n
        \t From the examples above you have seen that it is possible to specify a different \n
        \t border for each side. \n
        \t In CSS, there are also properties for specifying each of the borders (top, right, \n
        \t bottom, and left): \n
        \t Different Border Styles \n
        \t Example \n
        \t p { \n
        \t  border-top-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-right-style: solid; \n
         \t border-bottom-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-left-style: solid; \n
        \t } \n
        \t The example above gives the same result as this: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t p { \n
         \t border-style: dotted solid; \n
        \t } \n
        \t So, here is how it works: \n
        \t If the border-style property has four values: \n
        \t border-style: dotted solid double dashed; \n
        \t top border is dotted \n
        \t right border is solid \n
        \t bottom border is double \n
        \t left border is dashed \n
        \t If the border-style property has three values: \n
        \t border-style: dotted solid double;  \n
        \t top border is dotted \n
        \t right and left borders are solid \n
        \t bottom border is double \n
        \t If the border-style property has two values: \n
        \t border-style: dotted solid; \n
        \t top and bottom borders are dotted\n
        \t right and left borders are solid\n
        \t If the border-style property has one value: \n
        border-style: dotted; \n
        all four borders are dotted\n
        \t The border-style property is used in the example above. However, it also works with\n
        \t border-width and border-color. \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_css_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tCSS Margin - Individual Sides\n
        \tCSS has properties for specifying the margin for each side of an element: \n
        \tmargin-top\n
        \tmargin-right\n
        \tmargin-bottom\n
        \tmargin-left\n
        \tAll the margin properties can have the following values: \n
        \tauto - the browser calculates the margin\n
        \tlength - specifies a margin in px, pt, cm, etc.\n
        \tinherit - specifies that the margin should be inherited from the parent element\n
        \tTip: Negative values are allowed. \n
        \tThe following example sets different margins for all four sides of a <p> element: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t p {
          \t margin-top: 100px;
         \t margin-bottom: 100px;
         \t margin-right: 150px;
         \t margin-left: 80px;
        \t }\n\n

        Margin - Shorthand Property\n
        To shorten the code, it is possible to specify all the margin properties in one property.\n
        The margin property is a shorthand property for the following individual margin properties: \n
        \t margin-top\n
        \t margin-right\n
        \t margin-bottom\n
        \t margin-left\n
        \t So, here is how it works: \n
        \t If the margin property has four values: \n
        \t margin: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t top margin is 25px\n
        \t right margin is 50px\n
        \t bottom margin is 75px\n
        \t left margin is 100px\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t } \n
        \t If the margin property has three values: \n
        \t margin: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t top margin is 25px\n
        \t right and left margins are 50px\n
        \t bottom margin is 75px\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t } \n
        \t If the margin property has two values: \n
        \t margin: 25px 50px; \n
        \t top and bottom margins are 25px\n
        \t right and left margins are 50px\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px; \n
        \t } \n
        \t If the margin property has one value: \n
        \t margin: 25px; \n
        \t all four margins are 25px\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px; \n
        \t } \n\n

         CSS Padding - Individual Sides\n
        \t CSS has properties for specifying the padding for each side of an element: \n
        \t padding-top\n
        \t padding-right\n
        \t padding-bottom\n
        \t padding-left\n
        \t All the padding properties can have the following values: \n
        \t length - specifies a padding in px, pt, cm, etc. \n
        \t inherit - specifies that the padding should be inherited from the parent element\n
        \t Note: Negative values are not allowed. \n
        \t The following example sets different padding for all four sides of a <div> element:\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t div {\n
         \t padding-top: 50px; \n
         \t padding-right: 30px; \n
         \t padding-bottom: 50px; \n
          \t padding-left: 80px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Padding - Shorthand Property\n
        \t To shorten the code, it is possible to specify all the padding properties in one property.\n
        \t The padding property is a shorthand property for the following individual padding\n
         \t properties: \n
        \t padding-top\n
        \t padding-right\n
        \t padding-bottom\n
        \t padding-left\n
        \t So, here is how it works: \n
        \t If the padding property has four values: \n
        \t padding: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t top padding is 25px\n
        \t right padding is 50px\n
        \t bottom padding is 75px\n
        \t left padding is 100px\n
        \t Example\n\n
        \t div {\n
        \t  padding: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t } \n
        \t If the padding property has three values: \n
        \t padding: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t top padding is 25px\n
        \t right and left paddings are 50px\n
        \t bottom padding is 75px\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t div {\n
        \t  padding: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t }\n\n
        \t If the padding property has two values: \n
        \t padding: 25px 50px; \n
        \t top and bottom paddings are 25px\n
        \t right and left paddings are 50px \n
        \t If the padding property has one value: \n
        \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t all four padding are 25px\n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t p {\n
         \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t}\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_css_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\tCSS Text\n\n

        Text Color\n
        \t The color property is used to set the color of the text. The color is specified by: \n
        \t a color name - like \"red\"\n
        \t The default text color for a page is defined in the body selector. \n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t body {\n
        \t  color: blue; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h1 {\n
         \t color: green; \n
        \t } \n\n
        Text Alignment\n
        \t The text-align property is used to set the horizontal alignment of a text. \n
        \t A text can be left or right aligned, centered, or justified. \n
        \t The following example shows center aligned, and left and right aligned text (left alignment is default if text direction is left-to-right, and right alignment is default if
        text direction is right-to-left): \n\n
        Example\n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
        \t  text-align: left; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Text Decoration\n
        \t The text-decoration property is used to set or remove decorations from text. \n
        \t The value text-decoration: none; is often used to remove underlines from links: \n\n
        Example\n
        \t a {\n
        \t  text-decoration: none; \n
        \t } \n
        \t The other text-decoration values are used to decorate text: \n\n
        Example\n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-decoration: overline; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
         \t text-decoration: line-through; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Text Transformation\n
        \t The text-transform property is used to specify uppercase and lowercase letters in a text. \n
        \t It can be used to turn everything into uppercase or lowercase letters, or capitalize the \n
        \t first letter of each word: \n\n
        Example\n
        \t p.uppercase {\n
         \t text-transform: uppercase; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.lowercase {\n
        \t  text-transform: lowercase; \n
        \t }\n\n

        CSS Fonts\n
        \t Font Family\n
        \t The font family of a text is set with the font-family property. \n
        \t The font-family property should hold several font names as a /"fallback"/ system. If the \n
        \t browser does not support the first font, it tries the next font, and so on. \n
        \t Start with the font you want, and end with a generic family, to let the browser pick a\n
        \t similar font in the generic family, if no other fonts are available. \n
        \t Note: If the name of a font family is more than one word, it must be in quotation marks, \n
        \t like: \"Times New Roman\".\n
        \t More than one font family is specified in a comma-separated list: \n\n
        Example\n
        \t p {\n
         \t font-family: \"Times New Roman\", Times, serif; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Font Style\n
        \t The font-style property is mostly used to specify italic text. \n
        \t This property has three values: \n
        \t normal - The text is shown normally\n
         \t italic - The text is shown in italics\n
        \t oblique - The text is \"leaning\" (oblique is very similar to italic, but less \n supported) \n\n
        \t Example\n
        \t p.normal {\n
          font-style: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.italic {\n
          font-style: italic; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.oblique {\n
          font-style: oblique; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Font Size With Pixels\n
        \t Setting the text size with pixels gives you full control over the text size: \n\n
        Example\n
        \t h1 {\n
          \t font-size: 40px; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
          \t font-size: 30px; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Font Weight\n
        \t The font-weight property specifies the weight of a font: \n\n
        Example\n
        \t p.normal {\n
         \t font-weight: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.thick {\n
         \t font-weight: bold; \n
        \t} \n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- end of English CSS Contents -->

    <!-- Hausa CSS Contents -->
    <string name="ha_css_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
         \t\t\tGabatarwa CSS \n\n
        \t Menene CSS? \n
        • \t CSS na tsaye ga Cascading Style Sheets \n
        • \t CSS ya bayyana yadda za a nuna abubuwan HTML a allon, takarda, ko a wasu kafofin watsa labarai
        • \t CSS yana adana ayyuka da yawa. Zai iya sarrafa shimfidar shafukan yanar gizo da yawa gaba daya \n
        • \t Ana adana hanyoyin gado na waje cikin fayilolin CSS \n
        Me Yasa Amfani da CSS? \n
        \t Ana amfani da CSS don ayyana salon don shafukan yanar gizonku, gami da ƙira, shimfiɗa da bambanci a cikin nuni don na\'urori daban-daban da girman allo.\n\n

        CSS ta magance Matsala babba \n
        \t HTML ba\'a taɓa tunanin ta ƙunshi alama don tsara shafin yanar gizo ba! \n
        \t HTML an kirkireshi ne domin bayyana abubuwan da ke cikin shafin yanar gizo, kamar: \n
        \t <h1>This is a heading</h1>\n
        \t <p>This is a paragraph.</p>\n\n

        \t Lokacin da alamomi kamar <font>, kuma aka haɗa sifofin launi zuwa ƙimar HTML 3.2, ya fara mafarki mai ban tsoro ga masu haɓaka yanar gizo. Haɓaka manyan shafukan yanar gizo, inda aka ƙara fonts da bayanai masu launi akan kowane shafi, ya zama tsari mai tsayi da tsada. \n
        \t Don magance wannan matsalar, Kungiyar Hadin Kan Yanar gizo ta Duniya (W3C) ta kirkiro CSS. \n
        \t CSS ta cire Tsarin salon daga shafin HTML! \n
        \t CSS adana yawa na Aiki! \n
        \t Ana fassara ma\'anar salo na al\'ada a cikin fayil ɗin .css na waje. \n
        \t Tare da fayil na saitin waje, zaku iya canza yanayin yanar gizon gaba ɗaya ta canza fayil guda kawai! \n

        Sigar CSS da kuma masu Zaɓu \n\n

        \t CSS Syntax \n
        \t Tsarin mulkin CSS ya kunshi mai zaɓa da kuma toshe sanarwa: \n\n

        \t Mai zaɓar ya nuna alamar HTML ɗin da kake son kwaikwaya. \n
        \t Bayanin shela yana dauke da sanarwa guda ko fiye da keɓaɓɓu na biyu. \n
        \t Kowace sheda ya hada da sunan mallakar CSS da ƙimar ta, wanda mallaka ta raba shi. \n
        \t Bayanin CSS koyaushe yana ƙare tare da babban taron karairayi, kuma ana kewaye da bayyane. \n
        \t A cikin misali mai zuwa duk abubuwan <p> za a daidaita tsakanin su, tare da jan rubutu mai launin ja: \n\n

        \t Misalin \ n
        \t p {\n
         \t color: red; \n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Masu zaɓar CSS \n
        Ana amfani da masu zaɓar CSS don \"nemo\" (ko zaɓi) abubuwan HTML bisa laƙabin sunan asalinsu, id, aji, sifa, da ƙari. \n\n

        \t The element Selector \n
        \t A ɗakin zaɓaɓɓen zaɓin abubuwan zaɓuɓɓuka dangane da sunan kashi. \n
        \t Kuna iya zaɓar dukkan abubuwa <p> a kan wani shafi kamar haka (a wannan yanayin, dukkanin abubuwan <p> za su kasance a tsakiya-hade, tare da launi ja): \n\n

        Misali \n
        \t p {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t da id Selector \n
        \t Maɓallin id yana amfani da sifa id na kayan HTML don zaɓar wani sanannen kashi. \n
        \t Idan id ɗin ya kasance na musamman ne a cikin shafi, saboda haka ana amfani da mai zaɓar id don zaɓar ainihin ɓangaren abu! \n
        \t Don zaɓar wani abu tare da takamaiman id, rubuta harafin zantah (#), bibiyar asalin. \n
        \t Ana amfani da tsarin salon da ke ƙasa zuwa sashin HTML tare da id = \"para1\": \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t #para1 {\n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Maɓallin zaɓin aji \n
        \t Mai zaɓar aji yana zaɓar abubuwa tare da takamaiman sifofin aji. \n
        \t Don zaɓar abubuwa tare da takamaiman aji, rubuta harafin (.) hali, sunan aji. \n
        \t A misalin da ke ƙasa, duk abubuwan HTML tare da aji = \"cibiyar\" za a yi ja kuma a daidaita tsakanin: \n\n
        \t Misalin \ n
        \t.center {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Hakanan zaka iya saka takamaiman abubuwan HTML kawai ya kamata aji ya shafa. \n
        \t A cikin misalin da ke ƙasa, kawai <p> ​​abubuwa tare da aji = \"cibiyar\" za a daidaita tsakanin: \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p.center {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \ t Abubuwan HTML kuma zasu iya magana akan fiye da aji ɗaya. \n
        \ t A cikin misalin da ke ƙasa, sigar <p> za a daidaita ta daidai da aji = \"tsakiya\" kuma zuwa aji = \"babba\": \n\n
        \ t Misali \n
        \t <p class=\"center large\">This paragraph refers to two classes.</p> \n\n


        \ t Lura: Sunaye na aji ba zai fara da lamba ba! \ n

        \ t Rarraba Masu Zaɓuɓɓuka \ n
        \ t Idan kana da abubuwan da ke da fasali iri ɗaya, kamar haka: \ n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        }\n

        \t p {\n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \ t Zai fi kyau a tara masu zaɓaɓɓen, don rage ƙimar lamba. \ n
        \ t Ga masu zaɓaɓɓu, raba kowane zaɓaɓɓun tare da wakafi. \ n
        \ t A misalin da ke ƙasa mun tsara masu zaɓa daga lambar da ke sama: \n\n
        \ t Misalin \ n
        \t h1, h2, p {\n
         \t text-align: center;\n
          \t color: red;\n
        \t } \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_css_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tKYAUTA AKAN KYAUTA \n\n
        \t Hanyoyi Uku don Saka CSS \n
        \t Akwai hanyoyi guda uku na shigar da takardar salo: \n
        • \t Tsarin salo na waje \n
        • \t Akwatin salo na ciki \n
        • \t Tsarin Cikin Gida \n\n

        Rubutun Salon Yanayi \n
        \t Tare da takardar takarda ta waje, zaku iya sauya yanayin gidan yanar gizon ta \n
        \t canza fayil guda kawai! \n
        \t Kowane shafi dole ne ya hada da nuni ga fayil din takardar rubutu na waje a cikin <link>. \n
        \tSashin <link> ɗin yana shiga cikin sashin <head>: \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        <head>\n
        <link rel=\"stylesheet\" type =\"rubutu/css\" href=\"mystyle.css\" />\n
        </head>\n\n
        \t Za a iya rubuta takardar salon waje a kowane edita na rubutu. Fayil ya kamata ya ƙunshi alamun HTML \tany. Dole ne a adana fayil na saitin takardar tare da .css. \n
        \t Here is how the \"mystyle.css\" looks: \n
        \tbody {\n
        \t  background-color: lightblue; \n
        \t}\n

        \th1 {\n
         \t color: navy; \n
         \t margin-left: 20px; \n
        \t} \n

        \t Bayani: Kada a daɗa sarari tsakanin darajar dukiya da naúrar (kamar gefe-hagu: 20 px;). The correct way is: margin-left: 20px; \n\n

        Rubutun Salon Cikin gida \n
        \t Za a iya amfani da takardar salo na ciki idan shafi ɗaya kawai yana da salon musamman. \n
        \t Tsarin ciki an bayyana shi cikin ginin <style>, a cikin sashin <head> wani shafin HTML: \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t Example\n
        \t<head>\n
        \t<style>\n
        \tbody {\n
         \tbackground-color: linen; \n
        \t}\n

        \th1 {\n
        \t  color: maroon; \n
         \t margin-left: 40px; \n
        \t} \n
        \t</style>\n
        \t</head> \n\n

        Salon Incila \n
        \t Ana iya amfani da salon layin rubutu don amfani da wani salo na musamman don abubuwan guda. \n
        \t Don amfani da sahun layi iri ɗaya, ƙara sifayar sifa don dacewa. Salon attribute na iya anyunsar kowane kayan CSS. \n\n

        \t Misalin da ke ƙasa yana nuna yadda ake canza launi da gefen hagu na <h1> element: \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t <h1 style=\"color:blue; margin-left:30px;\">This is a heading</h1> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_css_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
                        \t\t\tBANGO CSS\n\n
        Ana amfani da abubuwan da suka gabata na CSS don ayyana tasirin bango don abubuwan. \n
        \t Bayanan al\'ummomin CSS: \n
        • \t baya-launi \n
        • \t-hoton \n
        • \t baya-maimaita \n
        • \t tushen abin da aka makala \n
        • \t tushen-baya \n\n

        \t Bango mai launi \n
         \t Dukiya mai launi mai launi tana fayyace launi na asalin al\'adar. \n
         \t An sanya asalin shafin kamar haka: \n\n
         \t Misalin \ n
          \t body { \n
         \t background-color: lightblue; \n
         \t }\n\n

        \t CSS, wani launi yakan fi dacewa da: \n
        • \t sunan launi mai inganci - kamar \"ja\" \n
        • \t wani darajar HEX - kamar \"# ff0000\" \n
        • \t an darajar RGB - kamar \"rgb (255,0,0)\" \n
        \t A cikin misalin da ke ƙasa, abubuwan <h1>, <p>, da <div> suna da banbanci masana: \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  background-color: green;\n
        \t }\n

        \t div {\n
         \t background-color: lightblue;\n
        \t }\n

        \t p {\n
        \t  background-color: yellow;\n
        \t }\n\n

        \t Hotunan Bango \n
        \t Ginin-bayan hoton yana nuna hoto don amfani da shi azaman asalin samfurin. \n
        \t Ta hanyar tsoho, ana maimaita hoton don haka ya rufe duka abubuwan. \n
        \t Hoto na baya na shafin za\'a iya saita shi kamar haka: \n\n
        \t Misalin \ n
        \t body { \n
         \t background-image: url(\"paper.gif\"); \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Da ke ƙasa akwai misalin mummunan haɗuwa da rubutu da hoton baya. Rubutun ba wuya ake karanta shi ba: \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"bgdesert.jpg\");\n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Lura: Lokacin amfani da hoton bango, yi amfani da hoto wanda baya rikitar da rubutu. \n\n

        \t Hotunan Bayan Fage - Maimaita kai tsaye ko a kai tsaye\n
        \tTa hanyar tsohuwar, dukiya ta bayan-hoto tana maimaita hoto ta fuska biyu kuma a tsaye.\n
        \t Wasu hotunan yakamata a maimaita su kawai a kwance ko a tsaye, ko kuma za su yi kama da juna, kamar haka:\n\n
        \t Misali \n
        \t body {
         \t background-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\");\n
        \t }\n\n

        \t Idan hoton da ke sama ana maimaita shi kawai a sama (bayan-maimaita: maimaita-x;), bango zai yi kyau: \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: repeat-x; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Tukwici: Don maimaita hoto tsaye, saita bango-maimaita: maimaita-y; \n\n

        Hoton Farko - Sanya matsayi kuma ba-sake \n
        \t Nuna hoton bango kawai sau daya kuma ana tantance shi ta hanyar asalin-maimaita dukiya: \n\n
        Misali \n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t } \n
        \n
        \t Matsayin hoton an tantance shi ta hanyar tushen matsayin: \n\n

        \t Misalin \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
         \t background-position: right top; \n
        \t  } \n\n

        Hoton Fage - Matsayin da aka kafa \n
        \t Don tantance cewa yakamata a daidaita hoton asalin (bazai jujjuya tare da sauran n ba shafin), yi amfani da kayan haɗin-baya: \n\n
        \t Misalin \ n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\");  \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t  background-position: right top; \n
        \t  background-attachment: fixed; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Nisaren kan iyaka \n
        \t propertyasar da ke kan iyaka tana ƙaddara girman kan iyakoki huɗu. \n
        \t Za\'a iya saita nisa azaman takamaiman girman (a px, pt, cm, em, da sauransu) ko ta amfani da ɗayan \n \t uku da aka ƙaddara: bakin ciki, matsakaici, ko kauri. \n
        \t -asar da ke kan iyaka za ta iya kasancewa daga dabi\'u ɗaya zuwa huɗu (don kan iyaka, dama iyaka, iyaka, da iyaka ta hagu). \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p.one { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: 5px; \n
        }\n

        \t p.two { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: medium; \n
        }\n

        \t p.three {\n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-width: 2px 10px 4px 20px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Launi mai iyaka \n
        \t Ana amfani da kadara mai launi-launi don saita launi na kan iyakoki huɗu. \n
        \t Za\'a iya saita launi ta: \n
        • \t suna - saka sunan launi, kamar \"ja\" \n
        • \t Hex - saka ƙimar hex, kamar \"#ff0000\" \n
        • \t RGB - saka darajar RGB, kamar \"rgb (255,0,0)\" \n
        • \t Bayyanawa \n\n
        \t -asar mai launi-launi na iya samun daga dabi\'u ɗaya zuwa huɗu (don kan iyaka, dama, iyakar, iyaka, da iyakar hagu). \n
        \t Idan ba\'a saita launi-iyaka ba, zai gaji daɗin adon. \n
        \t Iyakokin Red \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p.one { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: red; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.two { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: green; \n
        \t } \n

        \t p.three { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-color: red green blue yellow; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Kan iyaka - daidaikun mutane \n
        \t Daga misalan da ke sama kun ga cewa yana yiwuwa a tantance sabanin \n
        \t iyaka ga kowane gefe. \n
        \t A CSS, akwai kuma kaddarorin don tantance kowane kan iyakokin (saman, dama, \n
        \t kasa, da hagu): \n
        \t Tsarin Bango daban-daban \n\n
        \t Misalin \ n
        \t p { \n
        \t  border-top-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-right-style: solid; \n
         \t border-bottom-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-left-style: solid; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \ t Misalin da ke sama yana bada sakamako iri ɗaya kamar haka: \n\n
        \ t Misalin \ n
        \t p { \n
         \t border-style: dotted solid; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Don haka, ga yadda yake aiki: \n
        \t Idan dukiyar da ke kan iyaka tana da dabi\'u huɗa: \n
        • \t iyaka-style: dotted solid dashed; \n
        \sashin saman iyaka yana da alama\n
        \t iyakar iyaka tana da ƙarfi \n
        \t kasan iyakar ta ninka biyu \n\n

         \yankin iyakar hagu ya rushe \n
        \t Idan dukiyar da ke kan iyakar tana da dabi\'u uku: \n
        • \t iyaka-style: dotted m ninki biyu; \n
        \t sashin saman iyaka yana da alama \n
         \t dama da iyakokin hagu suna da ƙarfi \n
         \t kasan iyakar ta ninka biyu \n
        \t Idan dukiyar da ke kan iyaka tana da dabi\'u biyu: \n
        • \t iyaka-style: dotted solid; \n
         \t saman layi da na ƙasa dotted \n
         \t dama da iyakokin hagu suna da ƙarfi \n
        \t Idan dukiyar da ke kan iyakokin tana da darajar guda ɗaya: \n
        • saitin kan iyaka: dotted; \n
          \tduk shingayen hudun suna da ma\'ana \n
        \t Ana amfani da kadarar da ke kan iyaka a misalin da ke sama. Koyaya, yana kuma aiki tare da \n
        \t iyakar iyaka da launi-launi. \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_css_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tGefe(Margin) CSS - Keɓaɓɓun Sides \n\n
        \tCSS yana da kaddarorin don ƙaddara gefe ga kowane ɓangare na abun: \n
        \tmargin-top\n
        \tmargin-right\n
        \tmargin-bottom\n
        \tmargin-left\n\n

        \tDuk abubuwan iyakokin na iya samun waɗannan dabi\'u: \n
        • \tauto - mai binciken yana lissafta gefe & n\n
        • \tlength - ƙayyade gefe a px, pt, cm, da sauransu.\n
        • \tinherit - ƙaddara cewa ya kamata a gajiyar gado daga hannun mahaifinsa \n
        \tTip: An ba da izinin halayen marasa kyau. \n
        \t Misali mai zuwa yana kafa alƙalloli daban-daban don duk ɓangarorin huɗu na <p> kashi: \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p {
          \t margin-top: 100px;
         \t margin-bottom: 100px;
         \t margin-right: 150px;
         \t margin-left: 80px;
        \t } \n\n

        Karkatarwa - Kasuwancin Gida\n
        Don gajarta lambar, yana yiwuwa a tantance duk kayan gado a cikin gida ɗaya.\n
        Ginimar gefe-riɓi ce ta ɗan gajeren lokaci don waɗannan keɓaɓɓun gefe - \n
        • \t gefe-saman \n
        • \t gefe-dama \n
        • \t gefe-kasa \n
        • \t gefe-hagu \n\n
        \t Don haka, ga yadda yake aiki: \n
        \t Idan dukiyar gefe tana da dabi\'u huɗu: \n
        • \t gefe: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t saman gado shine 25px \n
        \t alamar madaidaiciya 50px\n
        \t kasan gado shine 75px \n
        \t gefen hagu shine 100px \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t } \n
        \n
        \t Idan dukiyar gefe tana da dabi\'u uku: \n
        • \t gefe: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t saman gado shine 25px \n
        \t dama da hagu alan 50px \n
        \t kasan gado shine 75px \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Idan dukiyar gefe tana da dabi\'u biyu: \n
        • \t gefe: 25px 50px; \n
        \t saman da ƙananan alamomi 25px \n
        \t dama da hagu alan 50px \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Idan dukiyar gefe tana da darajar guda ɗaya: \n

        • \t margin: 25px; \n
        \t duk alamomin hudun 25px \n
        \ t Misalin \ n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        CSS Padding - daidaikun mutane \n
        \ t CSS yana da kaddarorin don tantance madaidaicin sashin kowane bangare: \n
        \t padding-top\n
        \t padding-right\n
        \t padding-bottom\n
        \t padding-left\n\n

        \t Dukkanin kayan kwalliyar na iya samun waɗannan ƙimar: \n
        • \t tsayin - ƙayyade padding a px, pt, cm, da dai sauransu \n
        Inherit gado - ya nuna cewa gado ya kamata a gajiyar daga abin da mahaifa \n
        \t Bayani: Ba a yarda da ƙimar gari ba. \n
        \t Misali mai zuwa yana saita padding daban-daban ga dukkan bangarorin <div>: \n\n
        \t Misalin \ n
        \t div {\n
         \t padding-top: 50px; \n
         \t padding-right: 30px; \n
         \t padding-bottom: 50px; \n
          \t padding-left: 80px; \n
        \t } \n

        Padding - Shorthand Property \ n
        \t Don gajarta lambar, yana yiwuwa a tantance dukkan abubuwan mallakar kayan guda ɗaya. \n
        \t propertyarar abar ƙanƙantar da ita abu ce ta ɗan gajeren abu don abubuwan ɗorafan abubuwan da ke gaba \n
        \t padding-top\n
        \t padding-right\n
        \t padding-bottom\n
        \t padding-left\n\n

        \t Don haka, ga yadda yake aiki: \n
        \t Idan kayan kwalliyar suna da dabi\'u huɗu: \n
        • \t padding: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t saman padding shine 25px \n
        \t madaidaiciyar madaidaiciya 50px \n
        \t kasan padding din shine 75px \n
        \t bar madaidaicin hagu 100px \n\n
        \t Misalin \ n
        \t div {\n
        \t  padding: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Idan kayan kadar yana da dabi\'u uku: \n
        • \t padding: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t saman padding shine 25px \n
        \t dama da hagunan hagu 50px \n
        \t kasan padding din shine 75px \n\n
        \t Misalin \ n
        \t div {\n
        \t  padding: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t }\n\n

        \t Idan kayan kadar yana da dabi\'u biyu: \n
        • \t padding: 25px 50px; \n
        \t madaidaicin saman da ƙananan 25px \n
        \t dama da hagunan hagu 50px \n
        \t Idan kayan kadar yana da ƙima ɗaya: \n
        • \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t duk abubuwan hudun guda huɗu 25px \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p {\n
         \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t}
        \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_css_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\tRubutun CSS \n\n
        Launin Rubutu \n
        \t Ana amfani da kayan launi don saita launi na rubutu. An bayyana launi ta: \n
        • \t sunan launi - kamar \"ja\" \n
        \t Tsarin rubutu na tsohuwa don shafi an bayyana shi cikin zaɓin jiki. \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t jiki {\n
        \t launi: shuɗi; \n
        \t} \n

        \t h1 {\n
         \t launi: kore; \n
        \t} \n\n

        Rubutun rubutu \n
        \t Ana amfani da kayan-daidaita rubutu don saita kwance a rubutu na rubutu. \n
        \t Rubutun zai iya barin hagu ko dama, daidaita, ko daidaituwa. \n
        \t Misali masu zuwa suna nuna tsararren rubutu a tsakiya, da hagu da dama na rubutu masu rubutu (hagu \n
        \t karkatarwa tsoho ne idan allon rubutu ya kasance hagu-dama, kuma jeri na dama tsoho ne idan
        rubutu \n\n
        Misali \n
        shugabanci hannun dama ne zuwa hagu):\n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
        \t  text-align: left; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Rubutun Kaya \n
        \t Ana amfani da kayan adon rubutu don saitawa ko cire kayan ado daga rubutu. \n
        \t Darajar rubutu-ƙyalli: babu; galibi ana amfani da shi don cire layin tattaunawa daga hanyoyin: \n\n
        Misali \n

        \t a {\n
        \t  text-decoration: none; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Sauran hanyoyin rubutu na adon rubutu ana amfani dasu don yin ado da rubutu: \n\n

        Misali \n

        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-decoration: overline; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
         \t text-decoration: line-through; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Canjin rubutu \n
        \t Ana amfani da abin da za a yi amfani da kayan rubutu wajen tantance manyan haruffa da ƙananan inan rubutu a cikin rubutu. \n
        \t Ana iya amfani da shi don juya komai zuwa babba ko ƙananan baƙaƙe, ko cinye \n
        \t harafin farko na kowace kalma: \n\n

        Misali \n

        \t p.uppercase {\n
         \t text-transform: uppercase; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.lowercase {\n
        \t  text-transform: lowercase; \n
        \t }\n\n

        CSS Fonts \n
        \t Gidan dangi \n
        \t Gidan font na rubutu an saita shi tare da kayan iyali-font. \n
        \t Dukiyar dan-dan-font ya kamata ya riƙe sunaye da yawa na font a matsayin \"faɗuwa\" tsarin. Idan \n
        \t mai bincike baya goyan bayan font na farko, yana ƙoƙari font na gaba, da sauransu. \n
        \t Fara daga font da kake so, kuma ƙare tare da dangi na kowa, don barin mai binciken ya zaɓi \n
        Kundin font iri daya a cikin dangi, idan babu sauran rubutun. \n
        \t Bayani: Idan sunan ɗan font ya fi kalma ɗaya, dole ne ya kasance cikin alamun faɗar, \n\n
        son kamar: \"Times New Roman\". \n
        \t Fiye da gidan font an tantance a cikin jerin wakafi-rabu: \n\n

        Misali \n

        \t p {\n
         \t font-family: \"Times New Roman\", Times, serif; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Salon Harafi \n
        \t Ana amfani da dukiyar da ake amfani da rubutu don nuna rubutu ko rubutun rubutu. \n
        \t Wannan dukiya tana da dabi\'u uku: \n
        • \t al\'ada - Ana nuna rubutun a al\'ada \n
        • \t Italic - Rubutun yana nuna a cikin rubutun. \n
        • \t oblique - Rubutun yana \"jingina\" (duk da haka oblique yana da kama da ta hanyar rubutun ta, amma ƙasa da n \ goyan baya) \n\n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t p.normal {\n
          font-style: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.italic {\n
          font-style: italic; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.oblique {\n
          font-style: oblique; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Girman Font Tare da Pixels \n
        \t Saitin rubutun rubutu da pixels yana baka cikakken iko akan girman rubutun: \n\n
        Misali \n
        \t h1 {\n
          \t font-size: 40px; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
          \t font-size: 30px; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Nauyi Font  \n
        \t Dukiyar-font-nauyi ta bayyana nauyin font: \n\n
        Misali \n
        \t p.normal {\n
         \t font-weight: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.thick {\n
         \t font-weight: bold; \n
        \t} \n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- end of Hausa CSS Contents -->

    <!-- Yoruba CSS Contents -->
    <string name="yo_css_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
         \t\t\tIfihan CSS\n\n
        Kini CSS?\n
        •\t CSS duro fun Awọn awoṣe ara Cascading\n
        •\t CSS ṣapejuwe bi o ṣe le ṣe afihan awọn eroja HTML loju iboju, iwe, tabi ni awọn media miiran\n
        •\t CSS ṣe ipamọ iṣẹ pupọ. O le ṣakoso ifilelẹ ti awọn oju opo wẹẹbu ọpọ ni ẹẹkan\n
        •\t Awọn aṣọ ita ti wa ni fipamọ ni awọn faili CSS\n\n
        Kini idi ti o lo CSS?\n
        A lo CSS lati ṣalaye awọn aza fun awọn oju opo wẹẹbu rẹ, pẹlu apẹrẹ, akọkọ ati awọn iyatọ ninu ifihan fun awọn ẹrọ oriṣiriṣi ati titobi iboju.\n
        \n
        CSS yanju Iṣoro Nla kan\n
        HTML ko MII pinnu lati ni awọn aami fun ọna kika oju-iwe wẹẹbu kan!\n
        A ṣẹda HTML lati ṣe apejuwe akoonu ti oju-iwe wẹẹbu kan, bii:\n
        <H1> Eyi ni akọle </H1>\n
        <p> Eyi ni ìpínrọ kan. </p>\n
        Nigbati awọn afi bii <font>, ati awọn eroja ti awọ ni a ṣafikun si HTML 3.2 sipesifikesonu, o bẹrẹ alaburuku fun awọn olulo wẹẹbu. Idagbasoke ti awọn oju opo wẹẹbu nla, nibiti a ti fi awọn akọwe ati alaye awọ si gbogbo oju-iwe kan ṣoṣo, di ilana gigun ati gbowolori.\n
        Lati yanju iṣoro yii, Consortium World Wide Web (W3C) ṣẹda CSS.\n
        CSS kuro ni ọna kika ọna lati oju-iwe HTML!\n
        CSS Ṣàfipamọ Loti ti Iṣẹ!\n
        Awọn asọ-ara ti wa ni fipamọ deede ni awọn faili .css ita.\n
        Pẹlu faili itankale itagbangba, o le yi iwo oju opo wẹẹbu pada nipa yiyipada faili kan!\n

        \n\n
        CSS Syntax ati Selectors
        \n
        Syntax CSS\n
        Ofin CSS kan ti o jẹ ti yiyan ati bulọ ikede:\n
         \n\n
        Awọn olutayan tọka si nkan HTML ti o fẹ lati ara.\n
        Àkọsílẹ ìpolongo ni ọkan tabi diẹ awọn ikede ti o ya sọtọ nipasẹ semicolons.\n
        Ifiwe kọọkan pẹlu orukọ ohun-ini CSS ati iye kan, ti o ya sọtọ nipasẹ oluṣafihan.\n
        Ifiweranṣẹ CSS kan pari pẹlu semikilonni kan, ati pe awọn bulọọki ikede ni o wa yika nipasẹ awọn àmúró iṣupọ.\n
        Ninu apẹẹrẹ atẹle gbogbo awọn eroja <p> yoo jẹ abulẹ ni aarin, pẹlu awọ ọrọ pupa:\n\n

        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        p {\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
        }
        \n\n
        awọn olutapa CSS\n
        awọn olutapa CSS ni a lo lati \“wa\” (tabi yan) awọn eroja HTML ti o da lori orukọ eroja wọn, id, kilasi, isọda, ati diẹ sii.

        \n\n
        Awọn ano Selector\n
        Ẹya aṣeduro yan awọn eroja ti o da lori orukọ ano.\n
        O le yan gbogbo awọn eroja <p> lori oju-iwe bi eleyi (ni idi eyi, gbogbo awọn eroja </p> yoo jẹ isọdi aarin, pẹlu awọ ọrọ pupa kan):\n\n

        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        p {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }
        \n\n
        Awọn id Selector\n
        Oluṣakoso id naa nlo abuda id ti ẹya HTML lati yan ipin kan pato.\n
        Awọn id ti ano yẹ ki o jẹ alailẹgbẹ laarin oju-iwe kan, nitorinaa a ti lo id yiyan ti a yan lati yan ọkan alailẹgbẹ kan!\n
        Lati yan ipin kan pẹlu id kan pato, kọ kikọ silẹ (#) kan, atẹle nipa id ti ano.\n
        Ofin aṣa ti o wa ni isalẹ yoo lo si nkan HTML pẹlu id = \"para1\":\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        # para1 {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }\n\n
        Awọn kilasi Selector\n
        Olumulo kilasi yan awọn eroja pẹlu abuda kilasi pàtó kan.\n
        Lati yan awọn eroja pẹlu kilasi kan pato, kọ akoko kan (.) Kikọ, atẹle nipa orukọ ti kilasi naa.\n
        Ninu apẹẹrẹ ni isalẹ, gbogbo awọn eroja HTML pẹlu kilasi = \"ile-iṣẹ\" yoo jẹ pupa ati ila-aarin
        \n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        .aarin {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }
        \n\n
        O tun le ṣalaye pe awọn eroja HTML pato kan yẹ ki o ni ipa nipasẹ kilasi kan.\n
        Ninu apẹẹrẹ ni isalẹ, awọn eroja <p> nikan pẹlu kilasi = \"aarin\" yoo wa ni isọdọkan aarin:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        p.center {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }
        \n\n
        Awọn eroja HTML tun le tọka si siwaju ju kilasi kan lọ.\n
        Ninu apẹẹrẹ ni isalẹ, ipilẹ </p> yoo jẹ ara ni ibamu si kilasi = \"aarin\" ati si kilasi = \"nla\":\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <p kilasi = \"ile-iṣẹ ti o tobi\"> Apaadi yii tọka si awọn kilasi meji. </p>\n
        \n
        Akiyesi: Orukọ kilasi ko le bẹrẹ pẹlu nọmba kan!\n
        \n\n
        Awọn yiyan Ẹgbẹ\n
        Ti o ba ni awọn eroja pẹlu asọye ara kanna, bi eleyi:\n
        h1 {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }\n

        h2 {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }\n

        p {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }\n\n

        Yoo dara julọ lati ṣajọpọ awọn ti o yan, lati dinku koodu naa.\n
        Si awọn olukọ ẹgbẹ, ya onyan yiyan pẹlu komma kan.\n
        Ninu apẹẹrẹ ti o wa ni isalẹ a ti ṣe akojọ awọn yiyan lati koodu ti o wa loke:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        h1, h2, p {\n
          ọrọ-align: aarin;\n
          awọ: pupa;\n
        }: \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_css_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tAwọn oriṣi ti aṣọ atẹrin\n\n
        Awọn ọna mẹta lati Fi sii CSS\n
        Awọn ọna mẹta ni o wa ti ifi sii dì ara:\n
        • \tIwe ara ti ita\n
        • \tIwe ara inu\n
        • \tara Inline\n
        \n
        Iwe apẹrẹ ita \n
        Pẹlu iwe aṣa ara ita, o le yi oju wiwo oju opo wẹẹbu kan han nipasẹ yiyipada faili kan!\n
        Oju-iwe kọọkan gbọdọ ni itọkasi kan si faili ọna kika ita inu <link> ano. Ẹya <link> naa lọ si apakan <head>:\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <head>\n
        <ọna asopọ rel = \"stylesheet\" oriṣi = \"ọrọ / css\" href = \"mystyle.css\">\n
        </head>\n
        A le kọwe ara ita ni eyikeyi ọrọ olootu. Faili ko yẹ ki o ni awọn afi orukọ HTML. Faili kika ara gbọdọ wa ni fipamọ pẹlu ifaagun .css.\n
        Eyi ni bii oju \“mystyle.css\”:\n
        ara {\n
          awọ-awọ lẹhin: gilasi ina;\n
        }\n

        h1 {\n
          awọ: ọgagun;\n
          ala-apa osi: 20px;\n
        }\n
        Akiyesi: Maṣe ṣafikun aaye kan laarin iye ohun-ini ati ẹyọkan (bii ala-apa osi: 20 px;). Ọna ti o pe ni: ala-apa osi: 20px;\n\n

        Iwe inu ara\n
        A le lo iwe ara ti inu ti o ba lo pe oju-iwe kan ṣoṣo ni ara ọtọtọ.\n
        Awọn ara inu ti wa ni asọye laarin <style> ano, inu apakan <head> ti oju opo HTML kan:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        headhead \n‹
        <style>\n
        ara {\n
          awọ-lẹhin: aṣọ-ọgbọ;\n
        }
        \n
        h1 {\n
          awọ: maroon;\n
          ala-osi: 40px;\n
        }\n
        </style>\n
        </head>
        \n\n
        Awọn ilana Inline\n
        A le lo iru opo ara lati lo ara ọtọtọ fun ipin kan.\n
        Lati lo awọn aza inline, ṣafikun ẹya ara si ẹya ti o wulo. Ẹya ara le ni eyikeyi ohun-ini CSS.\n
        Apẹẹrẹ ni isalẹ fihan bi o ṣe le yi awọ ati ala osi ti ipin <h1> kan:\n\n
        Apẹẹrẹ\n
        <h1 ara = \"awọ: bulu; ala-osi: 30px;\"> Eyi ni akọle </H1> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_css_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
                        \t\t\tAwọn abẹlẹ CSS. \n\n

        \t Awọn ohun-ini ẹhin CSS ni a lo lati ṣalaye awọn ipa lẹhin fun awọn eroja.\n
        \t Awọn ohun-ini ẹhin CSS: \n
        \t background-color\n
         \t background-image\n
         \t background-repeat\n
         \t background-attachment\n
         \t background-position\n\n

        \t Awọ abẹlẹ \n
         \t Ohun-ini lẹhin-awọ ṣe asọtẹlẹ awọ abẹlẹ ti ano. \n
         \t Awọ ipilẹ ti oju-iwe ti ṣeto bi eleyi: \n
         \t Apeere \n
        \t body { \n
         \t background-color: lightblue; \n
         \t } \n\n

        \t Ni CSS, awọ kan ni a saba maa ṣalaye nipasẹ: \n
        \t a valid color name - like \"red\" \n
         \t a HEX value - like \"#ff0000\" \n
         \t an RGB value - like \"rgb(255,0,0)\" \n
        \t Ninu apẹẹrẹ ni isalẹ, awọn <h1>, <p>, ati awọn eroja <div> ni oriṣiriṣi abinibi \ tcolor: \n\n
        \t Apeere \n

        \t h1 { \n
        \t  background-color: green;\n
        \t }\n

        \t div {\n
         \t background-color: lightblue; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p {\n
        \t  background-color: yellow; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Aworan Aworan isẹlẹ \n
        \t Ohun-ini lẹhin-aworan n tọka aworan kan lati lo bi abẹlẹ ti ano. \n
        \t Nipa aiyipada, aworan naa tun jẹ nitorinaa o bo gbogbo nkan. \n
        \t Aworan ti ẹhin fun oju-iwe le ṣee ṣeto bi eyi: \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t body { \n
         \t background-image: url(\"paper.gif\"); \n
        \t }\n\n

        \t Ni isalẹ jẹ apẹẹrẹ ti akojọpọ buburu ti ọrọ ati aworan ẹhin. A ko le ka ọrọ naa fun: \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"bgdesert.jpg\");\n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Akiyesi: Nigbati o ba lo aworan abẹlẹ, lo aworan ti ko ṣe idamu ọrọ. \n

        \t Aworan ni abẹlẹ - Tun Horizontally tabi Ni inaro \n
        \t Nipa aiyipada, ohun-ini lẹhin-aworan tun ṣe aworan mejeeji ni petele ati ni inaro. \n
        \t Diẹ ninu awọn aworan yẹ ki o tun ṣe nikan ni ọna nitosi tabi ni inaro, tabi wọn yoo dabi ajeji,\n
        \t bi eleyi:\n\n
        \t Apere\n
        \t body {
         \t backgrou  	nd-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\");\n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ti a ba tun aworan ti o wa loke nikan ni ọna nitosi (lẹhin-tun-tun: tun-x;), abẹlẹ yoo dara julọ: \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: repeat-x; \n
        \t } \n
        \t: Lati tun aworan ṣe ni inaro, ṣeto lẹhin-tun-ṣe: tun-y; \n\n

        Aworan Ile lẹhin - Ṣeto ipo ko si-tun-\n
        \t Ṣiṣe aworan ẹhin lẹhin lẹẹkanṣoṣo ni o tọka nipasẹ ipilẹ-tun ohun-ini: \n\n
        Apeere\n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \ t Ipo ti aworan wa ni asọye nipasẹ ohun-ini ipo-lẹhin: \n\n

        \t Apeere\n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
         \t background-position: right top; \n
        \t  } \n\n

        Aworan Ile lẹhin - Ipo ti o wa titi \ n
        \t Lati ṣalaye pe aworan ẹhin yẹ ki o wa titi (kii yoo yi lọ pẹlu iyoku \n
        \t oju-iwe naa), lo ohun-ini isẹlẹ lẹhin-tẹle: \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\");  \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t  background-position: right top; \n
        \t  background-attachment: fixed; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Iwọn ààlà \n
        \t Ohun-iní iwọn-aala n ṣalaye iwọn ti awọn aala mẹrin naa. \n
        \t Iwọn naa le ṣeto bi iwọn kan pato (ni px, pt, cm, em, ati bẹbẹ lọ) tabi nipa lilo ọkan ninu awọn iye-iṣaaju asọtẹlẹ mẹta: tinrin, alabọde, tabi nipọn. \n
        \t Ohun-ini ipin-aala le ni lati ọkan si mẹrin awọn iye (fun oke aala, ọtun \n
        \t aala, aala isalẹ, ati aala osi). \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p.one { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: 5px; \n
        }\n

        \t p.two { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: medium; \n
        }\n

        \t p.three {\n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-width: 2px 10px 4px 20px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Awọ Aala \n
        \t Ohun-ini awọ-aala lo lati ṣeto awọ ti awọn aala mẹrin. \n
        \t A le ṣeto awọ naa nipasẹ: \n
        • \t orukọ - pato orukọ awọ kan, fẹran \"pupa\" \n
        • \t Hex - ṣalaye iye hex kan, bi \"#ff0000\" \n
        • \t RGB - ṣeduro iye RGB kan, bii \"rgb (255,0,0)\" \n
        • \t Sihin \n\n
        \t Ohun-ini awọ-aala le ni lati ọkan si mẹrin awọn iye (fun aala oke, ọtun \n
        \t àla, ààlà isalẹ, àti ààlà osi). \n
        \t Ti ko ba ṣeto awọ-aala, o jogun awọ ti ano. \n
        \t Aala pupa \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p.one { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: red; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.two { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: green; \n
        \t } \n

        \t p.three { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-color: red green blue yellow; \n
        \t }  \n\n

        Ààlà - Gbogbo Awọn itọsọna Ẹyọkan \n
        \t Lati awọn apẹẹrẹ loke o ti rii pe o ṣee ṣe lati tokasi iyatọ \n
        \t aala fun ẹgbẹ kọọkan. \n
        \t Ni CSS, awọn ohun-ini tun wa fun sisọ ọkọọkan awọn aala naa (oke, ọtun, \n
        \t isalẹ, ati osi): \n
        \t Awọn ọna ila odi oriṣiriṣi \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p { \n
        \t  border-top-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-right-style: solid; \n
         \t border-bottom-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-left-style: solid; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Apẹẹrẹ loke n fun abajade kanna bi eleyi: \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p { \n
         \t border-style: dotted solid; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Nitorinaa, eyi ni bi o ṣe n ṣiṣẹ: \n
        \t Ti ohun-ini aala-ilẹ ba ni awọn iye mẹrin: \n
        \t -aala-ara: ti fẹ danu ilopo meji; \n
        \t aala oke ni a ti sami \n
        \t aala otun ni ainidodo \n
        \t isalẹ aala jẹ ilọpo meji \n
        \t  osi ipin osi ti bajẹ \n
        \t Ti ohun-ini-aala-ilẹ ni awọn iye mẹta: \n
        \t -aala-ara: ti ilọpo meji ti o muna; \n
        \t t aala oke ni a ti sami \n
        \t t ọtun ati apa osi aala jẹ ri to \n
        \t t isalẹ aala jẹ ilọpo meji \n
        \t Ti ohun-ini aṣa-aala ba ni awọn idiyele meji: \n
        \t t-aala-ara: aito aami ti o muna; \n
        \t oke ati isalẹ awọn aala ti wa ni ti sami \n
        \t ọtun ati apa osi aala jẹ ri to \n
        \t Ti ohun-ini ara-aala naa ni iye kan: \n
        \t ara-aala: ti aami; \n
         gbogbo awọn aala mẹrin ni a dọka \n
        \t Awọn ohun-ini-aala a lo ni apẹẹrẹ loke. Sibẹsibẹ, o tun ṣiṣẹ pẹlu \n
        \t ààlà-iwọn ati awọ-aala. \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_css_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tAla CSS - Olumulo Kọọkan Sirin \n
        \t CSS ni awọn ohun-ini fun sisọ ala fun ẹgbẹ kọọkan ti ano: \n
        \tmargin-top\n
        \tmargin-right\n
        \tmargin-bottom\n
        \tmargin-left\n\n

        \t Gbogbo awọn ohun-ini ala le ni awọn iye wọnyi: \n
        \tauto - the browser calculates the margin\n
        \tlength - specifies a margin in px, pt, cm, etc.\n
        \tinherit - specifies that the margin should be inherited from the parent element\n\n

        \t Tip: Awọn iye odi jẹ gba laaye. \n
        \ t Apẹẹrẹ atẹle n ṣeto awọn ala oriṣiriṣi si gbogbo awọn ẹgbẹ mẹrin ti ipilẹ <p> kan: \n\n
        \ t Apeere \ n
        \t p {\n
          \t margin-top: 100px;\n
         \t margin-bottom: 100px;\n
         \t margin-right: 150px;\n
         \t margin-left: 80px;\n
        \t } \n\n

        Ala - Ohun-ini Shorthand \n
        Lati kuru koodu, o ṣee ṣe lati tokasi gbogbo awọn ohun-ala ni ohun-ini kan.\n
        Ohun-ini ala jẹ ohun-ini kukuru fun atẹle awọn ohun-ini ala-kọọkan ti n tẹle: \n
        \t margin-top\n
        \t margin-right\n
        \t margin-bottom\n
        \t margin-left\n\n
        \t Nitorinaa, eyi ni bi o ṣe n ṣiṣẹ: \n
        \t Ti ohun-ini ala\b
         ba ni awọn iye mẹrin: \n
         \t ala: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t oke ni 25px \n
         \t ala ọtun jẹ 50px\n
        \t ala isalẹ jẹ 75px \n
         \t osi ipin jẹ 100px \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ti ohun-ini ala ba ni awọn iye mẹta: \n
        • \t ala: 25px 50px 75px; \n
         \t oke ni 25px \n
         \t ọtun ati apa osi jẹ 50px \n
        \t ala isalẹ jẹ 75px \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ti ohun-ini ala ni awọn iye meji: \n
        • \t ala: 25px 50px; \n
         \t oke ati isalẹ awọn ala jẹ 25px \n
        \t ọtun ati apa osi jẹ 50px \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ti ohun-ini ala ba ni iye kan: \n

        • \t ala: 25px; \n
        \t gbogbo awọn igun mẹrin ni 25px \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px; \n
        \t } \n
        \n
        Ohun elo CSS - Awọn igbidanwo Kọọkan \n
        \t CSS ni awọn ohun-ini fun sisọ padi fun ẹgbẹ kọọkan ti ano: \n
        \t padding-top\n
        \t padding-right\n
        \t padding-bottom\n
        \t padding-left\n\n

        \t Gbogbo awọn ohun-elo fifọ le ni awọn iye wọnyi: \n
        \t length - specifies a padding in px, pt, cm, etc. \n
        \t inherit - specifies that the padding should be inherited from the parent element\n\n

        \t Akiyesi: A ko gba laaye awọn odi . \n
        \t Apẹẹrẹ to tẹle ṣeto padding oriṣiriṣi fun gbogbo awọn ẹgbẹ mẹrin ti ipilẹ <div>: \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t div {\n
         \t padding-top: 50px; \n
         \t padding-right: 30px; \n
         \t padding-bottom: 50px; \n
          \t padding-left: 80px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Sisọ - Ohun-ini kukuru. \n
        \t Lati ṣoki koodu, o ṣee ṣe lati tokasi gbogbo awọn ohun-elo fifọ ni ohun-ini kan. \n
        \t Ohun-elo fifọ jẹ ohun-ini kukuru fun ohun elo mimu kọọkan ti n tẹle \n\n
         \t Awọn ohun-ini: \n
        \t Nitorinaa, eyi ni bi o ṣe n ṣiṣẹ: \n
        \t Ti ohun-elo fifọ naa ni awọn idiyele mẹrin: \n
        • \t padding: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t padding oke ni 25px \n
        \t padding ọtun jẹ 50px \n
        \t isalẹ fifẹ jẹ 75px \n
        \t padding osi jẹ 100px \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t div {\n
        \t ẹmu: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n\n

        \t Ti ohun-elo fifọ naa ni awọn idiyele mẹta: \n
        • \t padding: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t padding oke ni 25px \n
        \t sọtun ati sosi apoti wa ni 50px \n
        \t isalẹ fifẹ jẹ 75px \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t div {\n
        \t ẹmu: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t}\n\n

        \t Ti ohun-elo fifọ ni awọn iye meji: \n
        • \t padding: 25px 50px; \n
        \t oke ati isalẹ awọn paddings jẹ 25px \n
        \t sọtun ati sosi apoti wa ni 50px \n
        \t Ti ohun-elo fifọ naa ni iye kan: \n
        • \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t gbogbo awọn fifẹ mẹrin jẹ 25px \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t}\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_css_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\tText CSS\n\n
        Awọ ọrọ \n
        \t A lo ohun-ini awọ lati ṣeto awọ ti ọrọ. A sọ asọtẹlẹ naa nipasẹ: \n
        • \t orukọ awọ kan - bi \"pupa\" \n
        \t Ayipada ọrọ awọ fun oju-iwe kan ni asọye ninu yiyan ara. \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t body {\n
        \t  color: blue; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h1 {\n
         \t color: green; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ifọwọsi Text \n
        \t Ohun-elo aligning ọrọ naa ti lo lati ṣeto tito petele ti ọrọ kan. \n
        \t A le fi ọrọ silẹ tabi apa otun, ti dojukọ, tabi lare. \n
        \t Apẹẹrẹ atẹle n ṣe afihan titọ aarin, ati osi ati apa ọtun ọrọ ti a ge ni ọwọ (osi \n
        & t
        ọrọ \n
        itọsọna jẹ ọtun-si-osi): \n\n
        Apeere \n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
        \t  text-align: left; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Ohun ọṣọ Text \n
        \t Ohun-ọṣọ ọrọ ti lo lati ṣeto tabi yọ awọn ohun-ọṣọ kuro ninu ọrọ. \n
        \t Ohun ọṣọ ọrọ-ọṣọ: ko si; ni a maa n lo nigbagbogbo lati yọ awọn atokọ kuro lati awọn ọna asopọ: \n\n
        Apeere \n
        \t a {\n
        \t  text-decoration: none; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Awọn iye-ọṣọ ọrọ miiran ni a lo lati ṣe ọṣọ ọrọ: \n\n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-decoration: overline; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
         \t text-decoration: line-through; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Iyipada Ọrọ \n
        \t Ohun-ini ọrọ-yipada ti lo lati ṣe afihan awọn lẹta nla ati kekere ni ọrọ kan. \n
        \t O le ṣee lo lati tan ohun gbogbo sinu apoti kekere tabi awọn lẹta kekere, tabi kawewe awọn \n
        \t lẹta akọkọ ti ọrọ kọọkan: \n\n
        Apeere \n

        \t p.uppercase {\n
         \t text-transform: uppercase; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.lowercase {\n
        \t  text-transform: lowercase; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Awọn fọnti CSS \n

        \t Font idile \n
        \t Awọn idile fonti ti ọrọ ti ṣeto pẹlu ohun-ini idile. \n
        \t Ohun-ini fonti-idile yẹ ki o mu ọpọlọpọ awọn orukọ font han bi eto \“isubu\” eto. Ti o ba ti \n
        \t aṣawakiri ko ṣe atilẹyin fonti akọkọ, o n gbiyanju fonti atẹle, ati bẹbẹ lọ. \n
        \t Bẹrẹ pẹlu akọ-ọrọ ti o fẹ, ati pari pẹlu idile jeneriki, lati jẹ ki aṣawakiri mu ohun \n
        \t font ti o jọra ninu idile jeneriki, ti ko ba awọn akọwe miiran wa. \n
        \t Akiyesi: Ti orukọ idile ẹbi ba ju ọrọ kan lọ, o gbọdọ wa ni awọn ami ọrọ asọye, \n
        \t fẹran: \"Times New Roman\". \n
        \t Diẹ ẹ sii ju idile font kan ni pato ninu atokọ ti o pin ipin-sọtọ: \n\n
        Apeere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t font-family: \"Times New Roman\", Times, serif; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Font Style \n
        \t Ohun-ini font-ara ni a lo igbagbogbo lati ṣe apejuwe ọrọ italiki. \n
        \t Ohun-ini yii ni awọn idiyele mẹta: \n
        \t normal - The text is shown normally\n
         \t italic - The text is shown in italics\n
        \t oblique - The text is \"leaning\" (oblique is very similar to italic, but less \n supported) \n\n

        \t Apeere \n
        \t p.normal {\n
          font-style: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.italic {\n
          font-style: italic; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.oblique {\n
          font-style: oblique; \n
        \t } \n\n


        Iwọn Font Pẹlu Awọn piksẹli \n
        \t Ṣiṣeto iwọn ọrọ pẹlu awọn piksẹli yoo fun ọ ni iṣakoso ni kikun lori iwọn ọrọ: \n\n
        Apeere \n
        \t h1 {\n
         \t font-size: 40px; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
          \t font-size: 30px; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Iwuwo Font \n
        \t Ohun-ini fonti-n ṣalaye iwuwo ti fonti: \n\n
        Apeere \n
        \t p.normal {\n
         \t font-weight: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.thick {\n
         \t font-weight: bold; \n
        \t} \n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- end of Yoruba CSS Contents -->

    <!-- Igbo CSS Contents -->
    <string name="ib_css_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tOkwu Ntinye CSS \n\n
        \t Gịnị bụ CSS? \n
        • \t CSS guzo maka Cascading Style Sheets \n
        • \t CSS kowara etu aga - esi gosiputa ihe HTML na enyo, akwukwo, ma obu n\’ime mgbasa ozi ndi ozo\n
        • \t CSS na-azọpụta ọtụtụ ọrụ. Ọ nwere ike ijikwa okirikiri nke ibe weebụ n\'otu oge \n
        • \t Echekwara akwa mpụga na faili CSS\n\n
        \t Gini kpatara iji CSS? \n
        A na-eji CSS kọwaa ụdị maka ibe weebụ gị, gụnyere imewe, okirikiri na ọdịiche dị na ngosipụta maka ngwaọrụ dị iche na nha ihuenyo. \n\n

        CSS doziri nnukwu nsogbu \n
        Achọghị HTML dị ka ihe nwere mkpado maka ị mepụta ibe weebụ. \n
        Emepụtara HTML iji kọwaa ihe dị na ibe weebụ, dị ka: \n
        \t <h1>This is a heading</h1>\n
        \t <p>This is a paragraph.</p>\n\n

        \t Mgbe mkpado dịka <font>, ma tinye njiri mara agba na nkọwapụta HTML 3.2, ọ malitere nro maka ndị mmepe web. Mmepe nke weebụsaịtị weebụ buru ibu, ebe agbakwunyere mkpụrụ akwụkwọ na ozi agba na ibe ọ bụla, ghọrọ usoro dị ogologo ma dị ọnụ. \n
        \t Iji dozie nsogbu a, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) mepụtara CSS. \n
        \t CSS wepụrụ usoro nhazi ụdị na ibe HTML! \n
        \t CSS azọputara Lọt Ọrụ \n
        \t A na-echekwa nkọwa n\'ụzọ dabara adaba na faịlụ .css. \n
        \t Site na faịlị uwe mpụga, ị nwere ike ịgbanwe ọdịdị nke weebụsaịtị du site n\'ịgbanwe naanị otu faịlụ! \n\n

        Nhazi CSS na ndi nhota \n

        \t CSS Syntax \n
        Ihe t-CSS setịpụrụ mebere onye na-ahọpụtara ihe na nkwupụta nkwupute: \n\n

        \t Onye ahọpụtara na-arụtụ aka na HTML HTML ịchọrọ ịke. \n
        \t Nkwupụta nkwupute ahụ nwere otu nkwupụta amamịghe nke mkpụrụedemede kewapụrụ. \n
        Nkwupụta nke ọ bụla gụnyere aha ihe onwunwe CSS na ọnụ ahịa ya, ndị colon na-ekewa. \n
        \t Nkwupụta CSS na-ejikarị eme mkpọtụ emechi mgbe nile, ihe nkwado na-agbagọkwa gburugburu. \n
        N\'ịma atụ na - esote, ihe niile <p> ga - adị n\'etiti, na iji ederede uhie: \n\n

        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t p {\n
         \t color: red; \n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ndị na-ahọrọ CSS \n
        A na-eji ndị na-ahọrọ CSS ka ha \'chọta\' (ma ọ bụ họrọ) HTML ihe sitere na aha mmewere, id, klas, njirimara na ndị ọzọ. \n\n

        Ihe ntinye ihe nlere \n
        \'The element selector ahọrọ ihe dabere na mmewere aha. \n
        \t can nwere ike ịhọrọ ihe niile <p> na ibe dị ka nke a (na nke a, ihe niile <p> ga-ahaziri, yana otu ederede uhie): \n\n

        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t p {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t id Selector \n
        \n idọpụtara id na-eji njirimara id nke HTML maka ịhọrọ otu akọwapụtara. \n
        \t The id nke mmewere kwesịrị ịbụ pụrụ iche n’ime ibe, yabụ ejiri onye na-ahọrọ id iji họrọ otu ihe pụrụ iche! \n
        \t Ka ịhọrọ mmewere nwere otu ụdị ederede, dee agwa hash (#), na-esochi ụdị mmewere. \n
        \t A ga-etinye ụkpụrụ ụdị dị n\'okpuru ebe a na HTML maka id = \"para1\": \n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t #para1 {\n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Onye klas Selector \n
        \'Klaasị na - ahọpụtara ihe klas nwere njiri mara otu \n
        \t Ka ịhọrọ ndị nwere klas a kapịrị ọnụ, dee akara (.) agwa, aha klaasị sochiri ya. \n
        \t N\'ihe atụ dị n\'okpuru ebe a, ihe HTML niile nwere klaasị = \"etiti\" ga-acha ọbara ma hazie: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t.center {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n
        \t cannwekwara ike ịkọwapụta na ọ bụ naanị klas ga-emetụta HTML ụfọdụ. \n
        \t Ihe atụ dị n\'okpuru, naanị <p> ihe nwere klaasị = \"etiti\" ga - arụ ọrụ etiti: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \ n
        \t p.center {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t HTML ihe nwekwara ike zoo aka na otu klaasị. \n
        \ t N\'ihe atụ dị n\'okpuru ebe a, ihe <p> ga-ahazi dịka klas = \"etiti\" yana klaasị = \"buru ibu\": \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t <p class=\"center large\">paragraf a na-ezo aka na klaasị abụọ. </p> \n

        \t Mara: Aha klaasị enweghị ike imalite na ọnụọgụ! \n\n

        \t Ndị Nhọrọ Ndị Nhọrọ\n
        \t O buru na inwere ihe dikwa otu ha di, otu a: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n

        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        }\n

        \t p {\n
         \t text-align: center; \n
        \t  color: red; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ọ ga-aka mma ịkpọkọta ndị ahọpụtara, iji belata koodu. \n
        Banye otu na-ahọpụta ndị na-ahọrọ ha, kewapụ onye ọ bụla na-ahọpụta ya na komama. \n
        N\'ịma atụ dị n\'okpuru, anyị chịkọtara ndị ahọpụtara site na koodu nke dị n\'elu: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t h1, h2, p {\n
         \t text-align: center;\n
          \t color: red;\n
        \t } \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_css_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tOFdị ụdị ụlọ nbipụta \n\n
        tzọ tozọ Atinye CSS \n
        \tEnwere ụzọ atọ eji etinye akwụkwọ mpempe akwụkwọ: \n
        • \tMpempe akwụkwọ mpụga \n
        • \tMpempị ụdị nke ime \n
        • \tụdị inline \n\n

        Mpempe Styledị Mpụga \n
        \tIji mpempe akwụkwọ mpụga, ị nwere ike ịgbanwe ọdịdị nke weebụsaịtị zuru oke site na \n
        \tna-agbanwe naanị otu faịlụ! \n
        \tibe obula aghaghi itinye ntinye aka na mpempe uzo ozo nke di n\’ime <link> \n \telement. Akụ <link> na-abanye n’ime ngalaba <head>: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n

        <head>\n
        <link rel=\"stylesheet\" type=\"text/css\" href=\"mystyle.css\">
        </head> \n\n

        \tEnwere ike ide mpempe akwụkwọ mpụga na ndezi ederede ọ bụla. Faịlị ekwesịghị inwe mkpado any HTML. A ga-echekwa faịlị mpempe akwụkwọ na ndọtị .css. \n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \tbody {\n
        \t  background-color: lightblue; \n
        \t}\n

        \th1 {\n
         \t color: navy; \n
         \t margin-left: 20px; \n
        \t} \n\n

        \tMara: Etinyekwa oghere n’etiti ihe onwunwe na otu ya (dịka oke aka ekpe : 20 px;). Correctzọ ziri ezi bụ: oke-ekpe: 20px; \n\n

        Mpempe Styledị N\'ime Ahụ \n
        \tEnwere ike iji mpempe akwụkwọ odide ime ma ọ bụrụ na otu peeji nwere ụdị pụrụ iche. \n
        A na-akọwa ụdị n\'ime n\'ime <style> element, n\'ime ngalaba <head> nke ibe \tHTML: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t<head>\n
        \t<style>\n
        \tbody {\n
         \tbackground-color: linen; \n
        \t}\n

        \th1 {\n
        \t  color: maroon; \n
         \t margin-left: 40px; \n
        \t} \n
        \t</style>\n
        \t</head> \n\n

        Ndepụta dị n\'ime \n
        Enwere ike iji ụdị inline tinye ụdị pụrụ iche maka otu mmewere. \n
        \tIji jiri udiri inline mee ihe, gbakwunye njiri mara nke dabara adaba. \Dị \n \ tattribute nwere ike ịnwe ihe onwunwe CSS. \n
        \tIhe atụ dị n\'okpuru ebe a na-egosi otu esi agbanwe agba na akara aka ekpe nke <h1> \n \ telement: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t <h1 style=\"color:blue;margin-left:30px;\">This is a heading</h1> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_css_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
          \t\t\tNtinye ihe omuma CSS \n\n

        A na-eji ihe ndabere nke CSS kọwaa nsonaazụ nzụlite maka ihe\n
        Ngwongwo ihe ndabere nke CSS: \n
        \t background-color\n
         \t background-image\n
         \t background-repeat\n
         \t background-attachment\n
         \t background-position\n\n

        \t Agba na agba \n
         Ngwongwo agba na-egosiputa mmezi agba di n\’ime ya. \n
         \t Agbaziiri ya otu ihu peeji ka edoziri: \n
          \t nlere \n
        \t body { \n
         \t background-color: lightblue; \n
         \t } \n\n

        N\'etiti CSS, agba na-abụkarị nke: \n
        • \t aha ezigbo agba di - ka \"acha uhie uhie\" \n
        • \t a HEX uru - dị ka \"# ff0000\" \n
        • \t uru RGB - dị ka \"rgb (255,0,0)\" \n
        \t N\'ihe atụ dị n\'okpuru ebe a, ihe <h1>, <p>, na <div> nwere ụdị nzụlite dị iche: \n
        \t nlere \n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  background-color: green;\n
        \t }\n

        \t div {\n
         \t background-color: lightblue;\n
        \t }\n

        \t p {\n
        \t  background-color: yellow;\n
        \t }\n\n

        \t Mkpo nkata \n
        Ngwongwo ihe ndabere na-egosiputa onyoonye iji dika ndabere nke ihe. \n
        \t Site na ndabara, a na-emeghachi onyonyo ya mere o ji kpuchie ihe niile. \n
        \t Enwere ike idozi ihe ndabere dị na peeji a dịka nke a: \n
        \t nlere \n
        \t body { \n
         \t background-image: url(\"paper.gif\"); \n
        \t } \n\n

        N\'okpuru ebe a bụ ịmaatụ nke njikọ jikọtara ederede na onyonyo ndabere. O sighị ike ọgụgụ ederede: \n
        \t  nlere \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"bgdesert.jpg\");\n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Mara: Mgbe ị na-eji ezigbo ihe osise dị n\’azụ, jiri ihe onyonyo anaghị enye nsogbu ederede. \n\n

        \t Background Image - Megharịa ya n\’usoro ma ọ bụ n\’agha\n
        Site na ndabara, akụ ihe ndabere na-akụ n\'okirikiri ma na-emegharị ihe eserese.\n
        A ga-ekwugharị ụfọdụ onyonyo naanị na larịị ma ọ bụ na a kwụ ọtọ, ma ọ bụ na ha ga-adị ka ihe ijuanya,\n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\");\n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ọ bụrụ n \’imegharị onyonyo dị n\’elu na –ekwu n\’usoro (ndabere - megharịa: ugboro-x;), ndabere ga-adị ya mma: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"gradient_bg.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: repeat-x; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t t t: To tughachi onyonyo n\’usoro, dozie okirikiri: ikwugharị-y; \n\n

        Ihe osise n\’azu - Ndoro onodu ma ghara imeghari \n
        A na-egosikwa igosipụta ihe ngosi dị n\’azụ otu ugboro site na nzụlite-imeghachi n ụlọ: n n\n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya \n
        Example\n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ekwuru ọnọdụ onyonyo a site na okirikiri ọnọdụ dị n\'azụ: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya\n
        \t body {\n
         \t background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\"); \n
         \t background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
         \t background-position: right top; \n
        \t  } \n\n

        Ihe osise n\'azu - Onodu adiwara \n
        \t Iji ezipụta na ekwesịrị idobe ihe ndabere dị na ya (agaghị agagharị na ndị ọzọ \n
        \t peeji ahụ), jiri akụ na - eme ihe ndabere: \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya\n
        \t body {\n
        \t  background-image: url(\"img_tree.png\");  \n
        \t  background-repeat: no-repeat; \n
        \t  background-position: right top; \n
        \t  background-attachment: fixed; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ókè Ókèré \n
        \t Akụkụ ala-obosara na-akọwapụta obosara nke ókèala anọ ahụ. \n
        Enwere ike ịtọ obosara ahụ ka ọ bụrụ otu akọwapụtara (na px, pt, cm, em, wdg) ma ọ bụ site na iji otu n \ ụkpụrụ atọ akọwapụtara: ọ dị larịị, nke etiti ma ọ bụ nke buru ibu. \n
        Ihe ala-obosara nwere ike ịnwe site n\’otu ruo anọ (maka oke elu, oke nri, oke ala, na oke ekpe). \n\n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya\n
        \t p.one { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: 5px; \n
        }\n

        \t p.two { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-width: medium; \n
        }\n

        \t p.three {\n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-width: 2px 10px 4px 20px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Agba ụcha \n
        A na-eji ihe ndị nwere agba ókèala iji dozie agba nke ókèala anọ ahụ. \n
        \t Enwere ike idozi agba a: \n

        • \t aha - dee aha agba dị ka \"acha ọbara ọbara\" \n
        • \t Hex - ezipụta ọnụego hex, dị ka \"# ff0000\" \n
        • \t RGB - ezipụta ọnụego RGB, dịka \"rgb (255,0,0)\" \n
        • \t Ntughari \n\n

        \t Akụkụ ókè-ala nwere ike ịnwe site n\'otu ruo anọ (maka oke ala, aka nri \n

        ókè-ala, ala a ala, na ókè-ala aka ekpe). \n

        Ọ bụrụ na edobeghị agba ala, ọ na-eketa ụcha agba. \n
        \t Oke ala \n\n

         \t Ihe Nlereanya\n
        \t p.one { \n
         \t border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: red; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.two { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
         \t border-color: green; \n
        \t } \n

        \t p.three { \n
        \t  border-style: solid; \n
        \t  border-color: red green blue yellow; \n
        \t }  \n\n

        Nnukwu - Otu Niile \n
        \t Site na ihe atụ dị n\’elu ahụ, ị ​​hụla na ọ ga-ekwe omume ịkọwapụta ihe dị iche n
        adala n\'akụkụ ọ bụla. \n\n

        \t Na CSS, odi ala nwekwara akowara nkenke uzo (nke di elu, aka nri, \n
        \t ala, na aka ekpe): \n
        \t Bzọ Bzọ Differentzọ Ọdịiche \n\n

        Ihe nlere \n

        \t p { \n
        \t  border-top-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-right-style: solid; \n
         \t border-bottom-style: dotted; \n
         \t border-left-style: solid; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ihe nlere \n

        \t p { \n
         \t border-style: dotted solid; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ya mere, lee otu o si aru oru: \n
        Ọ bụrụ na ókèala a na-ahụ maka ịkpa oke nwere ụkpụrụ anọ: \n\n

        \t Ya mere, lee otu o si aru oru: \n
        \t bụrụ na ókèala a na-ahụ maka ịkpa oke nwere ụkpụrụ anọ: \n
         \t ókè-ala: dotted siri ike okpukpu abụọ; \n
         \t oke ala na-dotted \n
        \t Oke ala siri ike \n
         \t ala di abuo \n
        \t kwụsịrị ókè ala ekpe \n
        \t  bụrụ na ihe eji achọ ime ókèala nwere ụkpụrụ atọ: \n
        \t ókè-ala: dotted siri ike okpukpu abụọ; \n
         \t oke ala na-dotted \n
        \t Ókèala aka nri na aka ekpe siri ike \n
         \t ala di abuo \n
        \t  bụrụ na ókèala a na-ahụ maka ịkpa oke nwere oke abụọ: \n
        \t ókè-ala: dotted solid; \n
         \t elu na ala na-dotted \n
        \t Ókèala aka nri na aka ekpe siri ike \n
         \t bụrụ na ihe eji achọ ime ókèala nwere otu uru: \n
        \t ụdị nke ókè-ala: dotted; \n
        \t niile akara anọ na-dotted \n
         \t A na-eji ihe eji eme ókèala na ihe atụ dị n\’elu. Agbanyeghị, ọ na - arụ ọrụ na \n
        \t akuku-obosara na akuku-agba. \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_css_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tMkpoko CSS - Ndi Isi Onwe Ya \n\n
        \tCSS nwere ngwongwo maka ịkọwa oke ala n\'akụkụ ọ bụla nke mmewere: \n
        \tmargin-top\n
        \tmargin-right\n
        \tmargin-bottom\n
        \tmargin-left\n\n

        Ngwongwo oke nwere ike inwe ihe ndia: \n
        • \tauto - ihe nchọgharị ahụ na-agbakọ oke ala \n
        • \tlength - na-akọwapụta oke na px, pt, cm, wdg.
        • \tinherit - na - ezipụta na aghọrọ ihe nketa site na ihe nne na nna
        \tTip: A na-ahapụ ụkpụrụ na-adịghị mma. \n
        Ihe atụ a na - esetịpụ akụkụ dị iche maka akụkụ anọ niile nke <p> mmewere: \n
        \t nlere \n
        \t p {
          \t margin-top: 100px;
         \t margin-bottom: 100px;
         \t margin-right: 150px;
         \t margin-left: 80px;
        \t }\n\n

        Mkpa - Ngwongwo Shorthand \n
        Ibelata koodu a, enwere ike ikwuputa akụrụngwa niile dị n\'otu ala.
        Ngwongwo oke bu ala ndi ozo di nkenke ma obu odi nma \n
        \t margin-top\n
        \t margin-right\n
        \t margin-bottom\n
        \t margin-left\n
        \t Ya mere, lee otu o si aru oru: \n
        Ọ bụrụ na Akụ Akụkụ Akụkụ Oke nwere ụkpụrụ anọ: \n
         \t oke: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t oke ala bụ 25px \n
        oke ngbago o 50px
        \t  ala bụ 75px \n
         \t hapụrụ ala bu 100px \n
         \t nlere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ọ bụrụ na akụ dị n\'akụkụ oke nwere ụkpụrụ atọ: \n
        • \t oke: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        o \t oke ala bụ 25px \n
        Osisi aka nri na aka ekpe bu 50px \n
        o \t  ala bụ 75px \n
        \t nlere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ọ bụrụ na Akụ Akụkụ Akụkụ Oke nwere ụkpụrụ abụọ: \n
        • \t ala: 25px 50px; \n
        o \t oke na akuku ala di 25px \n
        Osisi aka nri na aka ekpe bu 50px \n
         \t nlere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px 50px; \n
        \t } \n

        \t  bụrụ na akụ dị n\'akụkụ oke nwere otu uru: \n
         \t ala: 25px; \n
        \t n\'akụkụ anọ niile dị 25px \n
        \t  nlere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t margin: 25px; \n
        \t } \n\n


        Ngwunye CSS - Onye Isi N \n
        \t CSS nwere ihe ngwongwo maka ikwuputa uzo ndi ozo di n\’akuku obula: \n
        \t padding-top\n
        \t padding-right\n
        \t padding-bottom\n
        \t padding-left\n\n

        Ngwongwo padding niile nwere ike inwe ihe ndia: \n
        • \t ogologo - na-egosipụta padding na px, pt, cm, wdg. \n
        Inheritkete - akọwapụta na ekwesịrị inweta ihe mgbochi ahụ site na nne na nna
        \t Mara: Anaghị anabata ụkpụrụ ọjọọ. \n
        Ihe atụ a na - esetịpụ paịlị dị  iche maka akụkụ anọ niile nke <div> mmewere: \n
        \t  nlere \n
        \t div {\n
         \t padding-top: 50px; \n
         \t padding-right: 30px; \n
         \t padding-bottom: 50px; \n
          \t padding-left: 80px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ime akwa - Ngwongwo Shorthand \n
        \t Iji imechi koodu ahụ, ọ ga - ekwe omume ịkọpụta ngwongwo niile a na - eji akpa akụ n\’otu ihe. \n
        Ngwongwo ngwongwo a bụ ihe dị mkpụmkpụ maka ihe ndị dị na ya
         Ngw \n: \n
        \t padding-top \n
         \t padding-right \n
        \t padding-bottom \n
        \t padding-left \n
        \t Ya mere, lee otu o si aru oru: \n
        \t Ọ bụrụ na ngwongwo ahụ nwere ngwongwo anọ: \n
         \t padding: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
         \t n\’elu akwa bụ 25px \n
         \t right padding bu 50px \n
         \t padding ala bụ 75px \n
         \t padding aka ekpe bu 100px \n
         \t nlere \n
        \t div {\n
        \t  padding: 25px 50px 75px 100px; \n
        \t } \n\n

        \t Ọ bụrụ na ngwongwo ahụ e ji achọ ihe nwere ụkpụrụ atọ: \n
         \t padding: 25px 50px 75px; \n
         \t n\’elu akwa bụ 25px \n
         \t n\'aka nri na aka ekpe bu 50px \n
         \t padding ala bụ 75px \n\n
        Ihe nlere \n
        \t div {\n
        \t  padding: 25px 50px 75px; \n
        \t }
        \t Ọ bụrụ na ngwongwo e ji achọ ihe nwere ụkpụrụ abụọ: \n
        \t padding: 25px 50px; \n
         \t n\’elu na ala bụ 25px \n
         \t n\'aka nri na aka ekpe bu 50px \n
        \t Ọ bụrụ na ngwongwo e ji achọ ihe nwere otu uru: \n
         \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t ihe anọ a na-akụ ahụ bụ 25px \n
         \t nlere \n
        \t p {\n
         \t padding: 25px; \n
        \t} \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_css_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\tEderede CSS \n\n
        Agba Text \n
        \t A na-eji ihe eji agba idozi agba nke ederede. Akọwapụtara na agba ahụ: \n
        • \t aha agba - dị ka \"uhie\" \n
        \t Ahịrị ederede maka ibe akọwapụtara na ahụ ahọpụtara. \n\n
        \t nlere \n
        \t body {\n
        \t  color: blue; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h1 {\n
         \t color: green; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Ederede itinye n\'ọnọdụ \n
        A na-eji ihe ederede-itinye n\'ọnọdụ nke ederede iji dozie eriri kwụ ọtọ ederede. \n
        \t ederede nwere ike aka ekpe ma ọ bụ aka nri, kwezie, ma ọ bụ zie ezi. \n
        Ihe atụ a na-egosi na etinyere ederede n\'etiti, na aka ekpe na aka nri ederede (aka ekpe \n
        Ntinye ederede bụ ndabara ma ọ bụrụ na ntụzịaka aka ekpe-aka-nri, ma ka idozi ntinye aka nri bu oburu ma ọ bụrụ
        ederede \n
        \t direction is right-to-left): \n\n
        Nlele \n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-align: center; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
        \t  text-align: left; \n
        \t }\n

        Odikwa ederede \n
        A na-eji ihe ịchọ mma ederede iji wepu ma ọ bụ wepu ihe ndozi ederede. \n
        \t Ihe ndozi ederede bara uru: odighi; a na-ejikarị wepu gosipụta na njikọ: \n
        \t Nlele \n
        \t a {\n
        \t  text-decoration: none; \n
        \t } \n
        \t The other text-decoration values are used to decorate text: \n
        \t Nlele \n
        \t h1 {\n
        \t  text-decoration: overline; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
         \t text-decoration: line-through; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Ederede mgbanwe \n
        \tA na-eji ihe ederede-ederede iji kọwaa mkpụrụedemede ukwu na nke nta na ederede. \n
        Enwere ike iji ya mee ihe niile ka ọ bụrụ obere mkpụrụedemede ukwu na nke pere mpe, ma ọ bụ jiri akara \n
        \t leta mbu nke okwu obula: \n\n
        Nlele \n
        \t p.uppercase {\n
         \t text-transform: uppercase; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.lowercase {\n
        \t  text-transform: lowercase; \n
        \t }\n\n

        CSS Fonts \n

        Font ezinaulo \n
        \t Ezi font nke ederede ya ka atọrọ ya na ihe ulo ezighi ezi ya. \n
        Ngwongwo ulo font kwesiri inwe otutu font di ka \"ida ada\" usoro. Ọ bụrụ na \n
        \t nchọgharị anaghị akwado font nke mbụ, ọ na-anwale font na-esote, na ndị ọzọ. \n
        \t Bido na font ichoro, ma jiri ezinulo bipute mechie, ka ihe nchọgharị wee bulie \n
        Ọ bụ font yiri ibe ya na ezinụlọ jikọtara ọnụ, ọ bụrụ na enweghị fotin ọzọ dị. \n
        \t Mara: Ọ bụrụ na aha font ezinụlọ karịrị otu mkpụrụ okwu, ọ ga-abụrịrị na ntụte okwu,
        \t ka: \"Times New Roman\". \n
        A kọwara ihe karịrị otu ezinụlọ font na ndepụta nkewa: \n\n
        Nlele \n
        \t p {\n
         \t font-family: \"Times New Roman\", Times, serif; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Font Style \n
        A na-ejikarị ihe eji eme ihe iji dee ederede italic. \n
        \t Ngwongwo a nwere ihe ato: \n
        • \t nkịtị - Egosiputa ederede dika odi \n
        • \ Italic - E gosipụtara ederede n\'ozi nkịtị \n
        • \t oblique - Ederede \"adiahade\" (oblique yikariri ya na italic, mana na \n akwadoghi) \n\n
        \t nlere \n
        \t p.normal {\n
          font-style: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.italic {\n
          font-style: italic; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.oblique {\n
          font-style: oblique; \n
        \t } \n\n

        Font Size na Pixels \n
        \t tingtọlite ​​ederede ederede na pikselụ na-enye gị ikike ijikwa ogo ederede: \n\n
        Nlele \n
        \t h1 {\n
          \t font-size: 40px; \n
        \t }\n

        \t h2 {\n
          \t font-size: 30px; \n
        \t }\n\n

        Font Weight \n
        \t Njirimara font-nauyi na-akowa ibu nke font: \n\n
        Nlele \n
        \t p.normal {\n
         \t font-weight: normal; \n
        \t }\n

        \t p.thick {\n
         \t font-weight: bold; \n
        \t} \n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of Igbo CSS Contents -->
    <!-- End of CSS Contents -->

    <!-- JavaScript Contents -->
    <!-- English JavaScript Contents -->
    <string name="en_js_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJavaScript\n

        \t The <script> Tag\n
        \t In HTML, JavaScript code must be inserted between <script> and </script> tags.\n

        JavaScript in <head>\n
        \t In this example, a JavaScript function is placed in the <head> section of an HTML page. \n
        \t The function is invoked (called) when a button is clicked: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <head>\n
        \t <script>\n
        \t function myFunction() {\n
        \t  document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = \"Paragraph changed.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </script>\n
        \t </head>\n
        \t <body>\n
        \t <h1>A Web Page</h1>\n
        \t <p id=\"demo\">A Paragraph</p>\n
        \t <button type=\"button\" onclick=\"myFunction()\">Try it</button>\n
        \t </body>\n
        \t </html>\n
        JavaScript in <body>\n
        \t In this example, a JavaScript function is placed in the <body> section of an HTML page. \n
        \t The function is invoked (called) when a button is clicked: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body> \n

        \t <h1>A Web Page</h1>\n

        \t <p id=\"demo\">A Paragraph</p>\n
        \t <button type=\"button\" onclick=\"myFunction()\">Try it</button>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t function myFunction() {\n
        \t document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = \"Paragraph changed.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html>\n
        \t Placing scripts at the bottom of the <body> element improves the display speed, \n
         \t because script interpretation slows down the display. \n

        External JavaScript\n
        \t Scripts can also be placed in external files: \n
        \t External scripts are practical when the same code is used in many different web\n \tpages. \n
        \t JavaScript files have the file extension .js. \n
        \t To use an external script, put the name of the script file in the src (source) attribute\n of\n
        \t a <script> tag: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t <script src=\"myScript.js\"></script>\n
        \t You can place an external script reference in <head> or <body> as you like. \n
        \t The script will behave as if it was located exactly where the <script> tag is located. \n
        \t External scripts cannot contain <script> tags. \n

        External JavaScript Advantages\n
        \t Placing scripts in external files has some advantages: \n
        \t It separates HTML and code\n
        \t It makes HTML and JavaScript easier to read and maintain\n
        \t Cached JavaScript files can speed up page loads\n
        JavaScript Output\n

        \t JavaScript can \"display\" data in different ways: \n
        \t Writing into an HTML element, using innerHTML. \n
        \t Writing into the HTML output using document.write().\n
        \t Writing into an alert box, using window.alert().\n
        \t Writing into the browser console, using console.log().\n

        Using innerHTML\n
        \t To access an HTML element, JavaScript can use the document.getElementById(id) \n
         \t method\n.
        \t The id attribute defines the HTML element. The innerHTML property defines the HTML\n \t content: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n
        \t <p id=\"demo\"></p>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = 5 + 6; \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html> \n
        \t Changing the innerHTML property of an HTML element is a common way to display\n
        \t data in HTML. \n



        Using document.write()\n
        \t For testing purposes, it is convenient to use document.write():\n
        \t Example\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t document.write(5 + 6); \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html> \n
        \t Using document.write() after an HTML document is loaded, will delete all existing\n
        \t HTML: \n


        Using window.alert()\n
        \t You can use an alert box to display data: \n
        \t Example\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t window.alert(5 + 6); \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html>\n
        Using console.log()\n
        \t For debugging purposes, you can use the console.log() method to display data.\n
        \t You will learn more about debugging in a later chapter. \n
        \t Example\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t console.log(5 + 6); \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_js_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tJavaScript Statements\n

        \tExample\n
        \t var x, y, z;    // Statement 1\n
        \t x = 5;          // Statement 2\n
        \t y = 6;          // Statement 3\n
        \t z = x + y;      // Statement 4\n

        \tJavaScript Statements\n
        JavaScript statements are composed of:\n
        Values, Operators, Expressions, Keywords, and Comments.\n
        This statement tells the browser to write \"Hello Dolly.\" inside an HTML element with\n id=\"demo\":\n
        Example\n
        document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = \"Hello Dolly.\";\n
        Most JavaScript programs contain many JavaScript statements.\n
        The statements are executed, one by one, in the same order as they are written.\n
        JavaScript programs (and JavaScript statements) are often called JavaScript code. \n

        \tSemicolons ;\n
        Semicolons separate JavaScript statements.\n
        Add a semicolon at the end of each executable statement:\n
        \t var a, b, c;     // Declare 3 variables\n
        \t a = 5;           // Assign the value 5 to a\n
        \t b = 6;           // Assign the value 6 to b\n
        \t c = a + b;       // Assign the sum of a and b to c\n
        When separated by semicolons, multiple statements on one line are allowed:\n
        \t a = 5; b = 6; c = a + b; \n
        On the web, you might see examples without semicolons.\n
        Ending statements with semicolon is not required, but highly recommended.\n

        \tJavaScript Syntax\n

        JavaScript syntax is the set of rules, how JavaScript programs are constructed:\n
        \t var x, y, z;          // How to declare variables\n
        \t x = 5; y = 6;      // How to assign values\n
        \t z = x + y;         // How to compute values\n

        \tJavaScript Literals\n
        The most important rules for writing fixed values are:\n
        Numbers are written with or without decimals:\n
        10.50\n

        1001\n
        Strings are text, written within double or single quotes:\n
        \"Ahmed Mujahid\"\n

        \'Ahmed Mujahid\' \n

        \tJavaScript Variables\n
        In a programming language, variables are used to store data values.\n
        JavaScript uses the var keyword to declare variables.\n
        An equal sign is used to assign values to variables.\n
        In this example, x is defined as a variable. Then, x is assigned (given) the value 6:\n
        var x;\n

        x = 6;\n
        \tJavaScript Operators\n
        JavaScript uses arithmetic operators ( + - * / ) to compute values:\n
        (5 + 6) * 10\n
        JavaScript uses an assignment operator ( = ) to assign values to variables:\n
        var x, y;\n
        x = 5;\n
        y = 6; \n

        \tJavaScript Expressions\n
        An expression is a combination of values, variables, and operators, which computes to a value.\n
        The computation is called an evaluation.\n
        For example, 5 * 10 evaluates to 50:\n
        5 * 10 \n
        Expressions can also contain variable values:\n
        x * 10 \n
        The values can be of various types, such as numbers and strings.\n
        For example, \"John\" + \" \" + \"Doe\", evaluates to \"John Doe\":\n
        \"John\" + \" \" + \"Doe\" \n

        \tJavaScript Keywords\n
        JavaScript keywords are used to identify actions to be performed.\n
        The var keyword tells the browser to create variables:\n
        var x, y;\n
        x = 5 + 6;\n
        y = x * 10; \n

        \tJavaScript Comments\n
        Not all JavaScript statements are \"executed\".\n
        Code after double slashes // or between /* and */ is treated as a comment.\n
        Comments are ignored, and will not be executed:\n
        var x = 5;   // I will be executed\n

        // var x = 6;   I will NOT be executed\n
        \tSHORTCUT FOR COMMENT IS ( CTRL + /)\n

        \tJavaScript Identifiers\n
        Identifiers are names.\n
        In JavaScript, identifiers are used to name variables (and keywords, and functions, and labels).\n
        The rules for legal names are much the same in most programming languages.\n
        In JavaScript, the first character must be a letter, or an underscore (_), or a dollar sign ($).\n
        Subsequent characters may be letters, digits, underscores, or dollar signs.\n
        Numbers are not allowed as the first character.\n
        This way JavaScript can easily distinguish identifiers from numbers.\n

        \tJavaScript is Case Sensitive\n
        All JavaScript identifiers are case sensitive.\n 
        The variables lastName and lastname, are two different variables:\n
        var lastname, lastName;\n
        lastName = \"Doe\";\n
        lastname = \"Peterson\";\n
        JavaScript does not interpret VAR or Var as the keyword var.\n

        \tJavaScript and Camel Case\n
        Historically, programmers have used different ways of joining multiple words into one variable name:\n
        Hyphens:\n
        first-name, last-name, master-card, inter-city.\n
        Hyphens are not allowed in JavaScript. They are reserved for subtractions.\n
        Upper Camel Case (Pascal Case):\n
        FirstName, LastName, MasterCard, InterCity.\n
        Lower Camel Case:\n
        JavaScript programmers tend to use camel case that starts with a lowercase letter:\n
        firstName, lastName, masterCard, interCity.\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_js_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJavaScript Variables\n\n
        JavaScript variables are containers for storing data values.\n
        In this example, x, y, and z, are variables:\n
        Example\n
        var x = 5;\n
        var y = 6;\n
        var z = x + y; \n
        From the example above, you can expect:\n
        \t x stores the value 5\n
        \t y stores the value 6\n
        \t z stores the value 11\n

        \tMuch Like Algebra\n
        In this example, price1, price2, and total, are variables:\n
        Example\n
        var price1 = 5;\n
        var price2 = 6;\n
        var total = price1 + price2;\n
        In programming, just like in algebra, we use variables (like price1) to hold values.\n
        In programming, just like in algebra, we use variables in expressions (total = price1 + price2).\n
        From the example above, you can calculate the total to be 11.\n
        JavaScript variables are containers for storing data values.\n


        \tJavaScript Identifiers\n
        All JavaScript variables must be identified with unique names.\n
        These unique names are called identifiers.\n
        Identifiers can be short names (like x and y) or more descriptive names (age, sum, totalVolume).\n
        The general rules for constructing names for variables (unique identifiers) are:\n
        \t Names can contain letters, digits, underscores, and dollar signs.\n
        \t Names must begin with a letter\n
        \t Names can also begin with $ and _ (but we will not use it in this tutorial)\n
        \t Names are case sensitive (y and Y are different variables)\n
        \t Reserved words (like JavaScript keywords) cannot be used as names\n
        JavaScript identifiers are case-sensitive.\n

        \tThe Assignment Operator\n
        In JavaScript, the equal sign (=) is an \"assignment\" operator, not an \"equal to\" operator.\n
        This is different from algebra. The following does not make sense in algebra:\n
        x = x + 5 \n
        In JavaScript, however, it makes perfect sense: it assigns the value of x + 5 to x.\n
        (It calculates the value of x + 5 and puts the result into x. The value of x is incremented by 5.)\n
        The \"equal to\" operator is written like == in JavaScript.\n

        \tJavaScript Data Types\n
        JavaScript variables can hold numbers like 100 and text values like \"John Doe\".\n
        In programming, text values are called text strings.\n
        JavaScript can handle many types of data, but for now, just think of numbers and strings. \n
        Strings are written inside double or single quotes. Numbers are written without quotes.\n
        If you put a number in quotes, it will be treated as a text string.\n
        Example\n
        var pi = 3.14;\n
        var person = \"John Doe\";\n
        var answer = \'Yes I am!\'; \n

        \tDeclaring (Creating) JavaScript Variables\n
        Creating a variable in JavaScript is called \"declaring\" a variable. \n
        You declare a JavaScript variable with the var keyword:\n
        var carName; \n
        After the declaration, the variable has no value (technically it has the value of undefined).\n
        To assign a value to the variable, use the equal sign:\n
        carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        You can also assign a value to the variable when you declare it:\n
        var carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        In the example below, we create a variable called carName and assign the value \"Volvo\" to it.\n
        Then we \"output\" the value inside an HTML paragraph with id=\"demo\":\n

        Example\n
        <p id=\"demo\"></p>\n

        <script>\n
        \t var carName = \"Volvo\";\n
        \t document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = carName;\n
        </script> \n
        It\'s a good programming practice to declare all variables at the beginning of a script.\n

        \t One Statement, Many Variables\n
        You can declare many variables in one statement.\n
        Start the statement with var and separate the variables by comma:\n
        var person = \"John Doe\", carName = \"Volvo\", price = 200; \n
        A declaration can span multiple lines: \n
        var person = \"John Doe\",\n
        carName = \"Volvo\",\n
        price = 200; \n

    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_js_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\t\t JavaScript String Operators\n
        The + operator can also be used to add (concatenate) strings.\n
        Example\n
        var txt1 = \"Ahmed\";\n
        var txt2 = \"Mujahid\";\n
        var txt3 = txt1 + \" \" + txt2;\n
        The result of txt3 will be:\n
        Ahmed Mujahid\n
        The += assignment operator can also be used to add (concatenate) strings:\n
        Example\n
        var txt1 = \"Hello \";\n
        txt1 += \"Sir Musa\"; \n
        The result of txt1 will be:\n
        Hello Sir Musa\n
        When used on strings, the + operator is called the concatenation operator.\n

        \tAdding Strings and Numbers\n
        Adding two numbers, will return the sum, but adding a number and a string will return a string:\n
        Example\n
        var x = 5 + 10;\n
        var y = \"5\" + 5;\n
        var z = \"Good\" + 5;\n
        The result of x, y, and z will be:\n
        15\n
        55\n
        Good5\n
        If you add a number and a string, the result will be a string!\n

        \t JavaScript Arithmetic\n

        \tArithmetic Operations\n
        A typical arithmetic operation operates on two numbers.\n
        The two numbers can be literals:\n
        Example\n
        var x = 100 + 50;\n
        or variables:\n
        Example\n
        var x = a + b;\n
        or expressions:\n
        Example\n
        var x = (100 + 50) * a;\n

        Operators and Operands\n
        The numbers (in an arithmetic operation) are called operands.\n
        The operation (to be performed between the two operands) is defined by an operator.\n
        Operand	Operator	Operand\n
        100	+	50\n

        Adding\n
        The addition operator (+) adds numbers:\n
        Example\n
        var x = 5;\n
        var y = 2;\n
        var z = x + y;\n

        Subtracting\n
        The subtraction operator (-) subtracts numbers.\n
        Example\n
        var x = 5;\n
        var y = 2;\n
        var z = x - y;\n

        Multiplying\n
        The multiplication operator (*) multiplies numbers.\n
        Example\n
        var x = 5;\n
        var y = 2;\n
        var z = x * y;\n

        Dividing\n
        The division operator (/) divides numbers.\n
        Example\n
        var x = 5;\n
        var y = 2;\n
        var z = x / y;\n

    ]]></string>

    <string name="en_js_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\t\tJavaScript Data Types\n
        JavaScript variables can hold many data types: numbers, strings, objects and more:\n
        var length = 16;/t // Number\n
        var lastName = \"Ahmed\";/t // String\n
        var x = {firstName:\"Mujahid\", lastName:\"Musa\"};/t // Object\n
        The Concept of Data Types\n
        In programming, data types is an important concept.\n
        To be able to operate on variables, it is important to know something about the type.\n
        Without data types, a computer cannot safely solve this:\n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Does it make any sense to add \"Volvo\" to sixteen? Will it produce an error or will it produce a result?\n
        JavaScript will treat the example above as:\n
        var x = \"16\" + \"Volvo\"; \n
        When adding a number and a string, JavaScript will treat the number as a string.\n
        Example\n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\";\n
        Example\n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16;\n
        JavaScript evaluates expressions from left to right. Different sequences can produce different results:\n
        JavaScript:\n
        var x = 16 + 4 + \"Volvo\";\n
        Result:\n
        20Volvo \n
        JavaScript:\n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16 + 4;\n
        Result:\n
        Volvo164 \n
        In the first example, JavaScript treats 16 and 4 as numbers, until it reaches \"Volvo\".\n
        In the second example, since the first operand is a string, all operands are treated as strings.\n
        \tJavaScript Strings\n
        A string (or a text string) is a series of characters like \"John Doe\".\n
        Strings are written with quotes. You can use single or double quotes:\n
        Example\n
        var carName1 = \"Volvo XC60\";   // Using double quotes\n
        var carName2 = \'Volvo XC60\';   // Using single quotes \n
        You can use quotes inside a string, as long as they don\'t match the quotes surrounding the string:\n
        Example\n
        var answer1 = \"It\'s alright\";             // Single quote inside double quotes\n
        var answer2 = \"He is called \'Johnny\'\";    // Single quotes inside double quotes\n
        var answer3 = \'He is called \"Johnny\"\';    // Double quotes inside single quotes \n
        You will learn more about strings later in this tutorial.\n
        \tJavaScript Numbers\n
        JavaScript has only one type of numbers.\n
        Numbers can be written with, or without decimals:\n
        Example\n
        var x1 = 34.00;     // Written with decimals\n
        var x2 = 34;        // Written without decimals\n
        Extra large or extra small numbers can be written with scientific (exponential) notation:\n
        Example\n
        var y = 123e5;      // 12300000\n
        var z = 123e-5;     // 0.00123 \n
        You will learn more about numbers later in this tutorial.\n
        \tJavaScript Booleans\n
        Booleans can only have two values: true or false.\n
        Example\n
        var x = 5;\n
        var y = 5;\n
        var z = 6;\n
        (x == y)       // Returns true\n
        (x == z)       // Returns false \n
        Booleans are often used in conditional testing.\n
        You will learn more about conditional testing later in this tutorial.\n

        \tJavaScript Arrays\n
        JavaScript arrays are written with square brackets.\n
        Array items are separated by commas.\n
        The following code declares (creates) an array called cars, containing three items (car names):\n
        Example\n
        var cars = [\"Saab\", \"Volvo\", \"BMW\"];\n
        Array indexes are zero-based, which means the first item is [0], second is [1], and so on.\n
        You will learn more about arrays later in this tutorial.\n

        \t JavaScript Objects\n
        JavaScript objects are written with curly braces {}.\n
        Object properties are written as name:value pairs, separated by commas.\n
        Example\n
        var person = {firstName:\"Ahmed\", lastName:\"Mujahid\", age:30, eyeColor:\"blue\"};\n
        The object (person) in the example above has 4 properties: firstName, lastName, age, and eyeColor.\n
        You will learn more about objects later in this tutorial.\n

    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of English JavaScript Contents -->
    <!-- Hausa JavaScript Contents -->
    <string name="ha_js_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJavaScript Inda \n

        \t <script> Tag \n
        \t A cikin HTML, dole ne a saka lambar JavaScript tsakanin <script> da </script> alamun. \n

        JavaScript a cikin <head>\n
        \t A cikin wannan misalin, wata JavaScript aiki an sanya shi a cikin <head>sashe na shafin HTML. \n
        \t Ana kiran aikin (ana kiransa) lokacin da aka danna maballin: \n
        \t Misali\n
        \t <! KYAUTA html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <kai>\n
        \t <rubutun>\n
        \t aiki myFunction () {\n
        \t document.getElementById (\"demo\") .innerHTML = \"Sakin layi ya canza.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </ rubutun>\n
        \t </ kai>\n
        \t <jiki>\n
        \t <h1>Shafin yanar gizo</ h1>\n
        \t <p id= \"demo\">Sakin layi</ p>\n
        \t <maballin nau\'in= \"maballin\" onclick= \"myFunction ()\">Gwada shi</ maballin>\n
        \t </ jiki>\n
        \t </ html>\n
        JavaScript a cikin <body>\n
        \t A cikin wannan misalin, wata JavaScript aiki an sanya shi a cikin <body>sashe na shafin HTML. \n
        \t Ana kiran aikin (ana kiransa) lokacin da aka danna maballin: \n
        \t Misali\n
        \t <! KYAUTA html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <jiki> \n

        \t <h1>Shafin yanar gizo</ h1>\n

        \t <p id= \"demo\">Sakin layi</ p>\n
        \t <maballin nau\'in= \"maballin\" onclick= \"myFunction ()\">Gwada shi</ maballin>\n

        \t <rubutun>\n
        \t aiki myFunction () {\n
        \t document.getElementById (/\"demo\") .innerHTML = \"Sakin layi ya canza.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </ rubutun>\n

        \t </ jiki>\n
        \t </ html>\n
        \t Sanya rubutun a kasan <rabi> kashi yana inganta saurin nunawa, \n
         \t saboda fassarar rubutun yana rage jinkirin nuni. \n

        JavaScript na waje\n
        \t Hakanan za\'a iya sanya rubutun a cikin fayilolin na waje: \n
        \t Rubutun waje yana da amfani yayin da aka yi amfani da lambar iri ɗaya a cikin yanar gizo da yawa \n \tshafuka. \n
        \t Fayilolin JavaScript suna da tsawo .js. \n
        \t Don amfani da rubutun na waje, sanya sunan rubutun fayil ɗin a cikin src (tushe) sifa \n na \n
        \ta <script> tag: \n
        \t Misali\n
        \t <rubutun src= \"myScript.js\"> </ rubutun>\n
        \t Kuna iya sanya bayanin rubutun na waje a ciki <head> ko <body>kamar yadda kake so. \n
        \t Kundin rubutun zai nuna kamar an samo daidai inda <script>tag is located. \n
        \t Rubutun na waje baya iya ƙunsar <script>alamun. \n

        Jawabin JavaScript na waje\n
        \t Sanya rubutun a cikin fayilolin na waje yana da wasu fa\'idodi: \n
        \t Yana raba HTML da lambar \n
        \t Yana sa HTML da JavaScript sauki don karantawa da kiyaye \n
        \t Fayilolin JavaScript da aka cakuda na iya saurin sauke nauyin shafin \n
        JavaScript Output\n

        \t JavaScript na iya \"nuna\" bayanai ta hanyoyi daban-daban: \n
        \t Rubuta cikin hanyar HTML, ta amfani ciki. \n
        \t Rubuta cikin fitarwa ta HTML ta amfani da rubuce rubucen (). \n
        \t Rubuta cikin akwatin faɗakarwa, ta amfani taswabinda taga (). \n
        \t Rubutawa a cikin wasannifin mai bincike, amfani da maimako.log (). \n

        Amfani da HTML \n
        \t Don samun damar shiga abun HTML, JavaScript zai iya amfani da kundin.getElementById (id) \n
         \t hanyar \n.
        \t Sanarwar id ta bayyana ma\'anar HTML. Aikin HTML na ciki yana bayanin abun ciki na HTML \n \t: \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t <! KYAUTA html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <jiki>\n
        \t <p id= \"demo\"> </ p>\n

        \t <rubutun>\n
        \t document.getElementById (\"demo\") .innerHTML = 5 + 6; \n
        \t </ rubutun>\n

        \t </ jiki>\n
        \t </ html> \n
        \t Canza abun ciki na ciki na abubuwan HTML hanyace gama gari don nunawa \n
        \t bayanai a cikin HTML. \n

        Amfani da daftarin aiki.write () \n
        \t Don dalilai na gwaji, ya dace a yi amfani da takaddun rubutu .. (): \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t <! KYAUTA html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <jiki>\n

        \t <rubutun>\n
        \t rubuce (5 + 6); \n
        \t </ rubutun>\n

        \t </ jiki>\n
        \t </ html> \n
        \t Amfani da daftarin aiki .. () bayan an ɗoraftarin rubutun HTML, zai share duk wanda ke kasancewa \n
        \t HTML: \n

        Ta amfani da window.alert () \n
        \t Kuna iya amfani da akwatin faɗakarwa don nuna bayanai: \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t <! KYAUTA html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <jiki>\n

        \t <rubutun>\n
        \t sankarar (5 + 6); \n
        \t </ rubutun>\n

        \t </ jiki>\n
        \t </ html>\n
        Ta amfani da console.log () \n
        \t Don dalilai na yin gyara, zaku iya amfani da hanyarrngar tazarar.log () don nuna bayanai. \n
        \t Za ku sami ƙarin koyo game da yin fatarar kuɗi a cikin wani babi na gaba. \n
        \t Misalin \n
        \t <! KYAUTA html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <jiki>\n

        \t <rubutun>\n
        \t maimako.log (5 + 6); \n
        \t </ rubutun>\n

        \t </ jiki>\n
        \t </ html> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_js_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\tBayanin JavaScript \n

        \tExample \n
        \t var x, y, z; // Bayanin 1 \n
        \tx = 5; // Bayani na 2 \n
        \ty = 6; // Bayanin 3 3 n
        \tz = x + y; // Bayanin 4 4 n

        Bayanan Magana \tJavaScript. \n
        Bayanan JavaScript sun hada da: \n
        Dabi\'u, Ma\'aikata, Bayyanawa, Kalmomi, da Sharhi. \n
        Wannan sanarwa ta gaya wa mai binciken don rubuta \"Sannu Dolly.\" a cikin sigar HTML tare da \n id = \"demo\": \n
        Misali \n
        document.getElementById (\"demo\") .innerHTML = \"Sannu Dolly.\"; \n
        Mafi yawan shirye-shiryen JavaScript suna dauke da maganganun JavaScript da yawa. \n
        An aiwatar da maganganun, daya bayan daya, a cikin tsari iri daya kamar yadda aka rubuta. \n
        Shirye-shiryen JavaScript (da maganganun JavaScript) galibi ana kiranta da lambar JavaScript. \n

        \tSemicolons; \n
        Semicolons ya raba bayanan JavaScript. \n
        Sanya wani karamin abu a karshen kowane bayanin da za\'a iya aiwatarwa: \n
        \t var a, b, c; // Bayyana masu canji 3 \n
        \ta = 5; // Sanya darajar 5 zuwa \n
        \tb = 6; // Sanya darajar 6 zuwa b \n
        \tc = a + b; // Sanya jimlar a da b zuwa c \n
        Lokacin da aka raba shi da semicolons, ba da damar maganganu da yawa akan layi ɗaya: \n
        \ta = 5; b =6; c = a + b; \n
        A yanar gizo, zaku iya ganin misalai ba tare da wasan kwaikwayo ba. \n Maganar kawo karshen maganganu tare da wasanninta ba a buƙata, amma an ba da shawarar sosai. \n

        \tJavaScript Syntax \n

        Syntax JavaScript shine saitin dokoki, yadda ake gina shirye-shiryen JavaScript: \n
        \t var x, y, z; // Yadda zaka bayyana masu canji \n
        \tx = 5; y =6; // Yadda ake sanya abubuwan daraja \n
        \tz = x + y; // Yadda ake lissafin dabi\'u \n

        \tJavaScript Littattafan \n
        Mafi mahimman ka\'idoji don rubuta ƙididdigar ƙaddarar su sune: \n
        Lissafi an rubuta tare da ko ba tare da adada ba: \n
        10.50 \n

        1001 \n
        Kirtani rubutu ne, an yi rubutu cikin abubuwan da aka ninka biyu ko guda ɗaya: \n
        \"Ahmed Mujahid\" \n

        \'Ahmed Mujahid\' \n

        \tJavaScript Bambanci \n
        A cikin harshen shirye-shirye, ana amfani da masu canji don adana mahimman bayanan. \n
        JavaScript yana amfani da kalmar key domin sheda masu canji. \n
        Ana amfani da alamar daidai don sanya dabi\'u ga masu canji. \n
        A wannan misalin, an bayyana x a matsayin mai canzawa. Sannan, x an sanya (bayarwa) ƙimar 6: \n
        var x; \n

        x = 6; \n
        \tJavaScript masu aiki \n
        JavaScript yana amfani da masu amfani da ilmin lissafi (+ - * /) don lissafin dabi\'u: \n
        (5 + 6) * 10 \n
        JavaScript yana amfani da mai ba da sabis (=) don sanya dabi\'u ga masu canji: \n
        var x, y; \n
        x = 5; \n
        y = 6; \n

        Bayanin Maganganun \n
        Magana shine hade da dabi\'u, masu canji, da kuma masu aiki, wanda ke daidaitawa kan darajar. \n
        Ana kiran lissafin lissafi. \n
        Misali, 5 * 10 kimantawa zuwa 50: \n
        5 * 10 \n
        Bayyanawa na iya ƙunsar dabi\'u masu canzawa: \n
        x * 10 \n
        Dabi\'u na iya zama da nau\'ikan daban-daban, kamar lambobi da kiyoyi. \n
        Misali, \"John\" + \"\" \"\" Doe \", kimantawa ga\" John Doe \": \n
        \"Yahaya\" + \"\" + \"Doe\" \n

        \tJavaScript Keywords \n
        Ana amfani da kalmomin JavaScript don gano ayyukan da za a yi. \n
        Kalmar var za ta gaya wa mai binciken ya kirkiri masu canji: \n
        var x, y; \n
        x = 5 + 6; \n
        y = x * 10; \n

        \tJavaScript Sharhi \n
        Ba duk maganganun JavaScript bane \"an kashe su\". \n
        Lamari bayan bugu biyu // ko tsakanin / * da * / ana ɗaukarsa azaman bayani ne. \n
        Ba a yarda da tsokaci ba, kuma ba za a kashe shi ba: \n
        var x = 5; // Za\'a kashe ni \n

        // var x = 6; Ba za a kashe ni ba \n
        \tSHORTCUT DON CIGABA NE (CTRL + /) \n

        \tJavaScript ganowa \n
        Wadanda suke tantancewa sunaye ne. \n
        A cikin JavaScript, ana amfani da masu gano suna don masu canji (da kalmomin shiga, da ayyuka, da alamomi). \n
        Ka\'idoji don sunaye na doka sun yi daidai iri daya a yawancin yaruka shirye-shirye. \n
        A cikin JavaScript, harafin farko dole ne ya zama harafi, ko maƙasudin (_), ko alamar dala ($). \n
        Sauran haruffa na iya zama haruffa, lambobi, baƙi, ko alamun dala. \n
        Ba a yarda da lambobi azaman halin farko ba. \n Ta wannan hanyar JavaScript zai iya rarrabe masu gano abubuwa daga lambobi. \n

        \tJavaScript shi ne Maganar hankali \'n
        Duk masu gano JavaScript masu hankali ne. \n
        Masu canji sunanan karshe da sunan karshe, suna da bambanci guda biyu: \n
        var lastname, lastName; \n
        lastName = \"Doe\"; \n
        sunan mahaifa = \"Peterson\"; \n
        JavaScript ba ya fassara VAR ko Var kamar yadda kalma dabam take. \n

        \tJavaScript da Cefen Rakumi \n
        Tarihi, masu shirye-shirye sun yi amfani da hanyoyi daban-daban na haɗa kalmomi da yawa cikin suna masu canzawa: \n
        Hyphens: \n
        sunan farko, sunan mahaifa, mashin-kati, tsakiyar gari. \n
        Ba a yarda Hyphens a cikin JavaScript ba. An ajiye su don ragewa. \n
        Batu na Rakumi (Laifin Pascal): \n
        Na farko, Na karshe, da MasterCard, da na Intanet. \n
        Casearamar Rakumi: \n
        Masu shirya JavaScript sukan yi amfani da karar rakumi da ke farawa da ƙaramin wasika: \n
        Farkon, Sunan karshe, MasterCard, Sakon. \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_js_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJavaScript Bambanci\n
        JavaScript masu canji sune kwantena don adana bayanan ƙimar. \n
        A cikin wannan misalin, x, y, da z, masu canji ne: \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 6; \n
        var z = x + y; \n
        Daga misalin da ke sama, zaku iya tsammanin: \n
        \tx yana adana darajar 5 \n
        \ty yana adana darajar 6 \n
        \tz yana adana darajar 11 \n

        \tMuch Kamar Algebra \n
        A wannan misalin, farashin1, farashi2, da jimilla, masu canji ne: \n
        Misali \n
        var farashin1 = 5; \n
        var farashin2 = 6; \n
        var jimlar = farashin1 + farashin2; \n
        A cikin shirye-shirye, kamar a cikin aljibra, muna amfani da masu canji (kamar farashi1) don riƙe dabi\'u. \n
        A cikin shirye-shirye, kamar a cikin algebra, muna amfani da masu canji a cikin maganganu (jimlar = farashin1 + price2). \n
        Daga misalin da ke sama, zaku iya lissafta jimlar su zama 11. \n
        JavaScript masu canji sune kwantena don adana bayanan ƙimar. \n

        \tJavaScript ganowa \n
        Duk masu canji na JavaScript dole ne a gano su da sunaye na musamman. \n
        Wadannan suna na musamman ana kiransu masu gano. \n
        Wadanda ke bayyana su na iya zama gajerun sunaye (kamar x da y) ko ƙarin sunayen kwatanci (shekaru, jimla, jimlarVolume). \n
        Ka\'idojin gaba daya na yin sunayen masu canji (masu gano su daban) sune: \n
        \t Sunaye na iya lettersunsar haruffa, lambobi, ƙasashe, da alamun dala. \n
        \t Sunaye dole ne su fara da harafi \n
        \t Sunaye na iya farawa da $ da _ (amma ba za mu yi amfani da shi ba a wannan koyawa) \n
        \t Sunaye suna da hankali (y da Y masu bambanci daban-daban) \n
        \t Adana kalmomin da aka ajiye (kamar kalmomin shiga JavaScript) baza ayi amfani dasu azaman sunaye \n
        Masu gano JavaScript suna dauke da hujjoji. \n

        \t Mai ba da aiki Opera \n
        A cikin JavaScript, daidai alamar (=) ma\'aikaci ne \"aikin\", ba wani \"daidai da\" afareta ba. \n
        Wannan ya bambanta da algebra. Wadannan ba su da ma\'ana a cikin algebra: \n
        x = x + 5 \n
        A cikin JavaScript, koyaya, yana da ma\'ana: yana sanya darajar x + 5 zuwa x. \n
        (Yana ƙididdige darajar x + 5 kuma yana sanya sakamako cikin x. Ofimar x ta karu da 5.) \n
        Ana amfani da \"daidai da\" mai aiki kamar == a cikin JavaScript. \n

        \tJavaScript Nau\'in Bayani \n
        Masu cancantar JavaScript za su iya riƙe lambobi kamar 100 da ƙididdigar rubutu kamar \"John Doe\". \n
        A cikin shirye-shirye, ana kiran ƙimar rubutu
        JavaScript na iya sarrafa nau\'ikan bayanai da yawa, amma a yanzu, kawai tunanin lambobi da kirtani. \n
        An rubuta kirtani a ciki sau biyu ko guda. An rubuta lambobi ba tare da ambato ba. \n
        Idan ka sanya lamba a cikin kwatancen, za\'a dauke shi azaman zaren rubutu. \n
        Misali \n
        var pi = 3.14; \n
        var mutum = \"John Doe\"; \n
        var amsa = \'Na\'am!\'; \n

        \tDancewa (Kirkirar) JavaScript Bambanci \n
        Calledirƙira wani mai canzawa a cikin JavaScript ana kiranta \"ayyanawa\" m. \n
        Kuna sheda canjin JavaScript tare da kalmar key: \n
        var carName; \n
        Bayan sanarwar, mai canzawa bashi da wata daraja (a zahiri cewa yana da kimar da ba\'a tantance shi ba). \n
        Don sanya darajar ga m, yi amfani da alamar daidai: \n
        carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        Hakanan zaka iya sanya darajar ga mai canzawa lokacin da kuka ayyana shi: \n
        var carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        A misalin da ke ƙasa, muna ƙirƙirar canji da ake kira carName kuma muka sanya darajar \"Volvo\" a ciki. \n
        Sannan muna \"fitarwa\" ƙimar cikin sakin layi na HTML tare da id = \"demo\": \n

        Misali \n
        <p id= \"demo\"> </ p> \n

        <rubutun> \n
        \t var carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        \t document.getElementById (\"demo\") .innerHTML = carName; \n
        </ rubutun> \n
        Kyakkyawan tsarin shirye-shirye ne a bayyana duk masu canji a farkon rubutun. \n

        \t Bayani guda, Abubuwa da yawa \n
        Kuna iya bayyana yawancin masu canji a cikin sanarwa guda. \n
        Fara bayanin tare da var kuma ka ware masu canji ta comma: \n
        var mutum = \"John Doe\", carName = \"Volvo\", farashin = 200; \n
        A shela na iya yin layin da yawa: \n
        var mutum = \"John Doe\", \n
        carName = \"Volvo\", \n
        farashin = 200; \n
     ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_js_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\t\t \t JavaScript String Operator \n
        The + Hakanan za\'a iya amfani da afareta don ƙara (haɗakarwa) igiyoyi. \n
        Misali \n
        var txt1 = \"Ahmed\"; \n
        var txt2 = \"Mujahid\"; \n
        var txt3 = txt1 + \"\" + txt2; \n
        Sakamakon txt3 zai kasance: \n
        Ahmed Mujahid \n
        The + = Hakanan za\'a iya amfani da mai ba da sabis don ƙara (concatenate) kirtani: \n
        Misali \n
        var txt1 = \"Sannu\"; \ntxt1 + = \"Sir Musa\"; \n
        Sakamakon txt1 zai kasance: \n
        Sannu Sir Musa \n
        Lokacin da ake amfani da shi akan kirtani, ana kiran mai + afareta mai gudanarwa ta atomatik. \n

        \t dingara kirtani da Lambobi \n
        Adara lambobi biyu, zai dawo da jimlar, amma ƙara lamba da igiya za su dawo da kirtani: \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 5 + 10; \n
        var y = \"5\" + 5; \n
        var z = \"Yayi kyau\" + 5; \n
        Sakamakon x, y, da z zai kasance: \n
        15 \n55 \n
        Nagari5 \n
        Idan ka kara lamba da kirtani, sakamakon zai zama zaren! \n

        \t JavaScript ilmin lissafi \n

        \tasirin kayan aiki \n
        Wani aiki na yau da kullun na aiki kan lambobi biyu. \n
        Lambobi biyu na iya zama masu karantu: \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 100 + 50; \n
        ko masu canji: \n
        Misali \n
        var x = a + b; \n
        ko maganganu: \n
        Misali \n
        var x = (100 + 50) * a; \n

        Ma\'aikata da Ma\'aikata \n
        Lambobin (a cikin aikin ilimin lissafi) ana kiransu operands. \n
        Mai sarrafawa ya bayyana aikin (da za\'ayi a tsakanin ma\'aikatan nan biyu)
        Operand	Mai aiki	Operand \n
        100	+	50 \n

        \Ara \n
        Additionarin mai aiki (+) kara lambobi: \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = Na biyu; \n
        var z = x + y; \n

        Ragewa \n
        Operatorar rage ma\'aikaci (-) rabe lambobi. \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = Na biyu; \n
        var z = x - y; \n

        Mai yawa \n
        Mai haɗawa da masu sauyawa (*) ya ninka lambobi. \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = Na biyu; \n
        var z = x * y; \n

        Rarrabawa \n
        Ma\'aikatan Rarraba (/) ya rarraba lambobi. \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = Na biyu; \n
        var z = x / y; \n

    ]]></string>

    <string name="ha_js_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\t\t\tJavaScript Nau\'in Bayani \n
        Masu cancantar JavaScript na iya riƙe nau\'ikan bayanai masu yawa: lambobi, kirtani, abubuwa da ƙari: \n
        var tsawon = 16; // Yawan \n
        var lastName = \"Ahmed\"; // Kiran \n
        var x = {firstName:\"Mujahid\", sunan mahaifa:\"Musa\"}; // Abun \n
        Tunanin nau\'in bayanai \n
        A cikin shirye-shirye, nau\'in bayanai muhimmin ra\'ayi ne. \n
        Don samun ikon aiki akan masu canji, yana da mahimmanci ku san wani abu game da nau\'in. \n
        Ba tare da nau\'ikan bayanai ba, komfyuta ba zata iya magance wannan ba: \n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Shin yana da wata ma\'ana don ƙara \"Volvo\" zuwa goma sha shida? Shin zai haifar da kuskure ne ko kuwa zai haifar da sakamako? \n
        JavaScript zai dauki misalin da ke sama kamar: \n
        var x = \"16\" + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Lokacin da aka ƙara lamba da kirtani, JavaScript zai dauki lamba a matsayin kirtani. \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Misali \n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16; \n
        JavaScript yana kimanta maganganu daga hagu zuwa dama. Lokaci daban na iya samar da sakamako daban: \n
        JavaScript: \n
        var x = 16 + 4 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Sakamakon: \n
        20Volvo \n
        JavaScript: \n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16 + 4; \n
        Sakamakon: \n
        Volvo164 \n
        A cikin misali na farko, JavaScript ya ɗauka 16 da 4 azaman lambobi, har sai ya kai ga \"Volvo\". \n
        A misali na biyu, tunda farkon wakar zaren kirtani ne, ana daukar dukkan wakar a matsayin kirtani. \n
        \tJavaScript Strings \n
        Wakar (ko zaren rubutu) jerin haruffa ne kamar \"John Doe\". \n
        An rubuta kirtani tare da ambato. Kuna iya amfani da ambato ɗaya ko biyu: \n
        Misali \n
        var carName1 = \"Volvo XC60\"; // Amfani da zancen ninki \n
        var carName2 = \'Volvo XC60\'; // Amfani da lafazin guda \n
        Kuna iya amfani da ambato a cikin kirtani, muddin basu dace da kwatancen da ke kewaye da kirtani ba: \n
        Misali \n
        var amsa1 = \"Yana da kyau\"; // Bayani guda cikin nasihu n \n
        var amsa2 = \"Ana kiran shi \'Johnny\'\"; // Guda guda biyu cikin kwatancen ninki \n
        var amsa3 = \"Ana kiran shi\" Johnny \"\"; // Sau biyu daga cikin abubuwan guda biyu \n
        Za ku sami ƙarin ilimi game da kirtani a gaba a cikin wannan koyawa. \n
        \tJavaScript Lambobi \n
        JavaScript yana da iri guda kawai. \n
        Za\'a iya rubuta lambobi tare da, ko kuma ba tare da adadi ba: \n
        Misali \n
        var x1 = 34,00; // Rubuta shi da decimals \n
        var x2 = 34; // Rubuta ba tare da desaloli ba \n
        Za a iya rubuta manyan oran girma ko ƙarin lambobi tare da bayanan kimiyya (ƙayyadaddun) sanarwa: \n
        Misali \n
        var y = 123e5; // 12300000 \n
        var z = 123e-5; // 0.00123 \n
        Za ku fahimci ƙarin lambobi nan gaba a wannan koyawa. \n
        \tJavaScript Booleans \n
        Leabilan za su iya samun dabi\'u biyu kawai: gaskiya ne ko arya. \n
        Misali \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 5; \n
        var z = 6; \n
        (x == y) // Ya dawo da gaskiya \n
        (x == z) // Ya dawo da karya \n
        Yawancin lokaci ana amfani da lean Boole a cikin gwajin sharadi. \n
        Za ku ƙara koya game da gwaji na ɗaba\'a a cikin wannan koyawa. \n

        \tJavaScript Arrays \n
        Rubutun JavaScript an rubuta shi da santimukan murabba\'i. \n
        Abubuwan da aka kera sun rabu da wakafi. \n
        Lambar mai zuwa ta bayyana (ƙirƙira) tsararren da ake kira motoci, dauke da abubuwa uku (sunayen mota): \n
        Misali \n
        var motoci = [\"Saab\", \"Volvo\", \"BMW\"]; \n
        Manyan jigogi na tsararru ba su da sifili, wanda ke nufin abu na farko shine [0], na biyu shine [1], da sauransu. \n
        Za ku sami ƙarin koyo game da shirye-shiryen daga baya a cikin wannan koyawa. \n

        \t JavaScript Abubuwan \n
        An rubuta abubuwan JavaScript tare da abin ƙarfafa {}. \n
        Abubuwa masu ma\' ana rubuta su kamar suna: nau\'ikan darajar, wa an raba su. \n
        Misali \n
        var mutum = {firstName:\"Ahmed\", sunan mahaifa:\"Mujahid\", shekaru:30, eyeColor:\"shudi\"}; \n
        Abubuwan (mutum) a cikin misalin da ke sama yana da kaddarori 4: na fari, sunan karshe, shekara, da kuma ido. \n
        Za ku ƙara koya game da abubuwa daga baya a wannan koyarwar. \n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of Hausa JavaScript Contents -->

    <!-- Yoruba JavaScript Contents -->
    <string name="yo_js_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJavaScript Nibo Lati \n

        \t Orukọ <script> Tag \n
        \t Ni HTML, a gbọdọ fi koodu JavaScript sii laarin <script> ati </script> afi. \n

        JavaScript ni <head>\n
        \t Ni apẹẹrẹ yii, JavaScript kaniṣẹ ti wa ni gbe ninu headhead ‹apakan ti oju-iwe HTML kan. \n
        \t Iṣẹ naa jẹ ifiwepe (ti a pe) nigbati bọtini ti tẹ: \n
        \t Apẹẹrẹ\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <head>\n
        \t <script>\n
        \t function myFunction() {\n
        \t  document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = \"Paragraph changed.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </script>\n
        \t </head>\n
        \t <body>\n
        \t <h1>A Web Page</h1>\n
        \t <p id=\"demo\">A Paragraph</p>\n
        \t <button type=\"button\" onclick=\"myFunction()\">Try it</button>\n
        \t </body>\n
        \t </html>\n

        JavaScript ni <body>\n
        \t Ni apẹẹrẹ yii, JavaScript kaniṣẹ ti wa ni gbe ninu <body>apakan ti oju-iwe HTML kan. \n
        \t Iṣẹ naa jẹ ifiwepe (ti a pe) nigbati bọtini ti tẹ: \n
        \t Apẹẹrẹ\n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body> \n

        \t <h1>A Web Page</h1>\n

        \t <p id=\"demo\">A Paragraph</p>\n
        \t <button type=\"button\" onclick=\"myFunction()\">Try it</button>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t function myFunction() {\n
        \t document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = \"Paragraph changed.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html>\n

        \t Gbigbe awọn iwe afọwọkọ ni isalẹ ipilẹ <body> mu iyara ifihan han, \n
         \t nitori itumọ fa fifalẹ ifihan. \n

        JavaScript ti ita\n
        \t Awọn afọwọkọ le tun gbe si awọn faili ita: \n
        \t Awọn iwe afọwọkọ ti ita lo wulo nigbati wọn lo koodu kanna ni ọpọlọpọ awọn oriṣiriṣi wẹẹbu \n\tawọn oju-iwe. \n
        \t Awọn faili JavaScript ni ifaagun faili .js. \n
        \t Lati lo iwe afọwọkọ ti ita, fi orukọ faili si sinusrc (orisun) abuda \n ti \n
        \ta <script> tag: \n
        \t Apẹẹrẹ\n
        \t <script src= \"myScript.js\"> </ script>\n
        \t O le gbe itọkasi iwe itagbangba sinuheadhead ‹ tabi <body>bo se wun e. \n
        \t Iwe afọwọkọ naa yoo huwa bi ẹni pe o wa ni ibiti gangan ibiti<script>tag wa ni be. \n
        \t Awọn afọwọkọ ti ode ko le ni <script>afi. \n

        Awọn anfani Anfani JavaScript ti ita\n
        \t Gbigbe awọn iwe afọwọkọ ni awọn faili ita ni awọn anfani diẹ: \n
        \t O ya HTML ati koodu \n
        \t O jẹ ki HTML ati JavaScript rọrun lati ka ati ṣetọju \n
        \t Awọn faili JavaScript ti o fipamọ le yara awọn ikojọpọ oju-iwe \n
        JavaScript Abajade\n

        \t JavaScript le \"ṣafihan\" data ni awọn ọna oriṣiriṣi: \n
        \t Kikọ sinu nkan HTML, ni liloinu HTML. \n
        \t Kikọ sinu iṣejade HTML nipa lilo dolakoko (). \n
        \t Kikọ sinu apoti itaniji, ni lilo wikileti (). \n
        \t Kikọ sinu console ẹrọ aṣawakiri, lilo console.log (). \n

        Lilo awọn HTML \n
        \t Lati wọle si nkan HTML, JavaScript le lo iwe-ipamọ.getElementById (id) \n
         ọna t \n.
        \t Ẹrọ id náà tumọ si nkan HTML. Ohun-ini ti inu naa n ṣalaye akoonu HTML \n \t: \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n
        \t <p id=\"demo\"></p>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t document.getElementById(\"demo\").innerHTML = 5 + 6; \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html> \n

        \t Yiyipada ohun-ini HTML ti ẹya HTML jẹ ọna ti o wọpọ lati ṣafihan \n
        data \ HTML. \n



        Ni lilo document.write () \n
        \t Fun awọn idi idanwo, o rọrun lati lo iwe-ipamọ.write (): \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t document.write(5 + 6); \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html> \n

        Lílo àyọkà ..write () lẹyin tí wọn ti di àkọsílẹ̀ HTML, yóò ṣèparẹ́ gbogbo \n
        \t HTML: \n


        Lilo window.alert () \n
        \t O le lo apoti itaniji lati ṣe afihan data: \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t window.alert(5 + 6); \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html>\n

        Lilo console.log () \n
        \t Fun awọn ìdí ṣiṣatunkọ, o le lo ọna-ori console.log () lati ṣafihan data. \n
        \t Iwọ yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa ṣatunṣe aṣiṣe ninu ori atẹle kan. \n
        \t Apeere \n
        \t <!DOCTYPE html>\n
        \t <html>\n
        \t <body>\n

        \t <script>\n
        \t console.log(5 + 6); \n
        \t </script>\n

        \t </body>\n
        \t </html> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_js_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJAwọn ipinlẹ JavaScript \n

        \tExample \n
        \t var x, y, z; // Gbólóhùn 1 \n
        \tx = 5; // Gbólóhùn 2 \n
        \ty = 6; // Gbólóhùn 3 \n
        \tz = x + y; // Gbólóhùn 4 \n

        Awọn ipin-ọrọ \tJavaScript \n
        Awọn gbólóhùn JavaScript ti ni: \n
        Awọn iye, Awọn oniṣẹ, Awọn asọye, Awọn Koko, ati Awọn asọye. \n
        Alaye yii sọ fun aṣawakiri lati kọ \"Kaabo Dolly.\" ninu nkan HTML pẹlu \n id = \"demo\": \n
        Apeere \n
        documenting.getElementById (\"demo\") .innerHTML = \"Kaabo Dolly.\"; \n
        Pupọ awọn eto JavaScript ni ọpọlọpọ awọn alaye JavaScript. \n
        Awọn asọtẹlẹ naa ni a pa, ni ọkọọkan, ni aṣẹ kanna bi a ti kọ wọn. \n
        Awọn eto JavaScript (ati awọn alaye JavaScript) nigbagbogbo ni wọn pe ni koodu JavaScript. \n

        \tSemicolons; \n
        Awọn Semicolons sọ awọn alaye JavaScript ya. \n
        Ṣafikun iwe afọwọkọ kan ni opin ọrọ asọtẹlẹ kọọkan: \n
        \t var a, b, c; // Sọ awọn iyatọ 3 \n
        \ta = 5; // Sọ iye rẹ 5 si a \n
        \tb = 6; // Sọ iye 6 si b \n
        \tc = a + b; // Sọ iye ti a ati b si c \n
        Nigbati a ba pin nipasẹ awọn semicolons, awọn alaye pupọ lori laini kan ni a gba laaye: \n
        \ta = 5; b =6; c = a + b; \n
        Ni oju opo wẹẹbu, o le wo awọn apẹẹrẹ laisi awọn ere-ọrọ.

        \tJavaScript Syntax \n

        Syntax JavaScript ni ṣeto awọn ofin, bawo ni a ṣe kọ awọn eto JavaScript: \n
        \t var x, y, z; // Bawo ni lati fihan awọn oniyipada \n
        \tx = 5; y =6; // Bawo ni lati fi awọn iye ṣe n \n
        \tz = x + y; // Bi o ṣe le ṣe iṣiro awọn iye \n

        \tJavaScript Litireso \n
        Awọn ofin pataki julọ fun kikọ awọn iye ti o wa titi jẹ: \n
        Awọn nọmba ti kọ pẹlu tabi laisi awọn iyege: \n
        10,50 \n

        1001 \n
        Okun jẹ ọrọ, ti a kọ laarin ilọpo meji tabi ẹyọkan: \n
        \"Ahmed Mujahid\" \n

        \'Ahmed Mujahid\' \n

        \tJavaScript Awọn iyatọ \n
        Ninu ede siseto, awọn iyatọ lo lati ṣe ifipamọ awọn iye data. \n
        JavaScript nlo oro koko var lati ṣafihan awọn oniyipada. \n
        A nlo ami dogba lati pin awọn iye si awọn oniyipada. \n
        Ni apẹẹrẹ yii, x ṣalaye bi oniyipada kan. Lẹhinna, x jẹ sọtọ (fifun) iye 6: \n
        var x; \n

        x = 6; \n
        Awọn oniṣẹ \tJavaScript \n
        JavaScript nlo awọn oniṣẹ isiro (+ - * /) lati ṣe iṣiro awọn iye: \n
        (5 + 6) * 10 \n
        JavaScript nlo oluṣakoso iṣẹ iyansilẹ (=) lati fi awọn iye si awọn oniyipada: \n
        var x, y; \n
        x = 5; \n
        y = 6; \n

        Awọn ikede \tJavaScript \n
        Ifihan jẹ akojọpọ awọn iye, oniyipada, ati awọn oniṣẹ, eyiti o ṣe iṣiro iye kan. \n
        A pe iṣiro naa ni iṣiro. \n
        Fun apẹẹrẹ, 5 * 10 ṣe iṣiro si 50: \n
        5 * 10 \n
        Awọn ifihan tun le ni awọn iye oniyipada: \n
        x * 10 \n
        Awọn iye le jẹ ti awọn oriṣi, gẹgẹ bi awọn nọmba ati awọn okun. \n
        Fun apẹẹrẹ, \"John\" + \"\" \"Doe\", awọn iṣiro si \"John Doe\": \n
        “John” + \"\" + \"Doe\" \n

        \ Awọn ọrọ Koko ọrọ tJavaScript \n
        A lo awọn bọtini JavaScript lati ṣe idanimọ awọn iṣe lati ṣe. \n
        Koko ọrọ var sọ fun aṣawakiri lati ṣẹda awọn oniyipada: \n
        var x, y; \n
        x = 5 + 6; \n
        y = x * 10; \n

        \tJavaScript Awọn asọye \n
        Kii ṣe gbogbo awọn alaye JavaScript ni “pa”. \n
        Koodu lẹhin ti awọn ipalọlọ lẹmeji // tabi laarin / * ati * / ṣe itọju bi asọye. \n
        A ti kọ awọn asọye, ati pe a ko ni pa: \n
        var x = 5; // A o pa mi run \n

        // var x = 6; Emi yoo KO pa \n
        \tSHORTCUT FUN IṣẸ WA (Ctrl + /) \n

        \ Awọn idanimọ \tJavaScript \n
        Awọn idamo jẹ awọn orukọ. \n
        Ninu JavaScript, awọn idanimọ lo lati lorukọ awọn oniyipada (ati awọn ọrọ pataki, ati awọn iṣẹ, ati awọn aami). \n
        Awọn ofin fun awọn orukọ ofin jẹ kanna ni ọpọlọpọ awọn ede siseto. \n
        Ninu JavaScript, ohun kikọ akọkọ gbọdọ jẹ lẹta kan, tabi idasi (_), tabi ami dola kan ($). \n
        Awọn ohun kikọ atẹle le jẹ awọn lẹta, nọmba, awọn ifika, tabi awọn ami dola. \n
        Awọn nọmba ko gba laaye gẹgẹ bi ohun kikọ akọkọ. \n Ni ọna JavaScript le ṣe iyatọ awọn idamo lati awọn nọmba. \n

        \tJavaScript jẹ Ifamọra Ọran \n
        Gbogbo awọn idanimọ JavaScript jẹ kókó ọran. \n
        Awọn oniyipada onipin orukọ ti o kẹhin ati ti oruko idile, jẹ awọn iyatọ meji ti o yatọ: \n
        var oruko idile, Oruko idile; \n
        lastName = \"Doe\"; \n
        oruko idile = \"Peterson\"; \n
        JavaScript ko tumọ VAR tabi Var bi ọrọ pataki yatọ. \n

        \tJavaScript ati Ẹgbọn ibakasiẹ \n
        Itan-akọọlẹ, awọn pirogirama ti lo awọn ọna oriṣiriṣi ti apapọ awọn ọrọ lọpọlọpọ sinu orukọ oniyipada kan: \n
        Hyphens: \n
        orukọ akọkọ, orukọ ikẹhin, kaadi titunto si, aarin ilu. \n
        A ko gba laaye Hyphens ni JavaScript. Wọn ni ifipamọ fun iyokuro. \n
        Ọran Kamẹli Giga julọ (Ẹjọ Pascal): \n
        FirstName, LastName, MasterCard, InterCity. \n
        Isalẹ Kamẹli kekere: \n
        Awọn oluṣeto JavaScript ṣọ lati lo ọran rakunmi ti o bẹrẹ pẹlu lẹta kekere: \n
        ni akọkọ, Oruko idile, alakọkọ, abuku. \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_js_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tAwọn iyatọ JavaScript\n\n
        Awọn oniyipada JavaScript jẹ awọn apoti fun titoju awọn iye data. \n
        Ninu apẹẹrẹ yii, x, y, ati z, jẹ awọn oniyipada: \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 6; \n
        var z = x + y; \n
        Lati apẹẹrẹ loke, o le nireti: \n
        \tx tọjú iye 5 \n
        \ty tọjú iye 6 \n
        \tz tọjú iye 11 \n

        \tMuch Bii Algebra \n
        Ni apẹẹrẹ yii, idiyele1, idiyele2, ati lapapọ, jẹ awọn oniyipada: \n
        Apeere \n
        var owo1 = 5; \n
        var owo2 = 6; \n
        var lapapọ = price1 + price2; \n
        Ninu siseto, bii ninu algebra, a lo awọn oniyipada (bii idiyele1) lati mu awọn iye duro. \n
        Ninu siseto, bii ninu algebra, a lo awọn oniyipada ninu awọn ikosile (lapapọ = price1 + price2). \n
        Lati apẹẹrẹ loke, o le ṣe iṣiro lapapọ lati jẹ 11. \n
        Awọn oniyipada JavaScript jẹ awọn apoti fun titoju awọn iye data. \n

        \t Awọn idanimọ \tJavaScript \n
        Gbogbo awọn oniyipada JavaScript gbọdọ wa ni idanimọ pẹlu awọn orukọ alailẹgbẹ. \n
        Awọn orukọ alailẹgbẹ wọnyi ni a pe ni idamọ. \n
        Awọn idamo le jẹ awọn orukọ kukuru (bii x ati y) tabi awọn orukọ apejuwe diẹ sii (ọjọ-ori, apao, lapapọVolume). \n
        Awọn ofin gbogbogbo fun ṣiṣe awọn orukọ fun awọn oniyipada (awọn idamọ alailẹgbẹ) ni: \n
        \t Awọn orukọ le ni awọn leta, awọn nọmba, awọn ifika, ati awọn ami dola. \n
        \t Awọn orukọ gbọdọ bẹrẹ pẹlu lẹta \n
        \t Awọn orukọ tun le bẹrẹ pẹlu $ ati _ (ṣugbọn a kii yoo lo o ni olukọni yii) \n
        Awọn orukọ t jẹ ifamọra ọran (y ati Y oriṣiriṣi awọn oniyipada) \n
        Awọn ọrọ ti a fi pamọ (bii awọn ọrọ aṣiri JavaScript) ko le ṣee lo bi awọn orukọ \n
        Awọn idamo JavaScript jẹ ifamọra ọran. \n

        \ Oniṣẹ Iṣẹ iyansilẹ \n
        Ninu JavaScript, ami dogba (=) jẹ oluṣe \“iṣẹ iyansilẹ\”, kii ṣe \“dogba si oniṣẹ. \n
        Eyi yatọ si aljebra. Awọn atẹle ko ni ogbon ni aljebra: \n
        x = x + 5 \n
        Ninu JavaScript, sibẹsibẹ, o jẹ oye pipe: o fi iye ti x + 5 si x. \n
        (O ṣe iṣiro iye x + 5 o si fi abajade sinu x. Iye x ti pọ nipasẹ 5.) \n
        Oniṣẹ \"dogba si\" jẹ kikọ bi == ni JavaScript. \n

        \tJavaScript Awọn oriṣi data \n
        Awọn oniyipada JavaScript le mu awọn nọmba bii 100 ati awọn iye ọrọ bi \“John Doe\”. \n
        Ninu siseto, awọn iye ọrọ ni a pe ni awọn ọrọ. \n
        JavaScript le ṣakoso ọpọlọpọ awọn iru data, ṣugbọn fun bayi, ronu awọn nọmba ati awọn okun. \n
        Awọn okun wa ni kikọ inu ilọpo meji tabi ẹyọkan. Awọn nọmba ti kọ laisi awọn agbasọ. \n
        Ti o ba fi nọmba ninu awọn agbasọ, a yoo ṣe itọju rẹ bi okun ọrọ. \n
        Apeere \n
        var pi = 3.14; \n
        var eniyan = \"John Doe\"; \n
        var idahun = \'Bẹẹni emi!\'; \n

        \tDiṣẹ (Ṣiṣẹda) Awọn iyatọ JavaScript \n
        Ṣiṣẹda oniyipada ni JavaScript ni a pe ni \"ikede\" oniyipada kan. \n
        O sọ ikede JavaScript kan pẹlu ọrọ-ọrọ var:: n n
        var CarName; \n
        Lẹhin ikede, oniyipada ko ni iye (imọ-ẹrọ o ni iye ti a ko ni itọkasi). \n
        Lati fi iye si oniyipada, lo ami dogba: \n
        carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        O tun le fi iye le fun oniyipada nigbati o ba kede rẹ: \n
        var carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        Ninu apẹẹrẹ ti o wa ni isalẹ, a ṣẹda oniyipada kan ti a pe ni CarName ati fi iye naa \"Volvo\" si rẹ. \n
        Lẹhinna a \"ṣejade\" iye  inu paragi HTML pẹlu id = \"demo\": \n

        Apeere \n
        <p id= \"demo\"> </ p> \n

        <iwe afọwọkọ> \n
        \t var carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        \t document.getElementById (\"demo\") .innerHTML = carName; \n
        </ iwe afọwọkọ> \n
        O jẹ asa eto sisọ lati sọ gbogbo awọn oniyipada ni ibẹrẹ iwe afọwọkọ. \n

        \t Gbólóhùn kan, Ọpọlọpọ Awọn iyatọ \n
        O le sọ ọpọlọpọ awọn oniyipada ninu alaye kan. \n
        Bẹrẹ alaye naa pẹlu var ati ki o ya awọn oniyipada nipasẹ koma: \n
        var eniyan = \"John Doe\", carName = \"Volvo\", owo = 200; \n
        Ipolongo le ye awọn laini ọpọ: \n
        var eniyan = \"John Doe\", \n
        carName = \"Volvo\", \n
        owo = 200; \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_js_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\t\t \ Awọn oniṣẹ Ẹru JavaScript \n
        Awọn + O tun le ṣee lo oniṣẹ lati ṣafikun (awọn apo-ọrọ) awọn okun. \n
        Apeere \n
        var txt1 = \"Ahmed\"; \n
        var txt2 = \"Mujahid\"; \n
        var txt3 = txt1 + \"\" + txt2; \n
        Abajade ti txt3 yoo jẹ: \n
        Ahmed Mujahid \n
        Awọn + = Oṣiṣẹ iṣẹ iyansilẹ tun le lo lati ṣe afikun (awọn apo-iwe) awọn okun: \n
        Apeere \n
        var txt1 = \"Pẹlẹ o \"; \ntxt1 + = \"Sir Musa\"; \n
        Abajade ti txt1 yoo jẹ: \n
        Kaabo Sir Musa \n
        Nigbati a ba lo lori awọn okun, a pe oniṣẹ + oniṣẹ ẹrọ aṣipọn-ọrọ. \n


        \tAfikun Awọn okun ati Nọmba \n
        Ṣafikun awọn nọmba meji, yoo da iye naa pada, ṣugbọn fifi nọmba kan pọ ati okun yoo pada okun kan: \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 5 + 10; \n
        var y = \"5\" + 5; \n
        var z = \"O dara\" + 5; \n
        Abajade ti x, y, ati z yoo jẹ: \n
        15 \n55 \n
        O dara5 \n
        Ti o ba ṣafikun nọmba kan ati okun kan, abajade naa yoo jẹ okun! \n

        \t JavaScript Arithmetic \n

        \t Awọn Iṣẹ Iṣẹ t\'ẹgbẹ \n
        Iṣẹ iṣapẹẹrẹ aṣoju kan n ṣiṣẹ lori awọn nọmba meji. \n
        Awọn nọmba meji le jẹ awọn iwe kika: \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 100 + 50; \n
        tabi awọn oniyipada: \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = a + b; \n
        tabi awọn ikosile: \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = (100 + 50) * a; \n

        Awọn oniṣẹ ati Awọn oniṣẹ \n
        Awọn nọmba naa (ni iṣẹ adaṣe) ni a pe ni awọn oniṣẹ. \n
        Iṣẹ naa (lati ṣe laarin awọn oṣiṣẹ meji) ni asọye nipasẹ oniṣẹ kan. \n
        Operand	Oniṣẹ	Operand \n
        100	+	50 \n


        Ṣafikun \n
        Afikun oniṣe+) ṣe afikun awọn nọmba: \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x + y; \n

        Iyokuro \n
        Oniṣẹ iyokuro (-) awọn ayọkuro awọn nọmba. \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x - y; \n

        Isodipupo \n
        Oniṣẹ isodipupo (*) awọn nọmba isodipupo. \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x * y; \n

        Pinpin \n
        Olupin pipin (/) pin awọn nọmba. \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x / y; \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="yo_js_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\t\t\tJavaScript Awọn oriṣi data \n
        Awọn oniyipada JavaScript le mu awọn oriṣi data ọpọlọpọ: awọn nọmba, awọn okun, awọn nkan ati diẹ sii: \n
        var ipari = 16; // Nọmba \n
        var lastName = \"Ahmed\"; // okun \n
        var x = {akọkọName:\"Mujahid\", Oruko idile:\"Musa\"}; // Nkan \n
        Agbekale ti Awọn Orisi data \n
        Ninu siseto, awọn ori data jẹ apẹrẹ pataki. \n
        Lati le ṣiṣẹ lori awọn oniyipada, o ṣe pataki lati mọ nkankan nipa iru. \n
        Laisi awọn oriṣi data, kọnputa ko le yanju eyi lailewu: \n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Ṣe o ṣe eyikeyi ori lati ṣafikun \"Volvo\" si mẹrindilogun? Ṣe yoo gbejade aṣiṣe tabi yoo jẹ abajade kan? \n
        JavaScript yoo tọju apẹẹrẹ loke bi: \n
        var x = \"16\" + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Nigbati o ba n nọnba ati okun kan, JavaScript yoo tọju nọmba naa bi okun. \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16; \n
        JavaScript ṣe akojopo awọn ifihan lati osi si otun. Awọn atẹle oriṣiriṣi le gbe awọn abajade oriṣiriṣi: \n
        JavaScript: \n
        var x = 16 + 4 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Esi: \n
        20Volvo \n
        JavaScript: \n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16 + 4; \n
        Esi: \n
        Volvo164 \n
        Ni apẹẹrẹ akọkọ, JavaScript tọju 16 ati 4 bi awọn nọmba, titi ti o fi de “Volvo”. \n
        Ni apẹẹrẹ keji, nitori iṣelọpọ akọkọ jẹ okun, gbogbo awọn oniṣẹ ni a le ṣe bi awọn okun. \n
        \ Awọn okun \tJavaScript \n
        A okun (tabi okun ọrọ) kan lẹsẹsẹ ti ohun kikọ bi \"John Doe\". \n
        Awọn okun ti kọ pẹlu awọn agbasọ. O le lo awọn agbasọ ọrọ ẹyọkan tabi ilọpo meji: \n
        Apeere \n
        var carName1 = \"Volvo XC60\"; // Lilo awọn agbasọ ilọpo meji \n
        var carName2 = \'Volvo XC60\'; // Lilo awọn agbasọ ọrọ \n
        O le lo awọn agbasọ inu okun kan, niwọn igba ti wọn ko baamu awọn agbasọ ọrọ ti o tẹle okun naa: \n
        Apeere \n
        var idahun1 = \"O dara; // Nikan agbasọ inu awọn agbasọ ilọpo meji \n
        var idahun2 = “A n pe ni‘ Johnny ’”; // Awọn agbasọ Single inu awọn agbasọ ilọpo meji \n
        var idahun3 = \'A n pe ni \"Johnny\"\'; // Awọn agbasọ ilọpo meji inu awọn agbasọ ọrọ nikan \n
        O yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa awọn gbolohun ọrọ nigbamii ninu ikẹkọ yii. \n
        \ Awọn nọmba NỌMỌ: Iwe-iyeku \n
        JavaScript ni iru awọn nọmba kan pere. \n
        Awọn nọmba le kọ pẹlu, tabi laisi awọn iyege: \n
        Apeere \n
        var x1 = 34,00; // Ti kọ pẹlu awọn ipin decimals \n
        var x2 = 34; // Ti kọ laisi awọn aisi ipin \n
        Awọn nọmba kekere ti o tobi tabi afikun awọn nọmba kekere le jẹ kikọ pẹlu akiyesi imọ-jinlẹ (alaye)
        Apeere \n
        var y = 123e5; // 12300000 \n
        var z = 123e-5; // 0.00123 \n
        O yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa awọn nọmba nigbamii ni ikẹkọ yii. \n
        \tJavaScript Booleans \n
        Awọn Booleans le ni awọn iye meji nikan: ooto tabi èké. \n
        Apeere \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 5; \n
        var z = 6; \n
        (x == y) // Padà otitọ \n
        (x == z) // Padà padà irọ́ \n
        A nlo Boole ni igbagbogbo ni idanwo ipo ihuwasi. \n
        O yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa idanwo majemu laipẹ ni ikẹkọ yii. \n

        \tJavaScript Awọn irawọ \n
        A kọ awọn iwe JavaScript pẹlu awọn biraketi onigun mẹrin. \n
        Awọn ohun kan yatọ si ti a fi sọji bẹrẹ. \n
        Koodu atẹle n ṣalaye (ṣẹda) akojọpọ ti a pe oko, ti o ni awọn ohun mẹta (awọn orukọ ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ): \n
        Apeere \n
        var paati = [\"Saab\", \"Volvo\", \"BMW\"]; \n
        Awọn atọka Atọka jẹ ipilẹ-odo, eyiti o tumọ si ohun akọkọ ni [0], keji jẹ [1], ati bẹbẹ lọ. \n
        O yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa awọn iṣẹ atẹgun nigbamii ninu ikẹkọ yii. \n

        Awọn Obirin JavaScript \n
        Ti kọ awọn ohun JavaScript pẹlu awọn iṣupọ {}. \n
        Ti kọ awọn ohun-ède Ohun bi orukọ: awọn orisii iye, niya nipasẹ awọn aami idẹsẹ. \n
        Apeere \n
        var eniyan = {akọkọName:\"Ahmed\", Oruko idile:\"Mujahid\", ọjọ ori:30, eyeColor:\"bulu\"}; \n
        Ohun naa (eniyan) ninu apẹẹrẹ loke ni awọn ohun-ini 4: akọbi-akọkọ, Orukọ idile, ọjọ-ori, ati eyeColor. \n
        O yoo ni imọ siwaju sii nipa awọn nkan nigbamii igbimọ ikẹkọ yii. \n

    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of Yoruba JavaScript Contents -->

    <!-- Igbo JavaScript Contents -->
    <string name="ib_js_lesson_one"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJavaScript Ebee ka \n

        \t Ihe <script> Tag \n
        \t Na HTML, a ga-etinye koodu JavaScript n\'etiti <script> na </script> mkpado. \n

        Javascript na <isi>\n
        \t Na ihe atụ a, Javascript ọrụ etinye n\'ime <isi>ngalaba nke ibe HTML. \n
        \t A na-akpọ ọrụ ahụ (kpọọ) mgbe a pịa bọtịnụ: \n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya\n
        \t <! DOCTYPE htm>\n
        \t <htm>\n
        \t <isi>\n
        \t <edemede>\n
        \t ọrụ myFunction () {\n
        \t document.getElementById (\"ngosi\") .innerHTML = \"Paragraf gbanwere.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </ edemede>\n
        \t </ isi>\n
        \t <ahu>\n
        \t <h1>Ibe weebụ</ h1>\n
        \t <p id= \"ngosi\">Paragraf<p>\n
        \t <bọtịnụ ụdị= \"bọtịnụ\" pịa= \"myFunction ()\">Gbalịa ya</ bọtịnụ>\n
        \t </ anụ ahụ>\n
        \t </ HTML>\n
        JavaScript na <body>\n
        \t Na ihe atụ a, Javascript ọrụ etinye n\'ime <body>ngalaba nke ibe HTML. \n
        \t A na-akpọ ọrụ ahụ (kpọọ) mgbe a pịa bọtịnụ: \n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya\n
        \t <! DOCTYPE htm>\n
        \t <htm>\n
        \t <ahu> \n

        \t <h1>Ibe weebụ</ h1>\n

        \t <p id= \"ngosi\">Paragraf<p>\n
        \t <bọtịnụ ụdị= \"bọtịnụ\" pịa= \"myFunction ()\">Gbalịa ya</ bọtịnụ>\n

        \t <edemede>\n
        \t ọrụ myFunction () {\n
        \t document.getElementById (\"ngosi\") .innerHTML = \"Paragraf gbanwere.\"; \n
        \t }\n
        \t </ edemede>\n

        \t </ anụ ahụ>\n
        \t </ HTML>\n
        \t Idobe scripts na ala nke <body> mmezi na-eme ka ngosipụta ọsọ dị, \n
         \t n\'ihi na nkọwapụta edemede na-akwụsịlata ngosipụta. \n

        JavaScript nke mpụga\n
        \t A nwekwara ike itinye Scripts na faịlụ mpụga: \n
        \t Akwukwo anumanu di na ntinye aka mgbe ejiri otu koodu ahu otutu web \n \tpeeji. \n
        \t Faịlụ JavaScript nwere .js faịlụ ahụ. \n
        \t Iji jiri edemede mpụga, tinye aha nke faịlụ ahụ n\'ime src (isi) njiri \n nke \n
        \ta <script> mkpado: \n
        \t Ihe Nlereanya\n
        \t <edemede src= \"myScript.js\"> </ edemede>\n
        \t Can nwere ike itinye ntụnye ederede dị na <isi> ma obu <body>dị ka ị chọrọ. \n
        \t Akwụkwọ edemede ahụ ga-eme omume ka à ga - asị na ọ dị kpọmkwem ebe <script>mkpado dị. \n
        \t Ederede odere enweghị ya <script>mkpado. \n

        Uru JavaScript dị na ya\n
        \t Cingdebe scripts na faịlụ mpụga nwere ụfọdụ uru: \n
        \t Ọ na - ekewa HTML na koodu \n
        \t Ọ na - eme HTML na JavaScript dị mfe ọgụgụ na ijikwa \n
        \t Faịlị JavaScript echekwara nwere ike ime ka ibu peeji dị ngwa \n
        Mmepụta JavaScript\n

        \t JavaScript nwere ike igosipụta data dị iche: \n
        \t Ide ihe n’ime HTML, iji ime HTML. \n
        \t Ederede n\'ime mputa HTML site na iji akwụkwọ edemede (). \n
        \t Edemede n’ime igbe ozi, iji mpio. \n
        \t Ederede n\'ime njikwa ihe nchọgharị, na iji njikwa.log (). \n

        Iji ime HTML \n
        \t Iji nweta ihe HTML, Javascript nwere ike iji dọkụmentị.getElementById (id) \n
         \t usoro \n.
        \t Njirimara id na kọwaa ihe HTML. Ngwongwo nke HTML nke di n’ime kọwaa ihe HTML: \n
        Ihe nlere \n
        \t <! DOCTYPE htm>\n
        \t <htm>\n
        \t <ahu>\n
        \t <p id= \"ngosi\"> <p>\n

        \t <edemede>\n
        \t document.getElementById (\"ngosi\") .innerHTML = 5 + 6; \n
        \t </ edemede>\n

        \t </ anụ ahụ>\n
        \t </ HTML> \n
        \t inggbanwe ihe eji eme HTML nke ihe HTML bu uzo eji egosi \n
        data na HTML. \n

        Iji ederede.write () \n
        \t Maka ebumnuche nnwale, ọ dabara adaba iji akwụkwọ dọkụmentị (): \n
        Ihe nlere \n
        \t <! DOCTYPE htm>\n
        \t <htm>\n
        \t <ahu>\n

        \t <edemede>\n
        \t akwụkwọ edemede (5 + 6); \n
        \t </ edemede>\n

        \t </ anụ ahụ>\n
        \t </ HTML> \n
        \t Iji dọkụmentị mee ihe () mgbe ebuputere HTML akwụkwọ, ọ ga - ehichapụ ihe niile dịnụ
        \t HTML: \n

        Iji window.alert () \n
        \t can nwere ike iji igbe iji gosipụta data: \n
        Ihe nlere \n
        \t <! DOCTYPE htm>\n
        \t <htm>\n
        \t <ahu>\n

        \t <edemede>\n
        \t mpio5 + 6); \n
        \t </ edemede>\n

        \t </ anụ ahụ>\n
        \t </ HTML>\n
        Iji njikwa.log () \n
        \t Maka nzube debug, ị nwere ike iji usoro njikwa conlog.log () gosipụta data. \n
        \t will ga-amatakwu banyere ịme debugment na isiakwụkwọ na-abịa. \n
        Ihe nlere \n
        \t <! DOCTYPE htm>\n
        \t <htm>\n
        \t <ahu>\n

        \t <edemede>\n
        \t njikwa.log (5 + 6); \n
        \t </ edemede>\n

        \t </ anụ ahụ>\n
        \t </ HTML> \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_js_lesson_two"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tNkwupụta Javascript \n

        \tExample \n
        \t var x, y, z; // Nkwupụta 1 \n
        \tx = 5; // Nkwupụta 2 \n
        \ty = 6; // Nkwupụta 3 \n
        \tz = x + y; // Nkwupụta 4 \n

        Nkwupụta \tJavaScript \n
        E dere nkwupụta Javascript: \n
        ,Kpụrụ, ndị ọrụ, Nkọwapụta, Keywords na Comments. \n
        Nkwupụta a na-agwa ihe nchọgharị ahụ ka o dee \"Ndewo Dolly.\" n\'ime HTML ihe nwere \n id = \"ngosi\": \n
        Nlele \n
        document.getElementById (\"ngosi\") .innerHTML = \"Ndewo Dolly.\"; \n
        Ọtụtụ mmemme JavaScript nwere ọtụtụ nkwupụta Javascript. \n
        A na-emezu nkwupụta ndị a, otu, na otu usoro edere ede ha. \n
        A na-akpọkarị mmemme JavaScript (yana nkwupụta Javascript) Javascript koodu. \n

        \tSemicolons; \n
        Semicolons kewapụrụ nkwupụta JavaScript. \n
        Tinye gbakwunye semicolon na njedebe nke nkwupụta ọ bụla ga-emezu: \n
        \t var a, b, c; // Kwuwapụta mgbanwe 3 \n
        \ta = 5; // Nenye uru nke 5 na a \n
        \tb = 6; // Nwee uru 6 rue b \n
        \tc = a + b; // Kenye nchikota nke a na b ka c \n
        Mgbe ekewapụrụ na semicolons, a na-ahapụ ọtụtụ nkwupụta n’otu ahịrị: \n
        \ta = 5; b =6; c = a + b; \n
        Na ntanetị, ịnwere ike ịhụ ihe atụ na-enweghị semicolons.

        \tJavaScript Syntax \n

        Syntax JavaScript bụ usoro iwu, etu esi ewulite mmemme JavaScript: \n
        \t var x, y, z; // Esi kwuwapụta ndị na-agbanwe \n
        \tx = 5; y =6; // Otu esi ekenye ụkpụrụ \n
        \tz = x + y; // Otu esi agbakọ ụkpụrụ n \n

        \tJavaScript Akwụkwọ edemede \n
        Iwu kachasị mkpa maka ede ihe edebere bụ: \n
        Nọmba Ederela ya ma obu ya na odighi akara eji eme ya: \n
        10.50 \n

        1001 \n
        Eriri bụ ederede, edere ya na nkwupụta abụọ maọbụ otu: \n
        \"Ahmed Mujahid\" \n

        \'Ahmed Mujahid\' \n

        \tJavaScript Variables \n
        N\'asụsụ mmemme, a na-eji ihe mgbanwe maka ichekwa ogo data. \n
        Javascript na-eji var keyword iji kwuwapụta mgbanwe. \n
        A na-eji ihe ịrịba ama eme ihe iji kenye ụkpụrụ maka mgbanwe. \n
        N\'ihe atụ a, x na-akọwapụta x. Mgbe ah, x kenyere (enyere) uru 6: \n
        var x; \n

        x = 6; \n
        \tJavaScript Ndị ọrụ \n
        JavaScript na-eji ndị na-ahụ maka mgbakọ (+ - * /) gbakọọ ụkpụrụ: \n
        (5 + 6) * 10 \n
        JavaScript na-eji onye ọrụ (=) kenye ụkpụrụ maka ndị na-agbanwe: \n
        var x, y; \n
        x = 5; \n
        y = 6; \n

        Nkwupụta \tJavaScript \n
        Ngosiputa bu ngwongwo bara uru, ihe na-agbanwe ya na ndi oru ya, nke riri otu uru. \n
        A na-akpọ mgbako ahụ nyocha. \n
        Dịka ọmụmaatụ, 5 * 10 tụlere ruo 50: \n
        5 * 10 \n
        Ngosipụta nwekwara ike ịnwe ụkpụrụ agbanwe: \n
        x * 10 \n
        Valueskpụrụ nwere ike ịbụ nke ụdị dị iche, dịka ọnụọgụ na eriri. \n
        Dịka ọmụmaatụ, \"John\" + \"\" \"\" Doe \", tụlere ka\" John Doe \": \n
        \"John\" + \"\" + \"Doe\" \n

        \tJavaScript Keywords \n
        A na-eji isi okwu JavaScript mata ihe omume aga-eme. \n
        Ihe isiokwu var na agwa onye ihe nchọgharị ka o mepụta mgbanwe: \n
        var x, y; \n
        x = 5 + 6; \n
        y = x * 10; \n

        \tJavaScript kwuru \n
        Ọ bụghị n \’okwu JavaScript ọ bụla ka\“ na-egbu \”. \n
        A na-ewere koodu mgbe abụrụla nke abụọ // ma ọ bụ n\'etiti / * na * / dịka okwu. \n
        A na-eleghara nkọwa anya, a gaghị egbu ya: \n
        var x = 5; // A ga-egbu m \n

        // var x = 6; Agaghị egbu m \n
        \tSHORTCUT FOR COMMENT B. (Ctrl + /) \n

        \tJavaScript mata \n
        Ndị amata bụ aha. \n
        Na JavaScript, eji mata ndị na-eme mgbanwe iji kpọọ aha ngbanwe (yana isiokwu na ọrụ yana aha). \n
        Iwu maka aha iwu bụ otu na ọtụtụ asụsụ mmemme. \n
        Na JavaScript, agwa izizi ga-abụ mkpụrụedemede, ma ọ bụ ihe akara (_), ma ọ bụ akara dollar ($). \n
        Mkpụrụ edemede ndị na-esote nwere ike ịbụ mkpụrụedemede, mkpụrụ ọgụgụ, mkpụrụ ego, ma ọ bụ akara dollar. \n
        Anabataghị ọnụọgụ dị ka akara mbụ. \n N\'ụzọ a, Javascript nwere ike ịmata ndị dị iche na njirimara ndị dị mfe. \n

        \tJavaScript bu Case Sensitive \n
        Nchọpụta JavaScript niile nwere ntaramahụhụ ọfụma. \n
        Ihe ngbanwe aha lastame na aha ikpe azu, bu udiri olu abuo: \n
        var aha ikpeazu, aha ikpeazu; \n
        lastName = \"Doe\"; \n
        aha ikpeazụ = \"Peterson\"; \n
        JavaScript asugharia VAR ma obu Var dika isi okwu var. \n

        \tJavaScript na Camel Case \n
        N\’oge gara aga, ndị mmemme ejiriwo ụzọ dị iche nke ijikọta ọtụtụ okwu gaa n\’otu aha mgbanwe: \n
        Hyphens: \n
        aha mbu, aha ikpeazụ, nna ukwu, kaadị etiti. \n
        Anaghị anabata hyphens na JavaScript. Edebere ha maka mbepu. \n
        Oke Ochie Kamel (Pascal Case): \n
        FirstName, LastName, MasterCard, InterCity. \n
        Okpukpo nke Kamel: \n
        Ndị mmemme JavaScript na-ejikarị ikpe kamel nke na-amalite site na obere mkpirisi: \n
        aha izizi, aha ikpeazu, nna ukwu, abali. \n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_js_lesson_three"><![CDATA[
        \t\t\tJavascript iche\n
        Ihe mgbanwe Javascript bụ igbe maka ịchekwa ụkpụrụ data. \n
        N\'ihe atụ a, x, y, na z, ndị iche: \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 6; \n
        var z = x + y; \n
        Site na ihe atụ dị n\’elu, ị nwere ike ịtụ anya: \n
        \tx echekwala uru 5 \n
        \ty na-echekwa uru 6 \n
        \tz na-echekwa uru 11 \n

        \tMuch Dị ka Algebra \n
        N\’ihe atụ a, ọnụahịa1, ọnụahịa2, na mkpokọta, bụ mgbanwe: \n
        Nlele \n
        var ọnụahịa1 = 5; \n
        var ọnụahịa2 = 6; \n
        var mkpokọta = price1 + price2; \n
        Na mmemme, dị ka na algebra, anyị na-eji ihe mgbanwe (dịka ọnụahịa1) iji jide ụkpụrụ. \n
        N\'ime usoro mmemme, dị ka na algebra, anyị na-eji mgbanwe dịgasị iche na ngosipụta (mkpokọta = price1 + price2). \n
        Site na ihe atụ dị n\’elu, ị nwere ike gbakọọ mkpokọta ahụ ka ọ bụrụ 11. \n
        Ihe mgbanwe Javascript bụ igbe maka ịchekwa ụkpụrụ data. \n

        \tJavaScript mata \n
        Ekwesịrị iji akara ọdịiche dị na JavaScript nwee aha pụrụ iche. \n
        A na - akpọ ndị a aha pụrụ iche
        Ndị na-achọpụta ya nwere ike ịbụ obere aha (dị ka x na y) ma ọ bụ aha nkọwa karịa (afọ, nchikota, mkpokọta). \n
        Iwu izugbe maka iwu aha maka ndị na-eme mgbanwe (ihe nchọpụta pụrụ iche) bụ: \n
        Aha t nwere ike inwe mkpụrụedemede, mkpụrụ, ihe akara, yana akara dollar. \n
        \"T aha ga-amalite na leta \n
        \t Aha nwekwara ike imalite na $ na _ (mana anyị agaghị eji ya na nkuzi a) \n
        Aha t nwere mmetụta na-emetụ n\'ahụ (y na Y bụ ndị dịgasị iche) \n
        Ekwesịrị iji okwu echekwara (dị ka mkpụrụokwu JavaScript) dị ka aha \n
        Achọpụtara JavaScript enweghị nsogbu. \n

        \ Onye ọrụ onye na - enye ọrụ \n
        Na JavaScript, akara kwesiri (=) bụ onye ọrụ \"ekenye\", ọ bụghị \"ngbaghara\" onye ọrụ. \n
        Nke a dị iche na algebra. Ihe ndia adighi eme ezi uche na algebra: \n
        x = x + 5 \n
        Na JavaScript, ọ nwere ezi uche: ọ nyere oke nke x + 5 ka x. \n
        (Ọ na-agbakọ ọnụ ahịa x + 5 ma tinye nsonaazụ ya x. Ọnụ ahịa x na-arị elu site na 5.) \n
        Edere onye ọrụ \"hara nha\" dị ka == na JavaScript. \n

        \tJavaScript ụdị Datadị data \n
        Ndị mgbanwe JavaScript nwere ike ijide ọnụọgụ dịka 100 na ụkpụrụ ederede dịka \"John Doe\". \n
        Na mmemme, a na-akpọ ụkpụrụ ederede
        JavaScript nwere ike ijikwa ọtụtụ ụdị data, mana ugbu a, chee naanị maka ọnụ ọgụgụ na eriri. \n
        Edere eriri n\'ime ntanetịime ugboro abụọ ma ọ bụ otu. Edere onu ogugu na onu ogugu. \n
        O buru na itinye onu na onu ogugu, a gha ewere ya dika udiri ederede. \n
        Nlele \n
        var pi = 3.14; \n
        var mmadu = \"John Doe\"; \n
        var azịza = \'Ee abụ m!\'; \n

        \tDọpụtara (Creatmepụta) JavaScript ọdịiche \n
        Amepụta agbanwe na JavaScript ka akpọrọ \"ịkọpụta\" agbanwe. \n
        Na-ekwuputa mgbanwe JavaScript na-eji var isiokwu: \n
        var carName; \n
        Mgbe nkwupụta ahụ gachara, onye na-agbanwe enweghị uru (nyocha ọ nwere uru nke akọwaghị). \n
        Iji kenye onye na-agbanwe uru, jiri akara nhata: \n
        carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        I nwekwara ike ikenye onye na-agbanwe uru mgbe ị na-ekwupụta ya: \n
        var carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        Na ihe atụ dị n\'okpuru, anyị na-ekepụta agbanwe akpọrọ CarName ma kenye ya \"Volvo\" na ya. \n
        Mgbe ahụ anyị \"rụpụta\" uru dị na paragraf HTML na iji id = \"ngosi\": \n

        Nlele \n
        <p id= \"ngosi\"> <p> \n

        <edemede> \n
        \t var carName = \"Volvo\"; \n
        \t document.getElementById (\"ngosi\") .innerHTML = carName; \n
        </ edemede> \n
        Ọ bụ ezigbo mmemme ikwuwapụta mgbanwe niile na mbido edemede. \n

        Nkwupụta otu, ọtụtụ mgbanwe \n
        Nwere ike ikwuputa ọtụtụ mgbanwe na otu nkwupụta. \n
        Bido nkwupụta ahụ na var wee kewapụ ndị mgbanwe site na rikoma: \n
        var mmadu = \"John Doe\", carName = \"Volvo\", ọnụahịa = 200; \n
        Nkwupụta nwere ike wepụta ọtụtụ ahịrị: \n
        var mmadu = \"John Doe\", \n
        carName = \"Volvo\", \n
        ọnụahịa = 200; \n

    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_js_lesson_four"><![CDATA[
                \t\t\t\t \t JavaScript Eriri eji eme \n
        Na + A nwekwara ike iji onye ọrụ na ịgbakwunye (concatenate) ndido urụk. \n
        Nlele \n
        var txt1 = \"Ahmed\"; \n
        var txt2 = \"Mujahid\"; \n
        var txt3 = txt1 + \"\" + txt2; \n
        Nsonaazụ nke txt3 ga - abụ: \n
        Ahmed Mujahid \n
        Na + = A nwekwara ike iji onye na-enye ọrụ maka ịgbakwunye (concatenate) urụk: \n
        Nlele \n
        var txt1 = \"Nnọọ \"; \ntxt1 + = \"Sir Musa\"; \n
        Nsonaazụ nke txt1 ga - abụ: \n
        Ndewo Sir Musa \n
        Mgbe ejiri ya na eriri, a na-akpọ onye na-ahụ maka ọrụ + onye na-ahụ maka ikpe. \n

        \tAgbakwunye eriri na nọmba \n
        Dinggbakwunye nọmba abụọ, ọ ga-eweghachi nchikota, mana ịgbakwunye nọmba na eriri ga-alaghachi eriri: \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 5 + 10; \n
        var y = \"5\" + 5; \n
        var z = \"Ọ dị mma\" + 5; \n
        Nsonaazụ nke x, y, na z ga - abụ: \n
        15 \n55 \n
        Mma5 \n
        Ọ bụrụ na ịgbakwunye nọmba na eriri, nsonaazụ ga-abụ eriri! \n

        \t JavaScript Arithmetic \n

        \t Ọrụ Arụrụ ọrụ \n
        Ihe omumu na-aru oru na onu ogugu abuo
        Onu ogugu abuo nwere ike ibu akwukwo. \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 100 + 50; \n
        ma ọ bụ mgbanwe: \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = a + b; \n
        ma obu okwu: \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = (100 + 50) * a; \n

        Ndị ọrụ na ndị na-ahụ maka \ \n
        A na - akpọ nọmba ọnụọgụ (na arithmetic)
        Onye ọrụ ga-arụ ọrụ (nke a ga-eme n\'etiti ndị ọrụ egwuregwu abụọ ahụ). \n
        Operand	Onye ọrụ	Operand \n
        100	+	50 \n

        Na-agbakwunye \n
        Ndị ọrụ mgbakwunye (+) gbakwunye ọnụ ọgụgụ: \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x + y; \n

        Mbelata \n
        Mbelata onye ọrụ (belata)-) wepu nọmba. \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x - y; \n

        Otutu \n
        Onye na - eme ya ihe nuputa.*) ọnụọgụ. \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x * y; \n

        Nkesa \n
        Ndị na-arụ ọrụ nkewa (/) kewara ọnụọgụ. \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 2; \n
        var z = x / y; \n

    ]]></string>

    <string name="ib_js_lesson_five"><![CDATA[
            \t\t\t\t\tJavaScript ụdị Datadị data \n
        Mgbanwe Javascript nwere ike ijide ọtụtụ ụdị data: ọnụọgụ, eriri, ihe na ndị ọzọ: \n
        var ogologo = 16; // Nọmba \n
        var lastName = \"Ahmed\"; // Eriri \n
        var x = {mbụ aha:\"Mujahid\", aha ikpeazụ:\"Musa\"}; // Ihe \n
        Usoro nke ụdị data \n
        Na mmemme, ụdị data bụ echiche dị mkpa. \n
        Iji nwee ike ịrụ ọrụ na ndị na-agbanwe, ọ dị mkpa ịmata ihe gbasara ụdị. \n
        Enweghị ụdị data, kọmputa enweghị ike idozi nke a: \n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Ọ nwere ezi uche ịgbakwunye \"Volvo\" na iri na isii? Ọ ga - ebute njehie ka ọ ga - arụpụta ihe? \n
        JavaScript ga - emeso ihe atụ dị n\'elu dịka: \n
        var x = \"16\" + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Mgbe ị na-agbakwunye ọnụ ọgụgụ na eriri, Javascript ga-emeso ọnụọgụ ahụ dịka eriri. \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 16 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16; \n
        JavaScript na-enyocha okwu site n\'aka ekpe gaa n\'aka nri. Usoro dị iche nwere ike rụpụta nsonaazụ dị iche: \n
        Javascript: \n
        var x = 16 + 4 + \"Volvo\"; \n
        N\'ihi: \n
        20Volvo \n
        Javascript: \n
        var x = \"Volvo\" + 16 + 4; \n
        N\'ihi: \n
        Volvo164 \n
        Na ihe atụ mbu, JavaScript lebara 16 na 4 anya dika onu ogugu, rue mgbe o ruru “Volvo”. \n
        Na ihe atụ nke abụọ, ebe ọ bụ na arụ ọrụ izizi bụ eriri, a na - ewere ndị na - arụ ọrụ ọ bụla dịka eriri. \n
        \tJavaScript Eriri \n
        Eriri (ma obu udiri ederede) bu udiri ederede dika \"John Doe\". \n
        Edere eriri na mkpuru okwu. Nwere ike iji rutụ otu ma ọ bụ abụọ ụzọ: \n
        Nlele \n
        var carName1 = \"Volvo XC60\"; // Site na iji ntunye okwu abuo \n
        var carName2 = \'Volvo XC60\'; // Iji otu ruturu \n
        Nwere ike iji ruturu n\'ime eriri, ọ bụrụhaala na ha ekwekọghị na nkọwa okwu gbara gburugburu eriri: \n
        Nlele \n
        var azịza1 = \"Ọ dị mma\"; // Single see n\'ime abụọ kwuru okwu \n
        var azịza2 = \"A na-akpọ ya \'Johnny\'\"; // Single na-ehota n’ime nhota okwu abụọ \n
        var azịza3 = A na-akpọ ya \"Johnny\" \'; // Ugboro abụọ kwurịtara n\'ime otu ruturu \n
        Ga-amatakwu banyere ụdọ emechaa na nkuzi a. \n
        \tJavaScript Ọnụọgụ \n
        JavaScript nwere naanị ụdị ọnụọgụgụ. \n
        Enwere ike iji nọmba ọnụọgụ dee ya, ma ọ bụ na-enweghị akara: - \n
        Nlele \n
        var x1 = 34,00; // Edere ya na decimals \n
        var x2 = 34; // Edere na-enweghị decimur \n
        Enwere ike iji ọnụ ọgụgụ sayensị dị ukwuu ma ọ bụ karịa
        Nlele \n
        var y = 123e5; // 12300000 \n
        var z = 123e-5; // 0.00123 \n
        Ga-amatakwu gbasara ọnụọgụ dị iche na nkuzi a. \n
        \tJavaScript Booleans \n
        Ndị Booleans nwere ike ịnwe naanị ụkpụrụ abụọ: eziokwu ma obu ugha. \n
        Nlele \n
        var x = 5; \n
        var y = 5; \n
        var z = 6; \n
        (x == y) // Alaghachi eziokwu \n
        (x == z) // Na-alaghachi ụgha \n
        A na-ejikarị Booleans na nnwale nyocha. \n
        Ga-amatakwu maka ịnwale nnwale ọnọdụ mgbe emechara nkuzi a. \n

        \tJavaScript Arrays \n
        Ejiri nkenke akuku JavaScript jiri ihe nkwado. \n
        A na - ekewapu ahiri ihe n\'usoro. \n
        Koodu n ’e kwuputara (emeputa) usoro akpọrọ ụgbọala, nwere ihe atọ (aha ụgbọ ala): \n
        Nlele \n
        var ụgbọ ala = [\"Saab\", \"Volvo\", \"BMW\"]; \n
        Ihe ntinye ederede n\'usoro sitere na efu, nke putara ihe mbu bu [0], nke abuo bu [1], na ndi ozo. \n
        Will ga-amatakwu banyere aka ekpe nke emechara nkuzi a. \n

        \t Ihe JavaScript Ihe \n
        Ejiri ihe eji eme ihe ndi ozo wee dee JavaScript {}. \n
        Edere ihe akpọrọ dị ka aha: ọnụ ụzọ dị iche, commas na-ekewa. \n
        Nlele \n
        var mmadu = {firstName:\"Ahmed\", aha ikpeazụ:\"Mujahid\", afọ:30, eyeColor:\"acha anụnụ anụnụ\"}; \n
        Ihe (onye) nọ na ihe atụ dị n’elu nwere atụmatụ 4: nke izizi, aha ikpeazụ, afọ na anya. \n
        Ga-amatakwu banyere ihe emechaa na nkuzi a. \n
    ]]></string>

    <!-- End of Igbo JavaScript Contents -->

    <!-- End of JavaScript Contents -->

    <!-- Quiz Contents -->
    <string name="quiz">Quiz</string>
    <string name="true_text">True</string>
    <string name="false_text">False</string>
    <string name="correct_answer">That\'s correct</string>
    <string name="wrong_answer">That\'s incorrect</string>
    <string name="question_html_stands">HTML stands for Hypertext Markup Language.</string>
    <string name="question_heading"><![CDATA[<h1> is the largest HTML heading element]]></string>
    <string name="question_breaks"><![CDATA[The <br> tag is used for inserting line breaks]]></string>
    <string name="question_js_function"><![CDATA[The function myFunction(){} creates a function in JavaScript]]></string>
    <string name="question_background"><![CDATA[The correct syntax for inserting background color is <background>yellow</background>]]></string>
    <string name="question_hyperlink"><![CDATA[<a url=\"www.google.com\">Google</a> is the correct way of making a hyperlink]]></string>
    <string name="question_list"><![CDATA[The <list> tag is used to make a numbered list]]></string>
    <string name="question_css_stands"><![CDATA[CSS stands for Colorful Style Sheets]]></string>
    <string name="question_css_external"><![CDATA[The <head> tag is the correct place to refer to a external style sheet]]></string>
    <string name="question_css_internal"><![CDATA[The <style> tag is used to define an inline style sheet]]></string>
    <string name="next_text">next</string>
    <string name="prev">Prev</string>
    <string name="take_quiz">Take Quiz</string>

</resources>